<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-6-3"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-6-3"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="SRULE 6.3"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-6-3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-6-3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-6-3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-6-3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_SRULE-6-3">
        <num>SRULE 6.3</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-6-3__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If any member violates the Rules of Order of the Senate, in speech or otherwise, the President shall, and any member may, call him to order. Any member so called to order shall immediately take his seat unless the Senate permits him to explain his actions, upon his motion or that of another member duly adopted.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-6-3__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Every question of order shall be decided by the presiding officer, without debate, subject to an appeal to the Senate. When an appeal is taken from the decision of the presiding officer, the decision of the presiding officer shall be overruled only if a majority of the elected members of the Senate vote to overrule his decision. The presiding officer may call for the sense of the Senate on any question of order, but when an appeal has been taken from the decision of the presiding officer, any subsequent question of order which arises before the decision of the appeal by the Senate shall be decided by the presiding officer without debate, and every appeal therefrom also shall be decided at once and without debate.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-6-3__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If, after being called to order, a member persists in a breach of decorum, it shall be duty of the President to reprimand the offending member. Upon his motion, or that of another member duly adopted, the member may be permitted to explain his actions. He may appeal the reprimand to the Senate. The appeal shall be decided without debate.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-6-3__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the member refuses to submit to reprimand or continues to be in disorder after reprimand, the President may cause him to be ejected from the Senate for a stated period determined by the President or for such period as may be stated by the Senate upon motion duly adopted. In such case, he shall not again be admitted to the floor during the specified time, except by a vote of the Senate and upon such conditions and terms of apology as it may prescribe.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=180526</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>