<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-16-3"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-16-3"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="SRULE 16.3"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-16-3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-16-3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-16-3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-16-3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_SRULE-16-3">
        <num>SRULE 16.3</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-16-3__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon receipt of appointments for Senate confirmation, the chairman of the
Senate and Governmental Affairs Committee shall cause a listing to be compiled of all of
the appointments received, by office. On the fifteenth calendar day of the session the
chairman shall distribute a copy of the compiled listing to each senator and thereafter the
listing shall be updated and distributed to the members prior to the vote to confirm the
appointments.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-16-3__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The Senate and Governmental Affairs Committee, by motion of the chairman or
any member of the committee and with approval of at least a majority of the members of
the committee, may direct any appointee whose appointment has been submitted for
confirmation to appear before the committee. At such appearance, the committee may
examine into the qualifications of the appointee and the method by which the appointee
intends to administer the affairs of the office for which he has been appointed.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-16-3__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The standing committee having jurisdiction of the work to be administered by a
person whose appointment has been submitted for confirmation, by motion of the
chairman or any member of the committee and with approval of at least a majority of the
members of the committee, may direct that the appointee appear before the committee. At
such appearance, the committee may examine into the qualifications of the appointee and
the method by which the appointee intends to administer the affairs of the office for
which he has been appointed.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-16-3__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any information, finding, recommendations of the committee resulting from the
appearance before it of the appointee shall be transmitted to the chairman of the Senate
and Governmental Affairs Committee, who shall inform the committee thereof. The
Senate and Governmental Affairs Committee may consider such information in arriving
at its report to the Senate with respect to said appointment.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-16-3__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The standing committee having jurisdiction over the subject matter of the
department or agency administered by an officer confirmed by the Senate may at any time
during his tenure bring the officer before it for the purpose of reporting to the committee
on matters pertaining to the programs, operations, and administration of the department or
agency.
SR 144 of 2004 RS; SR 156 of 2011.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=180481</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>