<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-14-31-3"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-14-31-3"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CA 14 31.3"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-14-31-3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-14-31-3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-14-31-3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-14-31-3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CA-14-31-3">
        <num>CA 14 31.3</num>
        <heading>3.  New Orleans; railroad passenger stations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง31.3.  New Orleans; railroad passenger stations
General authorizations.  The City of New Orleans, acting through the
Public Belt Railroad Commission, shall have the power, in any manner it may
determine, to acquire, construct, maintain and operate one or more railroad
passenger stations, with all approaches thereto and appurtenances thereof, and
shall also have the power to acquire, by purchase, lease, contract, expropriation
or otherwise, all such lands, tracks and other property, real or personal, or
rights of use or possession thereof, as it may deem necessary or desirable for
the construction, maintenance and operation of said railroad passenger station
or stations; provided, however, that in the maintenance and operation of said
passenger station or stations and the other property referred to in this Section,
no funds of the City of New Orleans or of said Commission, except funds
derived from the revenues produced by said operation, shall be expended.  The
powers herein granted may be exercised anywhere in the Parish of Orleans or
in any parish adjacent thereto.  In connection with any project for building any
such passenger station or stations, the City of New Orleans, through said
Commission, shall have the power to do everything it deems necessary or
desirable for the purpose of minimizing interference, caused by railroad traffic
of any sort, with the use of streets, thoroughfares and roads, and with the
proper development of the City of New Orleans, and for that purpose may
include in the property acquired or constructed hereunder, or the right of use
or possession of which is acquired hereunder, any and all depots, freight
terminals, classification yards, tracks and other railroad facilities; provided,
however, that for the exclusive purpose of minimizing interference caused by
railroad traffic of any sort with the use of streets, thoroughfares and roads, or
with the proper development of the City of New Orleans, the power of
expropriation shall not be exercised to acquire any existing freight depot,
freight terminal, freight classification yard, track or other railroad facility.  The
Commission Council of the City of New Orleans, on such terms and conditions
as it may prescribe, may dedicate to the use of any project hereunder any
streets, thoroughfares, roads or other property belonging to or under the control
of the City of New Orleans; and the Police Jury of any adjacent parish, on such
terms and conditions as it may prescribe, may dedicate to the use of such
project any streets, thoroughfares, roads, or other property belonging to said
parish or under the control of said Police Jury.
The operation of any passenger station or stations herein authorized
may include operating, or granting leases or concessions for the operation of,
any restaurant, store or other enterprise of any sort associated with a railroad
passenger station.
The City of New Orleans, through the Public Belt Railroad
Commission, shall have the power at any time to rebuild, reconstruct, to
improve and to enlarge any constructed property therefore acquired, pursuant
hereto.
The City of New Orleans, through the Public Belt Railroad
Commission, shall have the power to make a loan or loans to any railroad
company or railroad companies to be used by said railroad company or railroad
companies for defraying the expenses of any improvement in the Parish of
Orleans, or in any parish adjacent thereto, to any tracks, depots, freight
terminals, classification yards or other facilities of such railroad company or
railroad companies; provided, however, that no funds of the City of New
Orleans or of said Commission shall be so loaned except funds obtained from
the source enumerated in Subsection (B) hereof.  The obligation of any
railroad company or railroad companies to repay any such loan may be pledged
under any mortgage referred to in said Subsection (B) hereof, and the interest
paid on any such loan shall be deemed part of the revenues referred to in this
Section 31.3.
(A).  Contracts.  The City of New Orleans, through the Public Belt
Railroad Commission, shall have the authority to enter into a contract or
contracts, containing such terms, conditions, stipulations and provisions, and
for such duration, as may be approved by the vote of a majority of all the
members of said Commission, with any railroad company or railroad
companies entering or hereafter entering New Orleans, for the use by such
railroad company or railroad companies of said passenger station or stations,
and the approaches thereto and appurtenances thereof, and/or of any tracks or
other property, constructed pursuant to Section 31.3 hereof, or the ownership
or right of use or possession of, which is acquired or dedicated pursuant to
Section 31.3 hereof, for or in connection with the transporting, conveying or
other handling, under the motive power of such railroad company or railroad
companies, of the locomotives, cars, trains and other equipment of such
railroad company or railroad companies, and passengers therein and freight
and other contents thereof.  Said passenger station or stations and all property
and rights of use or possession of property acquired, constructed or dedicated
pursuant to Section 31.3 hereof, shall be under the control and management of
the Public Belt Railroad Commission, but any contract entered into pursuant
to this Subsection (A) or resolution adopted by said Commission by a vote of
a majority of all the members thereof, may vest in a Committee or other body
composed of representatives of any and all interested parties, including but not
limited to representatives of any railroad company or railroad companies,
constituted as provided in such contract or resolution, such powers as may be
specified in such contract or resolution for supervising or controlling the
acquisition, construction, maintenance and operation of said passenger station
or stations, the approaches thereto and appurtenances thereof, and any tracks
or other property referred to in Section 31.3 hereof.  Any such contract may be
made superior to the lien of any mortgage executed to secure any bond issued
hereunder.  Any right of use granted pursuant to this Subsection (A) to any
railroad company or railroad companies by the City of New Orleans, through
the Public Belt Railroad Commission, shall be exempt from every form of
taxation.
Without restricting any power or discretion herein conferred upon the
City of New Orleans, acting either through its Commission Council or the
Public Belt Railroad Commission, it is hereby declared to be the policy of this
amendment that the railroad passenger station or stations or other railroad
facilities acquired or constructed by the City of New Orleans pursuant hereto,
shall not be operated at a profit to the City of New Orleans or the Public Belt
Railroad Commission, it being understood that the City of New Orleans and
the Public Belt Railroad Commission shall not be deprived of any element of
cost paid by them or either of them with proper interest on all amounts
expended or advanced, and it being understood, further, that after all costs with
interest have been reimbursed (but in no event sooner than 1988), the City of
New Orleans shall receive, in addition to all costs of maintenance and
operation, a net rental in an amount equal to what the taxes would be on the
stations or facilities furnished by it, based on their then fair value if the same
were not tax exempt.
(B).  Bond issue.  For the purpose of acquiring or constructing said
railroad passenger station or stations, with all approaches thereto and
appurtenances thereof, and any land, tracks and other property, real or
personal, or rights of use or possession thereof, referred to in Section 31.3
hereof, and of improving and enlarging any property theretofore acquired or
constructed pursuant hereto, and of complying with any obligation contained
in any contract which may be executed pursuant to Subsection (A) hereof, the
City of New Orleans, through its Commission Council, is hereby granted
power to issue by resolution, upon the recommendation of the Public Belt
Railroad Commission, its bonds not to exceed Fifteen Million Dollars
($15,000,000) in aggregate principal amount, in such forms, numbers and
amounts, at such times and prices, and upon such terms and conditions as to
maturities, rates and payment of interest, and final redemption (which shall not
be later than fifty years after their date), and otherwise, as the City of New
Orleans may deem advisable, subject to the following limitations and
provisions:
(a)  All such bonds shall be secured solely and only by mortgage of
such railroad passenger station or stations, the approaches thereto and
appurtenances thereof, and any lands, tracks and other property, real or
personal, or rights of use or possession thereof, acquired, constructed or
dedicated pursuant to Section 31.3 hereof, and by pledge of the net revenues
derived from the operation of such property and by pledge and assignment of
any contract or contracts executed pursuant to Subsection (A) hereof, and shall
be paid therefrom and not by any tax or assessment or levy upon any taxable
property in the City of New Orleans, nor out of any other funds, revenues or
things of value of said City; provided that during the period of acquisition and
construction of said passenger station or stations and other property, and
during the period, if any, after acquisition and construction while the net
revenues from the operation shall not be sufficient to provide for the interest
or sinking fund or maturing installments of principal of any and all outstanding
bonds hereinabove authorized to be issued, the same may be paid out of the
proceeds from the sale of any bonds authorized by this Subsection (B); and
provided, further, that if more than one such passenger</p>
        </content>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=67976</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>