<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-4731"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-4731"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCP 4731"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-4731/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-4731/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-4731/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-4731/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCP-4731">
        <num>CCP 4731</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="CCP-4731__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the lessee or occupant fails to comply with the notice to vacate required under
this Title, or if the lessee has waived his right to notice to vacate by written waiver contained
in the lease, and has lost his right of occupancy for any reason, the lessor or owner, or agent
thereof, may cause the lessee or occupant to be cited summarily by a court of competent
jurisdiction to show cause why he should not be ordered to deliver possession of the premises
to the lessor or owner.  The rule to show cause shall state the grounds upon which eviction
is sought.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-4731__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>After the required notice has been given, the lessor or owner, or agent thereof,
may lawfully take possession of the premises without further judicial process, upon a
reasonable belief that the lessee or occupant has abandoned the premises.  Indicia of
abandonment include a cessation of business activity or residential occupancy, returning keys
to the premises, and removal of equipment, furnishings, or other movables from the
premises.
C.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-4731__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In parishes subject to a federal disaster declaration, cessation of residential
occupancy shall not be deemed evidence of abandonment pursuant to Paragraph B of this
Article for thirty days following the initial declaration of a federally declared disaster.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-4731__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Failure of the lessor to comply with this Article shall give a residential lessee the
right to recover five hundred dollars or twice the amount of the monthly rent, whichever is
greater, from the lessor or owner, or from the lessor's successor in interest.  A residential
lessee may obtain a restraining order or a preliminary injunction to enforce the provisions of
this Article.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-4731__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The court may award costs and attorney fees to the prevailing party for actions
brought pursuant to this Article.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-4731__subsec_B__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In parishes subject to a federally declared disaster, a court shall not require a
residential lessee bringing an action for a temporary restraining order or preliminary
injunction under this Article to furnish security as required by Article 3610 for the thirty days
following the initial declaration of a federally declared disaster.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-4731__subsec_B__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Nothing in this Paragraph shall preempt the rights afforded to a lessor in Civil
Code Article 2693.
Amended by</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112078</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>