<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-921"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-921"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 921"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-921/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-921/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-921/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-921/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-921">
        <num>CHC 921</num>
        <heading>921.  Order of expungement and sealing; agency records</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-921__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>An order for the expungement and sealing of juvenile records and reports shall
be in the form provided in Article 925 and shall require that both of the following occur:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-921__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided by law, all officials, agencies, institutions, boards,
systems, and law enforcement offices, and their employees, agents, and consultants, expunge
and seal all records and reports, in any form, and any other photographic, fingerprint, DNA,
or any other information of any kind and all kinds or descriptions relating to the conduct or
conditions referred to in the motion for expungement and sealing.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-921__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>All agencies and law enforcement offices file with the court an affidavit to the
effect that such records and reports have been expunged and sealed and that no notation or
references have been retained in any central depository which will or might lead to the
inference that any record or report ever was on file with that agency or law enforcement
office.  A copy of the affidavit of expungement and sealing shall be retained by the court.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-921__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The order shall state that the expungement and sealing is to be effected no later
than thirty days from the date of the order. The order shall also specify the limitations on
information that may be maintained in accordance with this Article.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-921__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>An order for expungement and sealing shall be served in the manner provided for
service of the motion on both the district attorney and the head of each agency whose records
or reports are to be expunged and sealed.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-921__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A copy of the order of expungement and sealing may be maintained by the
custodian of  records and reports of the agency or office.  However, the custodian shall not
disclose to anyone the fact that such order is maintained or that the expunged and sealed
records or reports previously existed except upon written order of the court.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=73515</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>