<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1132"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1132"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 1132"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1132/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1132/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1132/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1132/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-1132">
        <num>CHC 1132</num>
        <heading>1132.  Notice of filing of surrender; form</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1132__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a mother of a child born outside of marriage has executed a surrender and
identifies the child's alleged or adjudicated father, the agency or individual to whom the child
was surrendered shall exercise due diligence in attempting to locate him and to offer pre-surrender counseling in accordance with Article 1120.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1132__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon approval of the mother's surrender by the court, notice of the filing of the
mother's surrender shall be served upon the alleged or adjudicated father unless any of the
following apply:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1132__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>His potential parental rights have been terminated by a judgment in accordance
with Title X of this Code.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1132__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>He has executed a surrender in accordance with this Title.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1132__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>He has given his consent in open court in accordance with Article 1195.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1132__subsec_B__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>He has executed a release of claims in accordance with Article 1196.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1132__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the alleged or adjudicated father is a minor, his parents or tutor shall be served
if required by Article 1113.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1132__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The notice of the surrender shall be issued by the clerk and shall contain the
following information in substantially the following form:
&quot;NOTICE OF FILING OF SURRENDER
Be advised that on the ___ day of ___, 20__, an authentic Act of Surrender executed
by ______ was filed wherein she surrendered for adoption her child, namely _____, born on
the ___ day of  _____, __, in the Parish of _____, State of ____.
The Act of Surrender alleges that you are the father of this child.  You may attempt
to oppose the adoption of this child only by filing a written objection with this court within
fifteen days after you receive this notice.
If you file a written objection timely, the court will then hold a hearing within twenty
days of the filing of the opposition, to determine whether you have established or forfeited
your parental rights.
To establish your parental rights to oppose the adoption, you must acknowledge that
you are the father of the child or be found to be the father by court order as a result of blood
tests.  Thereafter, you must also demonstrate to the court that you are a fit parent who is
willing and able to assume the legal and physical care of your child.  You must also
demonstrate that you have made a substantial commitment to your parental responsibilities
by providing or attempting to provide substantial and consistent support for the mother
during pregnancy or after the child's birth and by frequently and consistently visiting or
attempting to visit the child after birth.
If you fail to file a written motion of opposition, or if, after a hearing on a motion
timely filed, the court finds that you have failed to establish your parental right to oppose the
adoption, the court will order the termination of any and all parental rights you may have and
the child may be subject to adoption.&quot;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=72619</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>