<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-603-1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-603-1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 603.1"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-603-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-603-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-603-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-603-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-603-1">
        <num>CHC 603.1</num>
        <heading>603.1.  Required education; reporting child abuse</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-603-1__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Every person graduating from any teacher preparation program in Louisiana shall
have had in his curriculum instruction on the requirements of and how to report suspected
child abuse cases pursuant to Article 601 et seq., as well as instruction on how to identify the
signs and symptoms of child neglect and abuse, including sexual abuse, in order to receive
his teacher certification.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-603-1__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Teaching or child care providers as defined by Article 603 shall complete an
online training course provided by the Department of Children and Family Services between
June first and August thirty-first annually. A record of completion of the course by the
teaching or child care provider shall be provided to  each entity at which the teaching or child
care provider is employed.  No later than September thirtieth of each year and in a manner
prescribed by the state Department of Education each entity at which a teaching or child care
provider is employed shall submit a list to the state Department of Education of all teaching
and child care providers employed by the entity and identify the employees that have
complied with the training requirements and those employees that have not complied. The
state Department of Education shall publish the completion rates for each entity on its
website.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=113483</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>