<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-885-1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-885-1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 885.1"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-885-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-885-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-885-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-885-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-885-1">
        <num>CCRP 885.1</num>
        <heading>885.1.  Suspension of driving privileges; failure to pay criminal fines</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-885-1__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>When a fine is levied against a person convicted of any criminal offense,
including any violation of the Louisiana Highway Regulatory Act or any municipal or parish
ordinance regulating traffic, and the court grants the defendant an extension of time to pay
the fine, if at the expiration of the extended period granted by the court, the defendant shows
that he is financially unable to pay the fine, the judge of the court having jurisdiction shall
grant the person an extension of time, not to exceed one hundred eighty days, in which to pay
the fine, or offer the person, in lieu of paying the fine, the alternative of performing
community service as set by the judge.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-885-1__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If, at the expiration of the one-hundred-eighty-day period granted by the judge
pursuant to Paragraph A of this Article, the judge determines that the defendant has either
willfully not paid the fine or has not performed the community service, the judge may do
either of the following:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-885-1__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For any offense that involves the operation of any motor vehicle, aircraft,
watercraft, or other means of conveyance as a necessary element of proof in the commission
of the offense, order the person's driver's license to be surrendered to the sheriff or official
of the court collecting fines, and the sheriff or official of the court designated to collect fines
shall forward the license to the Department of Public Safety and Corrections.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-885-1__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Grant the person an extension of time to either pay the fine or perform the
community service.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-885-1__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the person's license is surrendered pursuant to Subparagraph (B)</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-885-1__subsec_C__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this
Article, upon receipt of the defendant's surrendered driver's license, the department shall
suspend the driver's license of the defendant.  The suspension shall begin when the
department receives written notification from the court, and the department shall send
immediate written notification to the defendant informing him of the suspension of driving
privileges.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-885-1__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The department shall not reinstate, return, reissue, or renew a driver's license in
its possession pursuant to this Article until payment of the fine and any additional
administrative cost, fee, or penalty required by the judge having the jurisdiction and any other
cost, fee, or penalty required by the department in accordance with R.S. 32:414(H) or other
applicable cost, fee, or penalty provision.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-885-1__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, if the person against whom
the fine is levied is financially unable to pay the fine, the provisions of this Article shall not
apply and the judge of the court shall not order that the person's driver's license be
surrendered for failure to pay such fine, unless the court determines that the defendant is
financially able but has willfully refused to pay the fine, or to perform the community service
ordered as an alternative to the fine pursuant to the provisions of this Article.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=191013</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>