<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-253"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-253"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCP 253"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-253/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-253/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-253/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-253/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCP-253">
        <num>CCP 253</num>
        <heading>253.  Pleadings, documents, and exhibits to be filed with clerk</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCP-253__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>All pleadings or documents to be filed in an action or proceeding instituted or
pending in a court, and all exhibits introduced in evidence, shall be delivered or transmitted
to the clerk of the court for that purpose. The clerk of court shall endorse thereon the fact and
date of filing and shall retain possession thereof for inclusion in the record, or in the files of
the clerk's office, as required by law. The endorsement of the fact and date of filing shall be
made upon receipt of the pleadings or documents by the clerk of court and shall be made
without regard to whether there are orders in connection therewith to be signed by the court.
B.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-253__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The filings as provided in Paragraph A of this Article and all other provisions
of this Chapter may be transmitted electronically in accordance with a system established by
the clerk of court. The clerk of court shall adopt a system for the electronic filing and storage
of any pleading, document, or exhibit filed with a pleading. A pleading or document filed
electronically is deemed filed on the date and time stated on the confirmation of electronic
filing sent from the system, if the clerk of court accepts the electronic filing. Public access
to electronically filed pleadings and documents shall be in accordance with the rules
governing access to paper filings.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-253__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>On and after January 1, 2026, all filings as provided in Paragraph A of this
Article and all other provisions of this Chapter filed by an attorney shall only be filed in
person in paper form or transmitted electronically in accordance with a system established
by a clerk of court or by Louisiana Clerks' Remote Access Authority. The filer shall be
responsible for ensuring that private information is not included in filings. No filing shall
include the first five digits of any social security number, tax identification numbers, state
identification numbers, driver's license numbers, financial account numbers, full dates of
birth, or any information protected from disclosure by state or federal law.  The clerk of court
shall adopt a system for the electronic filing and storage of any pleading, document, or
exhibit filed with a pleading.  A pleading or document filed electronically is deemed filed
on the date and time stated on the confirmation of electronic filing sent from the system, if
the clerk of court accepts the electronic filing.  Public access to electronically filed pleadings
and documents shall be in accordance with the rules governing access to paper filings.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-253__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of Subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-253__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Paragraph, the
following original documents may be filed in paper form, either in person, by U.S. mail, or
by commercial courier:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CCP-253__subsec_A__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An original will or testament filed and retained in accordance with Article 2911.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCP-253__subsec_A__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An original promissory note, other instrument, or any evidence required to be in
authentic form in accordance with Article 2635.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCP-253__subsec_A__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Motions for default judgment which do not require a hearing in open court
pursuant to Articles 1702 and 1702.1 and supporting attached documentation.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCP-253__subsec_A__subsec_2__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Documents which are required to be original in order to support or defend against
a claim.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-253__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The clerk of court may convert into an electronic record any pleading, document,
or exhibit that is filed in paper form. If requested by the filing party, the clerk of court shall
return to the filing party the original of any document or exhibit that has been converted into
an electronic record.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-253__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The official record shall be the electronic record. The original of any filed
document or exhibit shall be maintained by the filing party during the pendency of the
proceeding and until the judgment becomes final and definitive, unless otherwise provided
by law or order of the court. Upon request and reasonable notice, the original document or
exhibit shall be produced to the court. Upon reasonable notice, the original document or
exhibit shall be made available to the opposing party for inspection.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-253__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Unless otherwise directed by the court, the original of all documents and exhibits
introduced or proffered into evidence, submitted with a petition for executory process, or
filed in a summary judgment proceeding shall be retained by the clerk of court until the order
or judgment becomes final and definitive.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-253__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A judge or justice presiding over a court in this state may sign a court order,
notice, official court document, and other writings required to be executed in connection with
court proceedings by use of an electronic signature as defined by R.S. 9:2602.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-253__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the filing party fails to comply with any of the requirements of Paragraph A or
Subparagraph (B)</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-253__subsec_G__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Article, the electronic filing shall have no force or effect. A court
may provide by court rule for other matters related to filings by electronic transmission.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-253__subsec_H">
          <num>H.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The clerk of court may procure equipment, services, and supplies necessary to
accommodate electronic filings out of the clerk's salary fund.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-253__subsec_I">
          <num>I.</num>
          <content>
            <p>All electronic filings shall include an electronic signature. For the purpose of this
Article, &quot;electronic signature&quot; means an electronic symbol or process attached to or logically
associated with a record and executed or adopted by a person with the intent to sign the
record.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-253__subsec_J">
          <num>J.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The clerk of court shall not refuse to accept for filing any pleading or other
document that is signed by electronic signature and executed in connection with court
proceedings, or that complies with the procedures for electronic filing implemented pursuant
to this Article, solely on the ground that the pleading or document was signed by electronic
signature.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-253__subsec_K">
          <num>K.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon adoption of uniform filing standards by the LCRAA, no clerk of court shall
accept a filing not in accordance with the adopted standards.
Amended by</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=111473</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>