<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-644"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-644"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 644"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-644/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-644/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-644/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-644/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-644">
        <num>CCRP 644</num>
        <heading>644.  Appointment of sanity commission; examination of defendant</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-644__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Within seven days after a mental examination is ordered, the court shall appoint
a sanity commission to examine and report upon the mental condition of the defendant.  The
sanity commission shall consist of at least two and not more than three members who are
licensed to practice medicine in Louisiana, who have been in the actual practice of medicine
for not less than three consecutive years immediately preceding the appointment, and who
are qualified by training or experience in forensic evaluations.  The court may appoint, in lieu
of one physician, a clinical psychologist or medical psychologist who is licensed to practice
psychology in Louisiana, who has been engaged in the practice of clinical or counseling
psychology for not less than three consecutive years immediately preceding the appointment,
and who is qualified by training or experience in forensic evaluations.  Every sanity
commission shall have at least one psychiatrist as a member of the commission, unless one
is not reasonably available, in which case, the commission shall have at least one clinical
psychologist as a member of the commission.  No more than one member of the sanity
commission shall be the coroner or any of his deputies.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-644__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The members of the sanity commission appointed to make the examination shall
have free access to the defendant at all reasonable times.  The court shall subpoena witnesses
to attend the examination at the request of the defendant, the commission, or any member
thereof.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-644__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the purpose of the mental examination, the court may order a defendant
previously released on bail to appear for mental examinations and hearings in the same
manner as other criminal proceedings.
D.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-644__subsec_C__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The court, in any judicial district which enters into a cooperative endeavor
agreement with the local mental health unit, in lieu of appointing a sanity commission as
provided in Paragraph A, may appoint the local mental health unit to examine and report on
the mental condition of the defendant.  If the local mental health unit is ordered to conduct
the examination, it shall form a clinical team, consisting of at least two but not more than
three members, to conduct the examination.  The clinical team shall be composed of one or
more licensed physicians with at least three years experience in the study of psychiatry in an
approved United States General Psychiatry Residency Program; if only one such licensed
physician is a member of the clinical team, the remaining members of the clinical team may
be composed of clinical psychologists, medical psychologists, or licensed clinical social
workers, who are qualified by training or experience in forensic evaluations.
(2)</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-644__subsec_C__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>With respect to all other provisions of the Code of Criminal Procedure in
which the term &quot;sanity commission&quot; is designated, it shall also mean and include, for the
exclusive purpose of this Article, a clinical team designated by the local health unit to
conduct the examination of the defendant in accordance with this Paragraph.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-644__subsec_C__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;Local mental health unit&quot; as used in this Paragraph shall mean a legislatively
created Human Services Authority.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112663</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>