<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-648"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-648"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 648"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-648/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-648/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-648/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-648/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-648">
        <num>CCRP 648</num>
        <heading>648.  Procedure after determination of mental capacity or incapacity</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-648__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The criminal prosecution shall be resumed unless the court determines by a
preponderance of the evidence that the defendant does not have the mental capacity to
proceed.  If the court determines that the defendant lacks mental capacity to proceed, the
proceedings shall be suspended and one of the following dispositions made:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-648__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the court determines that the defendant's mental capacity is likely to be restored
within ninety days by outpatient care and treatment at a treatment facility as defined by R.S.
28:2 while remaining in the custody of the criminal authorities, and if the person is not
charged with a felony or a misdemeanor classified as an offense against the person and is
considered by the court to be unlikely to commit crimes of violence, then the court may order
outpatient care and treatment at any institution as defined by R.S. 28:2.
(2)</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-648__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Except as otherwise provided for in Subsubparagraph</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-648__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this Subparagraph,
if the person is charged with a felony, or with a misdemeanor violation of R.S. 14:35.3, and
is considered by the court to be likely to commit crimes of violence, and the court determines
that his mental capacity is likely to be restored within ninety days as a result of treatment, the
court may order immediate jail-based treatment by the Louisiana Department of Health not
to exceed ninety days.  Otherwise, if his capacity cannot be restored within ninety days and
inpatient treatment is recommended, the court shall commit the defendant to the Feliciana
Forensic Facility.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-648__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If a person is charged with a felony violation of the Uniform Controlled
Dangerous Substances Law, except for violations punishable under the provisions of R.S.
40:966(D) and (F) and 967(F)</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-648__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>and (c),</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-648__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If a person is charged with a misdemeanor classified as an offense against a
person, except for a misdemeanor violation of R.S. 14:35.3, and the court determines that his
mental capacity cannot be restored within ninety days, the court shall release the person for
outpatient competency restoration or other appropriate treatment.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-648__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If a defendant committed to the Feliciana Forensic Facility is held in a parish jail
for one hundred eighty days after the court's determination that he lacks the mental capacity
to proceed, the court shall order a status conference to be held with the defense and the
district attorney present, and for good cause shown and on motion of the defendant or the
district attorney or on the court's own motion, the court shall order a contradictory hearing
to determine whether there has been a change in the defendant's condition or other
circumstances sufficient to warrant a modification of the previous order.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-648__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If a defendant committed to the Feliciana Forensic Facility is held in a parish jail
for one hundred eighty days after the initial status conference provided in Subsubparagraph</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-648__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this Subparagraph, the court shall order a contradictory hearing to determine whether
to release the defendant or to order the appropriate authorities to institute civil commitment
proceedings pursuant to R.S. 28:54.  The defendant shall remain in custody pending such
civil commitment proceedings.  If the defendant is civilly committed to a treatment facility
pursuant to Title 28 of the Louisiana Revised Statutes of 1950, the director of the institution
designated for the patient's treatment shall, in writing, notify the court and the district
attorney when the patient is to be discharged or conditionally discharged, as long as the
charges are pending.
B.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-648__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In no instance shall such custody, care, and treatment exceed the time of the
maximum sentence the defendant could receive if convicted of the crime with which he is
charged. At any time after commitment and on the recommendation of the director or
administrator of the treatment facility that the defendant will not attain the capacity to
proceed with his trial in the foreseeable future, the court shall, within sixty days and after at
least ten days notice to the district attorney, defendant's counsel, and the bureau of legal
services of the Louisiana Department of Health, conduct a contradictory hearing to determine
whether the defendant is, and will in the foreseeable future be, incapable of standing trial and
whether he is a danger to himself or others.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-648__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Repealed by</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112667</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>