<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-833"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-833"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 833"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-833/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-833/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-833/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-833/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-833">
        <num>CCRP 833</num>
        <heading>833.  Presence of defendant; misdemeanor prosecution</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-833__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court may permit an unrepresented or pro se defendant charged with a
misdemeanor to be arraigned, enter his plea of guilty, or be tried, in his absence.
B.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-833__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A plea of not guilty of a misdemeanor may be allowed to be entered through
counsel of record.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-833__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A plea of not guilty of a misdemeanor shall be allowed to be entered through
counsel of record in the absence of the defendant by the filing of a sworn affidavit in advance
of the scheduled arraignment date.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-833__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The sworn affidavit referenced in Subparagraph (B)</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-833__subsec_C__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Article shall include
the caption of the case and summons number, citation number or docket number as
applicable, and state as follows:
AFFIDAVIT ACCEPTING SERVICE AND
WAIVER OF PRESENCE
BEFORE ME, the undersigned authority, did personally come and appear,
____________(CLIENT'S NAME), who after being duly sworn did depose and say:
1.
Affiant acknowledges that he is the defendant in the above captioned criminal matter;
that he is aware of all charges pending against him in this matter and that he has retained the
services of ____________ (ATTORNEY(S) or LAW FIRM) to represent him in these
proceedings;
2.
Affiant is aware that he is scheduled to be in court on the ______ day of ______,
20__ at ___ o'clock and that he has the right to be present on that day but expressly wishes
to waive this right and to have his legal counsel appear on his behalf;
3.
Affiant is aware that in his absence, additional court dates could be scheduled in these
proceedings and he hereby appoints his above named legal counsel as his agent</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-833__subsec_C__subsec_2__subsec_s">
              <num>(s)</num>
              <content>
                <p>to accept
service of notice to appear for those dates on his behalf, that he accepts service of those dates
through his counsel and that he expressly waives his appearance for those dates and
authorizes his counsel to appear on his behalf;4.
Affiant understands that the court, in its sole discretion, may revoke its acceptance
of this waiver and require that affiant personally appear in open court on subsequent court
dates; that his counsel will also be notified; that a notice of appearance will be mailed to
affiant at his address of record and that affiant's failure to appear at the subsequent court date
could result in the issuance of an arrest warrant, a revocation of appearance bond and/or is
punishable as contempt of court;
5.
Finally, Affiant acknowledges that his current address is:
_______________(Street, Apt/Lot No, City, State and Zip Code); and authorizes the
court to use this address for all notices, unless changed in writing by affiant.
____________________________________
Affiant
SWORN TO AND SUBSCRIBED BEFORE ME, notary, this ____ day of
______, 20__.
____________________________________
NOTARY PUBLIC</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112823</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>