<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1568"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1568"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 1568"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1568/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1568/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1568/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1568/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-1568">
        <num>CHC 1568</num>
        <heading>1568.  Petition</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1568__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A petition filed under the provisions of this Chapter shall contain the following:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1568__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The name of each petitioner and each person on whose behalf the petition is filed
and the name, address, and parish of residence of each individual alleged to have committed
abuse, if known.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1568__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the petition is being filed on behalf of a child or person alleged to be
incompetent, the relationship between that person and the petitioner.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1568__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The facts and circumstances concerning the alleged abuse.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1568__subsec_A__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The relationship between each petitioner and each individual alleged to have
committed abuse.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1568__subsec_A__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A request for one or more protective orders or a temporary restraining order.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1568__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The address and parish of residence of each petitioner and each person on whose
behalf the petition is filed may remain confidential with the court.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1568__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the petition requests a protective order for a spouse and alleges that the other
spouse has committed abuse, the petition shall state whether a suit for divorce is pending.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1568__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the petition requests the issuance of an ex parte temporary restraining order, the
petition shall contain a written affirmation signed and dated by each petitioner that the facts
and circumstances contained in the petition are true and correct to the best knowledge,
information, and belief of the petitioner, under penalty of perjury pursuant to R.S. 14:123. 
The affirmation shall be made before a witness who shall sign and print his name.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1568__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a suit for divorce is pending, any application for a protective order shall be filed
in that proceeding and shall be heard within the delays provided by this Chapter.  Any decree
issued in a divorce proceeding filed subsequent to the filing of a petition or an order issued
pursuant to this Chapter may, in the discretion of the court hearing the divorce proceeding,
supersede in whole or in part the orders issued pursuant to this Chapter. Such subsequent
decree shall be forwarded by the rendering court to the court having jurisdiction of the
petition for a protective order and shall be made a part of the record thereof.  The findings
and rulings made in connection with such protective orders shall not be res judicata in any
subsequent proceeding.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=73026</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>