<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-9-1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-9-1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="SRULE 9.1"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-9-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-9-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-9-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-9-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_SRULE-9-1">
        <num>SRULE 9.1</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-9-1__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>At any time between regular sessions, but no later than ten days before the
beginning of a regular session for joint resolutions proposing a constitutional amendment,
or no later than five o'clock in the evening of the forty-fifth calendar day prior to the first
day of a regular session for bills relative to retirement, or no later than five o'clock in the
evening of the tenth calendar day prior to the first day of a regular session for all other
bills, senators may prefile with the Secretary legislative instruments that are proposed for
introduction at the next session.  However, no instrument shall be prefiled between final
adjournment of the last regular session of a legislative term and promulgation of the
returns of the general election for members of the legislature for the next succeeding
term. After the promulgation of the election returns, any member-elect may prefile
instruments for introduction at the next regular session.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-9-1__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>No legislative instrument shall be prefiled without the written consent of the
author or, in case of more than one author, the written consent of at least the primary
author.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-9-1__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A request for legislation that is to be prefiled must be received by Senate
Legislative Services staff not later than forty-eight hours prior to the prefiling deadline
applicable to the instrument being requested.
SR 3 of 1994 2 nd EX; SR 6 of 2008 RS; SR 11 of 2010 RS.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=180551</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>