<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-791-1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-791-1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 791.1"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-791-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-791-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-791-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-791-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-791-1">
        <num>CHC 791.1</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <content>
          <p>CHAPTER 15.  TRUANCY ASSESSMENT SERVICE CENTERS
Art. 791.1.  Purpose
The purpose of this Chapter is to authorize the creation of truancy assessment service
centers.  Truancy has long been demonstrated nationwide as a primary indicator of a path to
juvenile delinquency.  Parishes and judicial districts have demonstrated a willingness to
address truancy by providing a physical location in each parish where personnel from local
schools, law enforcement, courts exercising jurisdiction over juveniles, district attorneys,
correction and substance abuse counselors, and family and child-serving agencies can work
together in a coordinated effort.  Early intervention has been demonstrated as the key to
providing the greatest chance for correcting the actions of juveniles who demonstrate a
propensity for destructive or criminal behavior.  The earliest possible venue for addressing
the problem begins in kindergarten.  By intervening at this phase, it is possible to correct
potential delinquent behavior before the chances for correction become insurmountable.  The
centers will address the underlying causes of truancy by pooling existing resources targeted
at the child and family through appropriate action by service and treatment agencies.</p>
        </content>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=73384</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>