<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-627"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-627"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 627"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-627/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-627/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-627/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-627/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-627">
        <num>CHC 627</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-627__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Following a hearing, the court may return the child to the parents or, in
accordance with Article 622, may place the child in the custody of a suitable relative, other
suitable individual, or  the department.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-627__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a child is not returned to the parents, the court shall place the child in the
custody of a suitable relative unless the court has made a specific finding that such placement
is not in the best interest of the child.  The court shall give specific oral and written reasons
for its findings, which shall be made a part of the record of the proceeding.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-627__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the court finds that the child can be safely returned home under a protective
order pending adjudication, the court may order return of the child and issue protective
orders as are deemed necessary for the health, welfare, and safety of the child.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-627__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a protective order is issued or modified, the judge shall cause to have prepared
a Uniform Abuse Prevention Order, as provided in R.S. 46:2136.2(C), shall sign such order,
and shall forward it to the clerk of court for filing, all without delay, and the clerk of the
issuing court shall transmit the Uniform Abuse Prevention Order to the Louisiana Protective
Order Registry, R.S. 46:2136.2(A), by facsimile transmission, mail, or direct electronic input,
where available, as expeditiously as possible, but no later than the end of the next business
day after the order is filed with the clerk of court.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-627__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the court finds that the child can safely remain in or return to the home with the
implementation of a safety plan developed and agreed upon by the state pending
adjudication, the court may order compliance with the conditions of the safety plan.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-627__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the court orders that the child be placed in the custody of a suitable relative or
other suitable individual, it shall make a safety plan part of its order.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-627__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court shall order the appointment of a curator for any parent who is an
absentee.  The court may order the appointment of a court-appointed special advocate.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=73220</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>