<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-848"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-848"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 848"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-848/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-848/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-848/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-848/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-848">
        <num>CHC 848</num>
        <heading>848.  Notice of right to counsel; form</heading>
        <content>
          <p>Art. 848.  Notice of right to counsel; form
&quot;NOTICE
RIGHT TO COUNSEL
Under the laws of Louisiana, every child accused of delinquency is entitled to have a lawyer to be present and to assist the child to answer the attached petition.  A child is entitled to be represented by a lawyer at every stage of proceedings in the juvenile court, including the right to appeal from any judgment of disposition which might be ordered by the court.
If the parents of an accused child are completely financially unable to afford to employ a lawyer, the court will appoint a lawyer and the state will pay for his services.
If the parents are found to be financially able to afford to employ a lawyer but fail to employ one, the juvenile court may appoint a lawyer for the child and require the parents to pay for the lawyer's services.
The financial ability or inability of the parents to employ a lawyer will be determined by the court after a hearing.  The court may require the parents to pay for some or all of the costs of lawyer's services on behalf of the child.
After consulting with parents or other adult interested in the child's welfare, the child may be permitted by the court to proceed without the assistance of a lawyer.  This decision can be made at any time during the proceedings in the juvenile court.&quot;</p>
        </content>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=73439</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>