<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1269-3"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1269-3"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 1269.3"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1269-3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1269-3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1269-3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1269-3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-1269-3">
        <num>CHC 1269.3</num>
        <heading>1269.3.  Continuing contact agreement; parties; required declarations</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1269-3__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Every post-adoption contact agreement shall be in writing and signed by the
adopting parents and by any adult granted contact.  If a sibling granted contact is a minor, his
parent or legal custodian shall sign the agreement.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1269-3__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In an agency adoption in which the department is the custodian of the child, the
department and counsel for the child shall report to the court approval or objection to the
agreement and the child's wishes concerning continuing contact.  The court-appointed special
advocate (CASA) for the child, if any, may also submit recommendations to the court
regarding a proposed agreement.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1269-3__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If requested by the parties, the court may refer them to mediation to assist them
in confecting a continuing contact agreement.  If necessary to ensure that the child's best
interest is taken into account, the court may also appoint independent counsel for any child
involved in future continuing contact.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1269-3__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A continuing contact agreement may authorize the exchange of information,
communication by telephone, mail, e-mail, or other means, and direct visitation in either the
adopting parents' home or elsewhere through a mutually agreed-upon intermediary.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1269-3__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Every agreement, in order to be enforceable in accordance with Article 1269.8,
must recite the following declarations:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1269-3__subsec_E__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The parties have freely and voluntarily entered into the agreement and it reflects
their intent to be bound by its terms, unless later modified by a replacement agreement or by
court order.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1269-3__subsec_E__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The sibling, grandparent, parent, or other relative by blood, adoption, or affinity,
or his representative, if any, has been counseled and advised by the department, by counsel,
or by other appropriate professional about the meaning of these declarations and the effects
of a continuing contact agreement and each has had the opportunity to have the agreement
reviewed by his counsel.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1269-3__subsec_E__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The sibling, grandparent, parent, or other relative by blood, adoption, or affinity,
or his representative, has been informed and understands that upon the execution of the
agreement, any dispute or litigation regarding its terms shall not affect the validity of any
surrender, termination of parental rights, adoption, or custody of the adopted child.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1269-3__subsec_E__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The adopting parents have been informed and understand that the sibling,
grandparent, parent, or other relative by blood, adoption, or affinity may seek enforcement
of the terms of the agreement in accordance with Article 1269.8.
NOTE: Subsection F eff. until October 1, 2027. See</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=72746</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>