<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-116"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-116"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 116"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-116/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-116/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-116/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-116/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-116">
        <num>CHC 116</num>
        <heading>116.  Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-116__subsec_1">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Act&quot; includes a failure or omission to perform a legal duty.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-116__subsec_2">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Capital offense&quot; means an offense that may be punished by death.
(2.1)  &quot;CASA program&quot; means a court-appointed special advocate program
established in compliance with  Louisiana CASA Association standards.
(2.2)  &quot;CASA volunteer&quot; means a court-appointed special advocate who has been
trained in accordance with  Louisiana CASA Association standards and is under the
supervision of a CASA program.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-116__subsec_3">
          <num>(3)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Child&quot; means a person who has not attained the age of eighteen years, except
as it is specially defined by a Title of this Code.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-116__subsec_4">
          <num>(4)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Court&quot; means any city, parish, district, or juvenile, or its judge, when exercising
juvenile jurisdiction as provided for in this Code.  It does not include a judge of a mayor's
court or a justice of the peace.
(4.1)  &quot;Diligent effort to locate&quot; means efforts made by a curator that, under the
circumstances known to the curator, are reasonably calculated to locate an absentee. Such
efforts may include a review of court records, department records, law enforcement records,
vital records, military records, directory assistance, internet search sites, and licensing
agencies.  Publication shall not be required except as specifically provided in this Code.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-116__subsec_5">
          <num>(5)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Felony&quot; means an offense that may be punished by death or by imprisonment
at hard labor.
(5.1)  &quot;Guardianship&quot; means the judicial placement of a child under the duty and
authority of a guardian to make decisions in matters having a permanent effect on the life and
development of the child as set forth in Article 719.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-116__subsec_6">
          <num>(6)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Home study&quot; means an evaluation of a home environment conducted in
accordance with applicable requirements of the state in which the home is located to
determine whether a proposed placement of a child would meet the individual needs of the
child, including the child's safety, permanency, health, well-being, and mental, emotional,
and physical development.
(6.1)  &quot;Indian child&quot; means any unmarried child under eighteen years of age who is
a member of an Indian tribe or who is eligible for membership in an Indian tribe and is the
biological child of a member of an Indian tribe.
(6.2)  &quot;Indian tribe&quot; means any Indian tribe, band, nation, or other organized group
or community of Indians recognized as eligible for the services provided to Indians by the
Secretary of the Interior in accordance with their status as Indians.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-116__subsec_7">
          <num>(7)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Indictment&quot; means a written accusation of crime made by a grand jury.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-116__subsec_8">
          <num>(8)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Information&quot; means a written accusation of crime  made and signed by the
district attorney or the city prosecutor.  It must be filed in open court in a court having
jurisdiction to try the offense, or in the office of the clerk thereof.
(8.1)  &quot;Interstate home study&quot; means a home study conducted by a state at the request
of another state to facilitate an adoptive or foster placement in the state of a child in foster
care under the responsibility of the state.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-116__subsec_9">
          <num>(9)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Judge&quot; means the judge of a court exercising juvenile jurisdiction.
(9.1)  &quot;Juvenile crime victim&quot; means a person, under the age of seventeen, against
whom a felony offense against the person has been committed.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-116__subsec_10">
          <num>(10)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Juvenile detention center&quot; means the same as a secure detention facility.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-116__subsec_11">
          <num>(11)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Juvenile proceeding&quot; or &quot;juvenile case&quot; means a proceeding or case in which
the court is exercising juvenile jurisdiction.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-116__subsec_12">
          <num>(12)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Legal custody&quot; means the right to have physical custody of the child and to
determine where and with whom the child shall reside; to exercise the rights and duty to
protect, train, and discipline the child; the authority to consent to major medical, psychiatric,
and surgical treatment; and to provide the child with food, shelter, education, and ordinary
medical care, all subject to any residual rights possessed by the child's parents.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-116__subsec_13">
          <num>(13)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Licensed institution&quot;, &quot;licensed facility&quot;, or &quot;licensed agency&quot; means an
institution or agency that has been licensed under state law, if licensure is required by law
for such an institution or agency.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-116__subsec_14">
          <num>(14)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Minor&quot; means a person who has not attained the age of eighteen years.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-116__subsec_15">
          <num>(15)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Misdemeanor&quot; means an offense other than a felony, and includes the violation
of an ordinance providing a penal sanction.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-116__subsec_16">
          <num>(16)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Offense&quot; includes both felony and misdemeanor.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-116__subsec_17">
          <num>(17)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Parent&quot; means any living person who is presumed to be a parent under the Civil
Code or a biological or adoptive mother or father of a child.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-116__subsec_18">
          <num>(18)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Parole&quot; means the legal status created by court order whereby a child is
conditionally released from a juvenile correctional institution to a less restrictive setting
where continued supervision will be provided by a probation officer and standards of conduct
will be imposed by the court.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-116__subsec_19">
          <num>(19)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Peace officer&quot; means any sheriff, police officer, or other person deputized by
proper authority to serve as a peace officer.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-116__subsec_20">
          <num>(20)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Physician&quot; means a person permitted to practice and in active practice as a
physician under the laws of Louisiana or a person in a postgraduate medical training program
of an accredited medical school in Louisiana or a medical officer similarly qualified by the
government of the United States while in this state in the performance of official duties.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-116__subsec_21">
          <num>(21)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Probation&quot; means the legal status created by court order following an
adjudication of delinquency or an adjudication that a family is in need of services or that the
child is in need of supervision, whereby a child is permitted to remain in a community
subject to supervision by a probation officer and to standards of conduct imposed by the
court.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-116__subsec_22">
          <num>(22)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Probation officer&quot; is a representative of the agency providing supervision
services to a court exercising juvenile jurisdiction.  It also includes any person designated by
the court to serve as the court's probation officer.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-116__subsec_23">
          <num>(23)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Psychiatrist&quot; means a physician who has at least three years of formal training
or primary experience in the diagnosis and treatment of mental illness.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-116__subsec_24">
          <num>(24)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Residual parental rights&quot; means those rights and responsibilities remaining
with the parents after the legal transfer of custody of their child, including but not necessarily
limited to right of visitation, consent to adoption, right to determine religious affiliation,
responsibility of support, and the right of inheritance from the child.
(24.1)  &quot;Secure detention facility&quot; means a facility that provides a physically
restricting environment for the temporary care of children in accordance with the Minimum
Standards for Licensure of the Louisiana Detention Association.
(24.2) &quot;Secure placement&quot; means a placement characterized by a range of moderate
to high security level facilities that include construction, fixtures, and staff supervision
designed to restrict the movements and activities of the residents, and to control, on a twenty-four-hour basis, the ability of the residents to enter and leave the premises, and which are
intended for the treatment and rehabilitation of children who have been adjudicated
delinquent. Secure placements shall include but are not limited to secure correctional centers
for children and may include community-based secure detention facilities. However, no
placement of a child to a community-based secure detention facility shall occur when a child
has been adjudicated for the commission of a crime listed in Article 897.1 unless notice of
such placement is provided to the committing judge and the district attorney.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-116__subsec_25">
          <num>(25)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Shelter care facility&quot; means a licensed, physically unrestricting public or private
child caring facility, a residential facility operated for runaway, homeless, or sexually
exploited children, or a safe house as defined in Article 725.1 which provides temporary care
for children.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-116__subsec_26">
          <num>(26)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;State&quot; includes a city or other political subdivision of the state.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-116__subsec_27">
          <num>(27)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Statute&quot; or &quot;law&quot; means a statute, a constitutional provision, or an ordinance
of a city or other political subdivision of the state.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-116__subsec_28">
          <num>(28)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Tutor&quot; means one other than a parent who has qualified for the office and has
been confirmed or appointed by a court.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=72638</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>