<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-334"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-334"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 334"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-334/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-334/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-334/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-334/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-334">
        <num>CCRP 334</num>
        <heading>334.  Notice of warrant for arrest</heading>
        <content>
          <p>Art. 334.  Notice of warrant for arrest
After a warrant for arrest is issued, the clerk of court shall, within sixty days of the
defendant's failure to appear, send a notice of warrant for arrest to the prosecuting attorney. 
The notice shall also be sent by United States mail or electronic means to the defendant, the
bail agent or bondsman, if any, and the personal surety.  Notice shall be sent by electronic
means or by certified mail return receipt requested to the commercial surety.  When the agent
or bondsman has filed a &quot;Notice of Electronic Notification Opt In&quot; form with the clerk of
court, the notice of warrant for arrest shall be sent to the agent or bondsman by electronic
means.  All notices shall be sent to the addresses provided pursuant to Article 329 or an
address registered with the Department of Insurance. The notice to the commercial surety
shall include the power of attorney number used to execute the bail undertaking.  Failure to
include the power of attorney number shall not affect the validity or enforcement of a
resulting judgment.  After sending the notice of warrant for arrest, the clerk of court shall
execute a certificate that notice was sent and place the certificate in the record.  Failure to
send notice to the commercial surety and the agent or bondsman who has opted into
electronic notification within sixty days of the defendant's failure to appear shall release the
surety of all obligations under the bail undertaking.</p>
        </content>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112457</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>