<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1283-2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1283-2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 1283.2"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1283-2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1283-2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1283-2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1283-2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-1283-2">
        <num>CHC 1283.2</num>
        <heading>1283.2.  Permissible reimbursement of expenses</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1283-2__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The petitioner shall file with the petition a preliminary estimate and accounting
of fees and charges in accordance with Article 1283.3.  The petitioner also shall file a final
Adoption Disclosure Affidavit with the court not later than ten days prior to the date
scheduled for the final hearing on the adoption.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1283-2__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Payments made by or on behalf of the adoptive parents or their representative to
the department or to a child-placing agency or its agent or any broker for reimbursement of
the following expenses are permissible and not a violation of R.S. 14:286:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1283-2__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Reasonable medical expenses, including hospital, testing, nursing,
pharmaceutical, travel, or other similar expenses incurred by the biological mother for
prenatal care and those medical and hospital expenses incurred by the biological mother and
child incident to birth.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1283-2__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Reasonable medical expenses, including hospital, testing, nursing,
pharmaceutical, travel, or other similar expenses and foster care expenses incurred on behalf
of the child prior to the decree of adoption.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1283-2__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Reasonable expenses incurred by the department or the agency for adjustment
counseling and training services provided to the adoptive parents and for home studies or
investigations.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1283-2__subsec_B__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Reasonable administrative expenses incurred by the department or the agency,
including overhead, court costs, travel costs, donations required by an orphanage, notarial
and interpreter fees, emigration permit costs, and attorney fees.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1283-2__subsec_B__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any other specific service or fee the court finds is reasonable and necessary.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1283-2__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The payment of expenses permitted by Paragraph B may not be made contingent
on the placement of a child for adoption, relinquishment of the child, or consent to the
adoption.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1283-2__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Adoptive parents shall pay to the department any of the expenses listed in
Paragraph A of this Article which may be imposed by the department.  Such payments shall
be imposed solely at the discretion of the department.  The department shall not include
payment of the expenses listed in Paragraph A of this Article as a requirement for adoption.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1283-2__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a court determines from an accounting that an amount that is going to be or has
been disbursed for expenses permitted by Paragraph B is unreasonable, it shall order a
reduction in the amount  disbursed, or to be disbursed, and order the person who received the
disbursement to refund that portion.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1283-2__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a court determines from an accounting that an amount is going to be or has been
disbursed for expenses not permitted by Paragraph B, it may:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1283-2__subsec_F__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Issue an injunction prohibiting the disbursement or order the person who received
the disbursement to refund it.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1283-2__subsec_F__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Inform the district attorney for the consideration of criminal charges pursuant to
R.S. 14:286.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1283-2__subsec_F__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If in the best interest of the child, the court may also refuse to approve the
adoption.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1283-2__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court shall not issue a final decree of adoption until it has reviewed and
approved the final accounting.
NOTE: Subsection H eff. until October 1, 2027. See</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=72784</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>