<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-HRULE-6-8"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-HRULE-6-8"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="HRULE 6.8"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-HRULE-6-8/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-HRULE-6-8/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-HRULE-6-8/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-HRULE-6-8/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_HRULE-6-8">
        <num>HRULE 6.8</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="HRULE-6-8__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The capital outlay bill, being any bill being designated as the &quot;comprehensive
state capital budget&quot; pursuant to the mandate of Paragraph B of Section 11 and Paragraph A
of Section 6 of Article VII of the Constitution shall be referred by the presiding officer to the
Committee on Ways and Means.  The committee's authority and duties with respect to such
instrument shall be as is generally provided by these Rules of Order, except that the
committee shall have no authority to propose amendments to said instrument other than to
those provisions affecting bonds or other evidences of indebtedness, including without
limitation the appropriation of the avails of bonds or other evidences of indebtedness, the
priority of issuance or expenditure thereof and the manner(s) of changing the priority of
issuance or expenditure.  The bill shall be reported in accordance with the provisions of Rule
6.11(A).  After such report, if the measure is ordered engrossed by the House, immediately
following such order, it shall be recommitted by the presiding officer to the Committee on
Appropriations.  The committee's authority and duties with respect to such instrument shall
be as is generally provided by these Rules of Order, except that the committee shall have no
authority to propose amendments to said instrument except those provisions providing for
appropriation of funds other than the avails of bonds or other evidences of indebtedness.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="HRULE-6-8__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any concurrent resolution providing for the adoption of the formula for the
allocation of minimum foundation funds to parish and city school systems shall be referred
by the presiding officer to the Committee on Education.  After the resolution is reported, if
the resolution is ordered engrossed by the House, immediately following such order it shall
be recommitted by the presiding officer to the Committee on Appropriations.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="HRULE-6-8__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any legislative instrument creating a special fund in the state treasury to which
proceeds from taxes, fees, or other charges are dedicated and any legislative instrument
amending provisions of law relative to such a special fund shall be referred to a standing
committee under the provisions of Rule 6.5 and, if reported, shall be reported to the clerk of
the House in accordance with the requirements of Rule 6.11(A).  However, after such report,
any such House instrument ordered engrossed, immediately following the engrossment order,
and any such Senate instrument reported favorably or with amendments, immediately
following the reading of such report and action on any amendments reported, shall be
recommitted by the Speaker to the Committee on Appropriations.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="HRULE-6-8__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any legislative instrument with an estimated fiscal cost of one hundred thousand
dollars or more of state general funds annually in any one of the three ensuing fiscal years
as reflected in the fiscal note prepared in accordance with Joint Rule No. 4, or with a fiscal
cost that, although not specified in the fiscal note, is indicated in the fiscal note as likely to
equal or exceed one hundred thousand dollars of state general funds annually in any of the
three ensuing fiscal years, shall be referred to a standing committee under the provisions of
Rule 6.5 and, if reported, shall be reported to the Clerk of the House in accordance with the
requirements of Rule 6.11(A).  However, after such report, any such House instrument
ordered engrossed, immediately following the engrossment order, and any such Senate
instrument reported favorably or with amendments, immediately following the reading of
such report and action on any amendments reported, shall be recommitted by the Speaker to
the Committee on Appropriations.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="HRULE-6-8__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any legislative instrument which originates in the Senate which produces a net
decrease in fees or increases fees or taxes or which authorizes an increase in fees or taxes of
five hundred thousand dollars or more annually in any one of three ensuing fiscal years as
reflected in the fiscal note prepared in accordance with Joint Rule No. 4 or which provides
for or authorizes an increase in fees or taxes which, although not specified in the fiscal note,
is indicated in the fiscal note to likely exceed five hundred thousand dollars annually in any
of the three ensuing fiscal years shall be referred to a standing committee under the
provisions of Rule 6.5 and, if reported, shall be reported to the Clerk of the House in
accordance with the requirements of Rule 6.11(A).  However, after such report, any such
Senate instrument reported favorably or with amendments, immediately following the
reading of such report and action on any amendments reported, shall be recommitted by the
Speaker to the Committee on Ways and Means.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="HRULE-6-8__subsec_H">
          <num>H.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any legislative instrument which contains a provision or provisions the effect of
which exempts or excepts certain information from the laws relative to public records,
having been referred to a standing committee other than the Committee on House and
Governmental Affairs under the provisions of Rule 6.5, if reported, shall be reported in
accordance with the requirements of Rule 6.11(A).  However, after such report, any such
House instrument ordered engrossed, immediately following the engrossment order, and any
such Senate instrument reported favorably or with amendments, immediately following the
reading of such report and action on any amendments reported, shall be recommitted by the
speaker to the Committee on House and Governmental Affairs.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="HRULE-6-8__subsec_I">
          <num>I.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any legislative instrument which contains a provision or provisions the effect of
which provides that the state join an interstate compact, having been referred to a standing
committee other than the Committee on House and Governmental Affairs under the
provisions of Rule 6.5, if reported, shall be reported in accordance with the requirements of
Rule 6.11(A).  However, after such report, any such House instrument ordered engrossed,
immediately following the engrossment order, and any such Senate instrument reported
favorably or with amendments, immediately following the reading of such report and action
on any amendments reported, shall be recommitted by the Speaker to the Committee on
House and Governmental Affairs.
Mason's Manual:  Sec. 620
HR 3, 1975; HR 6, 1977; HR 12, 1977; HR 13, 1977; HR 4, 1978; HR 18, 1979; HR
6, 1981; HR 23, 1981; HR 7, 1984; HR 18, 1985; HR 10, 1st Ex. Sess., 1986; HR 2, 1998;
HR 25, 2001; HR 73, 2003; HR 36, 2007, eff. June 22, 2007; HR 42, 2010, eff. April 26,
2010, until Jan. 9, 2012; HR 37, 2011, eff. June 8, 2011; HR 59, 2012; HR 6, 2013, eff. May
30, 2013; HR 31, 2013, eff. June 6, 2013 and Jan. 11, 2016.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=113341</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>