<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-323"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-323"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 323"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-323/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-323/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-323/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-323/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-323">
        <num>CCRP 323</num>
        <heading>323.  Secured personal surety</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-323__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A secured personal surety is a personal surety who satisfies all the requirements
of Article 311</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-323__subsec_A__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and specifically mortgages immovable property located in the state of
Louisiana.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-323__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Bail without surety may be secured by a mortgage on the immovable property of
the defendant pursuant to this Article or unsecured. A secured personal surety may establish
a mortgage over immovable property in favor of the state of Louisiana or the proper political
subdivision to secure a bail undertaking. The security shall apply only to and be limited to
that immovable property specifically described in the mortgage.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-323__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The mortgage is established upon the recordation of a written mortgage, in
authentic form satisfactory to the officer authorized to receive the bail, in the mortgage
records of the parish where the immovable is located that:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-323__subsec_C__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Contains the name and signature of the person making the mortgage.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-323__subsec_C__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Describes the immovable and declares that a mortgage is given over it as security
for the performance of the bail obligation.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-323__subsec_C__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Certifies that the person making the mortgage owns the immovable and states its
value, in excess of the amount of all encumbrances against it.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-323__subsec_C__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Attaches to it a copy of the order fixing bail.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-323__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The person providing the security shall deliver a certified copy of the recorded
statement establishing the mortgage and a mortgage certificate to the officer authorized to
receive the bail.  The officer may require additional evidence of ownership and value of the
mortgaged property including a copy of the current tax assessment.
E.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-323__subsec_D__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The recorder shall cancel the mortgage from his records upon the order of the
court.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-323__subsec_D__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In all other cases, the effect of its recordation shall cease ten years after its
recordation unless it is reinscribed in the manner otherwise provided by law.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-323__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any materially false or incorrect statements made by a person who intentionally
and knowingly gives a mortgage or security interest pursuant to this Article shall be prima
facie proof of a violation of the provisions of R.S. 14:125, false swearing.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112442</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>