<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1470"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1470"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 1470"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1470/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1470/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1470/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1470/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-1470">
        <num>CHC 1470</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1470__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A minor suffering from substance abuse may be admitted and detained at a public or private general hospital or a substance abuse inpatient facility for observation, diagnosis, and treatment for a period not to exceed twenty-eight days, when a parent has admitted the person or caused him to be admitted pursuant to the provisions of Chapter 8 of this Title.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1470__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>At the time of admission, the parent shall execute or provide a written statement of facts, including personal observations, leading to the conclusion that the minor is suffering from substance abuse and is dangerous to himself or others or is gravely disabled, specifically describing any dangerous acts or threats, and stating that the minor has been encouraged to seek treatment but is unwilling to be evaluated on a voluntary basis.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1470__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>As soon as practicable, but in no event more than eight hours after admission to the hospital or inpatient facility, a physician shall examine the minor and either execute an emergency certificate in accordance with Article 1422 or order the minor discharged.  If an emergency certificate is executed, the physician or the director of the hospital or inpatient facility shall immediately notify the coroner and the coroner or his deputy shall conduct an independent examination in accordance with Article 1423.  If the coroner or his deputy executes a second emergency certificate, the minor patient may be detained for treatment for a period not to exceed twenty-eight days from the date of his admission.  Otherwise, he shall be discharged.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1470__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as inconsistent with the provisions of this Article, all other provisions of this Title applicable to persons admitted by emergency certificate shall be applicable.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=72966</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>