<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-313"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-313"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 313"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-313/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-313/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-313/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-313/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-313">
        <num>CCRP 313</num>
        <heading>313.  Gwen's Law; bail hearings; detention without bail</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-313__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon motion of the prosecuting attorney, the judge or magistrate may order the
temporary detention of a person in custody who is charged with the commission of an
offense, for a period of not more than five days, exclusive of weekends and legal holidays,
pending the conducting of a contradictory bail hearing. Following the contradictory hearing,
upon proof by clear and convincing evidence either that there is a substantial risk that the
defendant might flee or that the defendant poses an imminent danger to any other person or
the community, the judge or magistrate may order the defendant held without bail pending
trial.
C.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-313__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A contradictory bail hearing, as provided for in this Paragraph, shall be held
prior to setting bail for a person in custody who is charged with the commission of a sex
offense and who has been previously convicted of a sex offense.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-313__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The court, after having been given notice of an applicable prior conviction as
described in Subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-313__subsec_B__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Paragraph, shall order a contradictory hearing to be
held within five days of receiving notice of the prior conviction, exclusive of weekends and
legal holidays.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-313__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>At the contradictory hearing the court, in addition to hearing whatever evidence
it finds relevant, shall, on motion of the prosecuting attorney, perform an in camera
examination of the evidence against the accused.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-313__subsec_B__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In addition to the factors listed in Article 316, the court shall take into
consideration the previous criminal record of the defendant; any potential threat or danger
the defendant poses to the victim, the family of the victim, or to any member of the public,
especially children; and the court shall give ample consideration to any statistical evidence
prepared by the United States Department of Justice relative to the likelihood of the
defendant, or any person in general who has been convicted of sexually inappropriate
conduct with a prepubescent child under the age of thirteen, to commit similar offenses
against juvenile victims in the future.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-313__subsec_B__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For purposes of this Paragraph, &quot;sex offense&quot; means any offense as defined as
a sex offense in R.S. 15:541 when the victim is under the age of thirteen at the time of
commission of the offense and less than ten years have elapsed between the date of the
commission of the current offense and the expiration of the maximum sentence of the
previous conviction.
D.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-313__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person charged with the commission of a capital offense shall not be
admitted to bail if the proof is evident and the presumption great that he is guilty of the
capital offense.  When a person charged with the commission of a capital offense makes an
application for admission to bail, the judge shall hold a hearing contradictorily with the state.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-313__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The burden of proof at the contradictory bail hearing:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-313__subsec_B__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Prior to indictment is on the state to show that the proof is evident and the
presumption great that the defendant is guilty of the capital offense.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-313__subsec_B__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>After indictment is on the defendant to show that the proof is not evident or the
presumption is not great that he is guilty of the capital offense.
Amended by</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112431</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>