<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-892"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-892"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 892"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-892/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-892/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-892/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-892/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-892">
        <num>CCRP 892</num>
        <heading>892.  Post-sentence statement by sheriff; accompanying documents</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-892__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The sheriff shall prepare a statement indicating the amount of time a defendant
has spent in custody prior to conviction when the defendant has been convicted of a felony
and is committed to the Department of Public Safety and Corrections, has been convicted of
a misdemeanor and sentenced for a term of one year or more to any penal institution, or has
been ordered committed to any mental institution or mental hospital.  The sheriff shall retain
a copy of the statement and submit the original to the sheriff of the parish to which the
defendant is sentenced.
B.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-892__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>When a sheriff's statement is required pursuant to Paragraph A of this Article,
the clerk of court shall also prepare the following documents:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-892__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A copy of the indictment under which the defendant was convicted.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-892__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A copy of the Uniform Sentencing Commitment Order in the format authorized
by the Louisiana Supreme Court which shall include the name and address of the judge, the
district attorney, and the defense attorney who participated in the sentencing trial.  If the
department needs information relating to the sentence not provided in the Uniform
Sentencing Commitment Order, it may request that information from the court.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-892__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The clerk shall retain a copy of the statement and documents and send the
original to the sheriff of the parish to which the defendant has been sentenced, where they
shall be preserved.  The documents, or copies thereof, shall be made available to the
governor, the pardon board, and the parole committee.
C.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-892__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>All statements and documents required by this Article shall physically
accompany any defendant when said defendant is transferred to a penal institution or a
mental institution or mental hospital.  Said documents and statements shall be tendered to
the officer in charge of the institution at the time that the defendant is presented for
admittance thereto.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-892__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For defendants who have been convicted of a felony and committed to the
Department of Public Safety and Corrections, all statements and documents required by this
Article shall be submitted electronically in accordance with R.S. 15:1228.10.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-892__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Failure to comply with the provisions of this Article shall not affect the validity
of a prosecution, conviction, or sentence.
Amended by</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112878</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>