<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-3-3"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-3-3"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="SRULE 3.3"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-3-3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-3-3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-3-3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-3-3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_SRULE-3-3">
        <num>SRULE 3.3</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_1">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Convene the Senate at the time fixed by Senate Rule 10.1 and shall open each
session by taking the chair and calling the members to order.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_2">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Preside at all sessions of the Senate, but he may designate any member to serve
as presiding officer for a limited time, which shall not extend beyond adjournment each
day.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_3">
          <num>(3)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Cause the Senate to proceed with its business in the order established by the
rules, if a quorum is present, and announce or direct the Secretary to announce the
business before the Senate as the Senate proceeds upon each order of business.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_4">
          <num>(4)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Preserve order and decorum, particularly as provided in these rules.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_5">
          <num>(5)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Confine members to the question under consideration.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_6">
          <num>(6)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Speak on points of order, and he shall have preference over other members in
doing so.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_7">
          <num>(7)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Decide all points of order, subject to appeal to the Senate as provided in Senate
Rule 6.3.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_8">
          <num>(8)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Explain or clarify any rule of procedure upon request.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_9">
          <num>(9)</num>
          <content>
            <p>State, or direct the Secretary to state, each motion as it is made, as provided in
Senate Rule 11.1.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_10">
          <num>(10)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Recognize members who seek the floor for the purpose of speaking in debate
or otherwise, but such recognition shall be in accordance with Senate Rules 6.5 and 6.6.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_11">
          <num>(11)</num>
          <content>
            <p>State and put to a vote all questions requiring a vote or upon which a vote is
ordered and announce the vote as provided in Senate Rules 12.5 and 12.8.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_12">
          <num>(12)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Cast his vote when the Senate is equally divided; otherwise, he may but shall
not be required to vote.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_13">
          <num>(13)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Have general charge and supervision of the Senate Chamber and all physical
facilities, particularly as provided in Chapter 1.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_14">
          <num>(14)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Assemble the members in meetings during the interim between sessions or at
any other time for any purpose he deems necessary or desirable and expend funds of the
Senate to pay the expenses thereof, including per diem and travel expenses.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_15">
          <num>(15)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Appoint or remove the members of each Senate and conference committee,
except as otherwise provided by law, rule, or resolution, and appoint or remove the
chairman and vice chairman of each committee, as provided by Senate Rule 13.2.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_16">
          <num>(16)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Create select committees and appoint or remove the members thereof.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_17">
          <num>(17)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Provide for a schedule of committee meetings, as provided by Senate Rules
13.69 and 13.70.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_18">
          <num>(18)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Refer to standing committees all prefiled instruments or other matters to be
referred to committee, as provided in Senate Rules 13.4 and 13.5.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_19">
          <num>(19)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Sign all documents which require his signature, particularly as provided in
Senate Rule 7.11.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_20">
          <num>(20)</num>
          <content>
            <p>At his discretion, examine and correct the Journal.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_21">
          <num>(21)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Have general charge and supervision over the Secretary and his assistants, the
Sergeant at Arms and his assistants, and all employees of the Senate.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_22">
          <num>(22)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Employ, fix the compensation, and have authority to discharge all Senate
employees.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_23">
          <num>(23)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Approve all expenditures of the Senate and its members and enter into
contracts for the Senate and its members.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_24">
          <num>(24)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Preside over joint sessions of the legislature, as provided in Joint Rule No. 1.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_25">
          <num>(25)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Do and perform such other duties as are required by the constitution and laws,
the legislature, or the Senate, and such other duties as may properly appertain to the office
of the President.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_26">
          <num>(26)</num>
          <content>
            <p>At his discretion, name any senator to perform any duties of the chair for a
time he shall specify.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_27">
          <num>(27)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Delegate any of his duties or functions to the President Pro Tempore.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_28">
          <num>(28)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Appoint a parliamentarian.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_29">
          <num>(29)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Have control and custody of all vehicles owned by or assigned to the Senate.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_30">
          <num>(30)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Be responsible for the assignment and use of vehicles owned by or assigned to
the Senate and may assign such vehicles for use by the staff for Senate business.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_31">
          <num>(31)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Submit receipts or documentation supported by other evidence for all
expenses for which reimbursement is sought pursuant to R.S. 24:503.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_32">
          <num>(32)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Cause to be distributed reports covering interim activity from standing, joint,
or special legislative or Senate committees or subcommittees to all members of the
Senate, particularly Senators representing geographic areas included in the study.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-3-3__subsec_33">
          <num>(33)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Suspend any or all of the duties of the Secretary of the Senate prescribed in
Senate Rule 3.7 when the Secretary has been censured and placed on probation by the
Senate by adoption of a resolution. The length of time of any probation shall be specified
in a resolution in which the Secretary is censured and placed on probation. Upon the
conclusion of such a period of probation, the authority of the President under this
Paragraph shall cease. In addition to the suspension of duties, the President may reduce
the compensation of the Secretary commensurate with the suspension of the Secretary's
duties and may designate an acting secretary of the Senate to perform such duties during
the time of the Secretary's suspension.
SR 3 of 1996 1 st ES; SR 14 of 1996 1 st ES; SR 8 of 2004 1 st EX</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=180507</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>