<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1160"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1160"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 1160"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1160/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1160/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1160/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1160/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-1160">
        <num>CHC 1160</num>
        <heading>1160.  Additional regulations; Administrative Procedure Act; reporting</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1160__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The department, in accordance with the Administrative Procedure Act, shall
promulgate all rules and regulations necessary to carry out the provisions of this Chapter,
including but not limited to the following:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1160__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notice to the public of the existence of designated emergency care facilities and
the use of safe havens through the following actions:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-1160__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The establishment of a toll-free telephone number to direct individuals to
designated emergency care facilities.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-1160__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The provision of safe haven publicity and informational materials on the
department's website for review and download by the public.
(c)</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-1160__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_i">
              <num>(i)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Promulgation of the image that shall constitute the official Safe Haven symbol
in accordance with Article 1161.
(ii)  Transmittal of an electronic version of the Safe Haven symbol to any designated
emergency care facility upon request.
(iii)  Production and distribution to designated emergency care facilities of signage
bearing the Safe Haven symbol, subject to availability of funding for this purpose.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-1160__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Written information, training materials, and an instructional video to be made
available for download on the department's website, for the instruction of representatives of
emergency medical care facilities who are designated to receive relinquished children and
to interview relinquishing parents.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-1160__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The department shall review all information, materials, video, and any other
media produced in accordance with this Paragraph at least annually; and, to the extent that
funding is available for such purposes, shall update, revise, and reissue these resources as the
secretary of the department deems necessary.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1160__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Procedures and forms informing a relinquishing parent about his right to file a
claim and be heard in accordance with Articles 1156 and 1157 and his right to use the
services of the voluntary registry in accordance with Chapter 15 of Title XII.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1160__subsec_A__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Procedures for use by a physician in conducting the medical evaluation of the
child in accordance with Article 1153.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1160__subsec_A__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The department shall utilize existing funds to effectuate the provisions of
Subparagraphs (A)</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1160__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1160__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Article.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1160__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition to any other duties as may be required by this Article, the department
shall develop and implement annually each of the following plans:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1160__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An annual communication and public information action plan to increase public
awareness of the Safe Haven Law.  This plan shall include, without limitation, all of the
following actions:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-1160__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Issuing media releases for distribution to print, radio, and television media.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-1160__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Disseminating information through social media.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-1160__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Conducting outreach to the public through collaborations with community-based
organizations, child protection stakeholder groups, offices of state government, and any other
entities the secretary of the department deems appropriate.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-1160__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Undertaking any other communication or publicity activity deemed necessary by
the secretary of the department and for which sufficient funding is available.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-1160__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An action plan providing for dissemination of information and training
resources relating to the Safe Haven Law to designated emergency care facilities.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-1160__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>To the extent the secretary of the department deems appropriate, and contingent
upon availability of funding for this purpose, the department may also disseminate the
information and resources provided for in Subsubparagraph</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-1160__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this Subparagraph to any
of the following:</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-1160__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_i">
              <num>(i)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Schools of medicine.
(ii)  Schools of nursing.
(iii)  Law enforcement training schools.
(iv)  Firefighter training programs.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-1160__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_v">
              <num>(v)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Emergency medical service provider training programs.
(vi)  Any other institutions that train professionals who typically work in a designated
emergency care facility.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1160__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>On or before January first annually, the department shall submit to the House
Committee on Health and Welfare and the Senate Committee on Health and Welfare a report
addressing efforts undertaken in the period covered by the report to raise public awareness
of the Safe Haven Law.  The report shall include but not be limited to a recapitulation of
content of the communication and public information action plan and action plan for
dissemination of safe haven information and training resources required by this Article.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=180659</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>