<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-608"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-608"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 608"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-608/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-608/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-608/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-608/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-608">
        <num>CHC 608</num>
        <heading>608.  Parents' right to counsel; payment</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-608__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The parents of a child who is the subject of a child in need of care proceeding
shall be entitled to qualified, independent counsel after the court issues any order in
accordance with Article 619(C) or 620 or at the filing of a petition and at all stages of the
proceedings thereafter.  If the court does not issue an order in accordance with Article 619(C)
or 620, the right to counsel shall attach upon the filing of a petition.  At all proceedings
governed by Chapter 6 of this Title, the parents shall be presumed to be indigent.  Thereafter,
indigence shall be determined in accordance with Article 320.  The right to counsel may be
waived by a parent if the court determines that the parent choosing to waive the right to
representation has been instructed by the court about the rights and the possible
consequences of waiver.  Before accepting a waiver of counsel, the court shall ensure each
of the following:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-608__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The parent has been informed by the court that the Department of Children and
Family Services cannot provide legal advice to the parent or represent the parent's interest.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-608__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The parent has been informed by the court that the child's attorney cannot provide
legal advice to the parent and does not represent the parent's interest.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-608__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The parent has been informed by the court that a proceeding brought in
accordance with this Title may ultimately result in a termination of parental rights and a
complete and permanent separation of the parent from the child.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-608__subsec_A__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The parent has been informed by the court that if the parent is unable to afford
an attorney, one will be provided by the Indigent Parents' Representation Program.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-608__subsec_A__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>That the parent is eighteen years of age or older.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-608__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a parent of a child is financially unable to afford counsel or is presumed
indigent in accordance with Paragraph A of this Article, the district public defender office
shall provide for representation, unless the Louisiana Public Defender Board has contracted
to provide for representation in accordance with R.S. 15:185.3(B)</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-608__subsec_B__subsec_12">
            <num>(12)</num>
            <content>
              <p>or any other provision
of law.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-608__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The unavailability of counsel to represent the parent shall be good cause for a
continuance of the continued custody hearing for up to three days, and the hearing shall not
proceed until a qualified, independent attorney is provided to the parent.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=73200</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>