<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-610"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-610"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 610"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-610/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-610/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-610/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-610/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-610">
        <num>CHC 610</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-610__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A reporter shall immediately report suspected child abuse or neglect or that child
abuse or neglect was a contributing factor in a child's death in the following ways:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To the Department of Children and Family Services if the reporter has reason to
believe that the perpetrator is  any of the following:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A parent or caretaker as defined in Article 603.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A person who maintains an interpersonal dating or engagement relationship with
the parent or caretaker.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A person living in the same residence  as the parent or caretaker.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A person living in the same residence as the child, or any residence of the child,
if the child has more than one residence.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An employee or an operator of an early learning center as defined in R.S.
17:407.33.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An operator or employee of a registered family child day care home.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Another child residing in the same residence for cases of suspected sexual abuse.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_h">
              <num>(h)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Indeterminable by the mandatory reporter, but the reporter suspects that the abuse
occurred at the child's residence.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To a local or state law enforcement agency if the reporter has reason to believe
that the perpetrator is any of the following:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_A__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A person other than a person provided for in Subparagraph</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Paragraph.</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A teacher, instructor, administrator, staff person, school bus driver, teacher aide,
paraprofessional, food service worker, or employee of any public or private elementary,
secondary, vocational-technical training, special, or postsecondary school, city, parish, or
other local public school board, if the abuse or neglect is perpetrated on a student.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Another child who does not reside in the same residence for cases of suspected
sexual abuse.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Dual reporting to both the department and the local or state law enforcement
agency is permitted. However, the agency who receives a report pursuant to Subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Paragraph shall be the agency responsible for accepting and acting on the
report and shall ensure referral to other agencies as necessary.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_A__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Reports to the department shall be made as follows:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_A__subsec_4__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A mandatory reporter shall make a report of suspected abuse or neglect requiring
immediate assistance via the designated state child protection reporting hotline telephone
number. A report of suspected abuse or neglect which is of a nonemergency nature may be
reported via the Louisiana Department of Children and Family Services Mandated Reporter
Portal online. Reports may also be made in person at any child welfare office.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_A__subsec_4__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If a report involves alleged sex trafficking, all mandatory reporters shall report via
the hotline telephone number to the department regardless of whether there is alleged
parental or caretaker culpability.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_A__subsec_4__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A permitted reporter shall make a report through the designated state child
protection reporting hotline telephone number or in person at any child welfare office.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_A__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a school resource officer suspects child abuse or neglect of a student or if a 
mandatory reporter reports suspected child abuse or neglect to a school resource officer, the
school resource officer shall immediately notify the officer's employing law enforcement
agency or the Department of Children and Family Services in accordance with the provisions
of this Article. The school resource officer's employer shall assign investigation of the matter
to the most appropriate law enforcement officer, who may be the school resource officer.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_A__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a mandatory reporter is prohibited from immediately making the report required
by this Chapter to the department or local or state law enforcement because of an employer's
policies or employee manual, the mandatory reporter shall file a complaint with local or state
law enforcement. Local or state law enforcement shall investigate the complaint, and an
employer violating this Chapter shall be subject to the penalties provided for in R.S. 14:131.1
and 403. An employer shall not discriminate or retaliate against an employee who is a
mandatory reporter for complying with this Article. If an employer is found discriminating
or retaliating against an employee for complying with this Article, the employer shall be
subject to double the fines provided for in R.S. 14:131.1 and 403.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_A__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In an investigation of a report of abuse or neglect allegedly committed by a parent
or caretaker, the department shall determine whether the person is an active duty member of
the United States Armed Forces or the spouse of a member on active duty. If the department
determines that the person is an active duty member of the United States Armed Forces or
the spouse of a member on active duty, the department shall notify the United States
Department of Defense Family Advocacy Program at the closest active duty military
installation of the investigation.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-610__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The report shall contain the following information, if known:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The name, address, age, sex, and race of the child.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The nature, extent, and cause of the child's injuries or endangered condition,
including any previous known or suspected abuse to this child or the child's siblings.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The name and address of the child's parent</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_B__subsec_3__subsec_s">
              <num>(s)</num>
              <content>
                <p>or other caretaker.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_B__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The names and ages of all other members of the child's household.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_B__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The name and address of the reporter.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_B__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An account of how this child came to the reporter's attention.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_B__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any explanation of the cause of the child's injury or condition offered by the
child, the caretaker, or any other person.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_B__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The number of times the reporter has filed a report on the child or the child's
siblings.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_B__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any other information which the reporter believes might be important or relevant.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-610__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The report shall also name the person or persons who are thought to have caused
or contributed to the child's condition, if known, and the report shall contain the name of
such person if he is named by the child.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-610__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the initial report was in oral form by a mandatory reporter, it shall be followed
by a written report made within five days via the online Mandated Reporter Portal of the
department or by mail to the centralized intake unit of the department at the address provided
on the website of the department; or, if necessary, to the local law enforcement agency.  The
reporter may use a form for the written report, which shall be developed, approved, and made
available by the Department of Children and Family Services.  The form is optional and may
be available electronically on the department's website.
E.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_D__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>All reports made to any local or state law enforcement agency involving abuse
or neglect in which  an individual provided for in Subparagraph (A)</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_D__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Article is
believed responsible shall be  reported to the department within twenty-four hours in
accordance with Paragraph A of this Article.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_D__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>All reports made to the department involving abuse or neglect  in which someone
other than an individual provided for in Subparagraph (A)</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_D__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Article is believed to be
responsible shall be reported to the appropriate law enforcement agency within twenty-four
hours by telephone. The department also shall report all cases of child death which involve
a suspicion of abuse or neglect as a contributing factor in the child's death to the local and
state law enforcement agencies, the office of the district attorney, and the coroner.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_D__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Reports involving a felony-grade crime against a child shall be promptly
communicated to the appropriate law enforcement authorities as part of the interagency
protocols for multidisciplinary investigations of child abuse and neglect in each judicial
district as provided in Articles 509 and 510.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_D__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The department shall communicate as soon as possible all reports involving
alleged child victims of sex trafficking to the Louisiana State Police for referral to the
appropriate local law enforcement agency for investigation or other action as appropriate.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-610__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any commercial film or photographic print processor who has knowledge of or
observes, within the scope of this professional capacity or employment, any film,
photograph, video tape, negative, or slide depicting a child who he knows or should know
is under the age of seventeen years, which constitutes child pornography or child sexual
abuse materials as defined in Article 603, shall report immediately to the local law
enforcement agency having jurisdiction over the case.  The reporter shall provide a copy of
the film, photograph, videotape, negative, or slide to the agency receiving the report.
G.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_F__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a physician has cause to believe that a newborn was exposed in utero to an
unlawfully used controlled dangerous substance, as defined by R.S. 40:961 et seq., the
physician shall order a toxicology test upon the newborn, without the consent of the
newborn's parents or guardian, to determine whether there is evidence of prenatal neglect. 
If the test results are positive, the physician shall issue a report, as soon as possible, in
accordance with this Article.  If the test results are negative, all identifying information shall
be obliterated if the record is retained, unless the parent approves the inclusion of identifying
information.  Positive test results shall not be admissible in a criminal prosecution.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_F__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If there are symptoms of withdrawal in the newborn or other observable and
harmful effects in his physical appearance or functioning that a physician has cause to believe
are due to the chronic or severe use of alcohol by the mother during pregnancy or are the
effects of fetal alcohol spectrum disorder, the physician shall issue a report in accordance
with this Article.
H.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_F__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>All instances of alleged child abuse that occur in a school setting shall be
immediately reported to the child's parent or legal guardian and to local or state law
enforcement, regardless of the alleged perpetrator.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_F__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If more than one child is involved in the allegations, the school shall immediately
report to the parent or legal guardian of all involved children.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_F__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Law enforcement shall begin an investigation of the allegations within forty-eight
hours of receiving the report.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_F__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If more than one child is involved in the allegations, law enforcement shall
interview the parent or legal guardian of all children involved.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_F__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any sexual abuse cases in which the alleged perpetrator is a child shall be referred
to the Department of Children and Family Services. The department shall assess the family
of the child victim and the alleged child perpetrator to ensure child safety and well-being in
accordance with Children's Code Article 612(A)(3).</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_F__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For purposes of this Article, the following definitions shall apply:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_F__subsec_6__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;School setting&quot; means in a school building, on school grounds, in school
vehicles, or at any activities sponsored by a school.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_F__subsec_6__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;Sexual abuse&quot; means the perpetration or attempted perpetration of R.S. 14:41,
42, 42.1, 43, 43.1, 43.2, 43.3, 43.4, 80, 81, 81.1, 81.2, 86, 89, or 89.1.
I.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_F__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions of this Paragraph shall be known and may be cited as The Alfred</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-610__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Williams Child Protection Act.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_C__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Beginning May 1, 2017, and annually thereafter, the department shall provide to
the legislature the following child-specific information regarding reports of child abuse or
neglect reported to the department pursuant to the provisions of this Article:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_C__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The actual or estimated age, the sex, and the race of each child at the time the
latest report was received.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_C__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The parish location of primary case name of the latest report accepted for
investigation received.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_C__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The categories, levels, and final findings assigned to each allegation contained in
reports received for each child.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_C__subsec_2__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The number of cases accepted for investigation in which the child was an alleged 
victim during the report year.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_C__subsec_2__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The number of cases accepted for investigation in which the child was a 
substantiated victim during the report year.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_C__subsec_2__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The number of reports accepted for investigation prior to report year in which the
child was an alleged or  substantiated victim.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_C__subsec_2__subsec_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The number of other alleged victims in reports accepted for investigation in each
child's cases prior to report year.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_C__subsec_2__subsec_h">
              <num>(h)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The number of reports accepted for investigation prior to the report year in which
the child was a  substantiated victim.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_C__subsec_2__subsec_i">
              <num>(i)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The number of other  substantiated victims in reports accepted for investigation
in each child's cases prior to report year.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_C__subsec_2__subsec_j">
              <num>(j)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The number of distinct reporter names for all investigations in which the child is
an alleged or  substantiated victim.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_C__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For purposes of this Paragraph, the following words shall have the following
meanings:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_C__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;Alleged victim&quot; includes a child who is the subject of an investigation and for
whom there is an allegation of abuse or neglect.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_C__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;Substantiated victim&quot;  includes an alleged victim for whom one or more
allegations of abuse or neglect have been  substantiated pursuant to Article 615.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_C__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The information provided in the annual report required by Subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_C__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of
this Paragraph shall not include the name, street address, or other identifying information of
any child, parent, sibling, or reporter.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_C__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the department fails to submit timely the report required by Subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-610__subsec_C__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Paragraph, then the legislature or either house thereof, through its authorized
representative, may petition the Nineteenth Judicial District Court for writs of mandamus to
compel the submission of the report.  Any failure to obey a writ of mandamus issued by the
court may be punishable by the court as contempt thereof.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=73202</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>