<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-HRULE-7-19"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-HRULE-7-19"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="HRULE 7.19"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-HRULE-7-19/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-HRULE-7-19/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-HRULE-7-19/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-HRULE-7-19/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_HRULE-7-19">
        <num>HRULE 7.19</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="HRULE-7-19__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>For purposes of this Rule, the following phrases shall have the following 
meanings:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="HRULE-7-19__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>&quot;Federal disaster funds&quot; means money received by the state from the federal
government in response to and for recovery from a federally declared disaster or emergency.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="HRULE-7-19__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>&quot;Money available for appropriation&quot; means the amount of money to be received
for a fiscal year by the state general fund and dedicated funds, exclusive of federal funds.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="HRULE-7-19__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>&quot;One-time money&quot; means any one of the following:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="HRULE-7-19__subsec_B__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Money available for appropriation from any special treasury fund  excluding any
monies forecast to be dedicated into such a fund by the Revenue Estimating Conference in
the official forecast for that fiscal year.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="HRULE-7-19__subsec_B__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Money available for appropriation from the state general fund from one time
transactions, but not recognized as nonrecurring revenue by the Revenue Estimating
Conference, including but not limited to court settlements, the sale of state facilities, and the
privatization of state operations.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="HRULE-7-19__subsec_B__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>&quot;Ordinary recurring expenses&quot; means all expenses of a continuing or recurring
character, that in the normal course of administration, would be expected to be necessary in
approximately the same amounts each year.
C.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="HRULE-7-19__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A motion the effect of which is to finally pass an appropriation bill that
appropriates one-time money for ordinary recurring expenses shall be in order without a
separate prior motion authorizing the use of such money if:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="HRULE-7-19__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The total recommended general operating appropriations contained in the
executive budget for the fiscal year for which the appropriation is recommended are less than
or equal to the total general operating appropriations for the existing operating budget of the
current fiscal year included in the executive budget; and</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="HRULE-7-19__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Appropriations from one-time money for ordinary recurring expenses do not
exceed the projected growth of the state general fund from the fiscal year for which the
appropriation is proposed and the subsequent fiscal year according to the most recent official
forecast.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="HRULE-7-19__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A motion the effect of which is to finally pass an appropriation bill that
appropriates federal disaster funds for ordinary recurring expenses shall be in order without
a separate prior motion authorizing the use of such money if:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="HRULE-7-19__subsec_B__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Ordinary recurring expenses are not increased above amounts budgeted
immediately prior to the federal declaration of the disaster or emergency.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="HRULE-7-19__subsec_B__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The federal disaster funds are payable to the state on a reimbursement basis.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="HRULE-7-19__subsec_B__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The Revenue Estimating Conference adopts a revised forecast that indicates that
ordinary recurring revenues are sufficient to fully fund any increase in ordinary recurring
expenses for the current fiscal year and at least the next two fiscal years.
D.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="HRULE-7-19__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Prior to consideration on third reading and final passage of any appropriation
bill, the Legislative Fiscal Officer shall submit a report to the House of Representatives
which shall indicate whether the appropriation bill appropriates one-time money or federal
disaster funds for ordinary recurring expenses. No appropriation bill shall be considered
unless the report of the Legislative Fiscal Officer has been placed on the desk of each
member.
(2)</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="HRULE-7-19__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Prior to the adoption of any  Committee of the Whole House Amendment, any
floor amendment, and any conference committee report  to an appropriation bill, the
presiding officer, after giving due consideration to the advice of legislative staff, shall make
a determination if the amendment or any amendment recommended by the conference
committee, as the case may be, appropriates one-time money or federal disaster funds for
ordinary recurring expenses.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="HRULE-7-19__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Prior to concurrence in an amendment to an appropriation bill, the presiding
officer, after giving due consideration to the advice of legislative staff, shall make a
determination if the amendment appropriates one-time money or federal disaster funds for
ordinary recurring expenses.
HR 27, 2011, eff. May 23, 2011; HR 17, 2022, eff. May 31, 2022.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=762046</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>