<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-311"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-311"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 311"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-311/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-311/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-311/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-311/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-311">
        <num>CCRP 311</num>
        <heading>BAIL</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-311__subsec_1">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Bail is the security given by a person to assure a defendant's appearance before
the proper court whenever required.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-311__subsec_2">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An appearance is a personal appearance before the court or the court's designee,
where the charges are pending.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-311__subsec_3">
          <num>(3)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A surrender is the detention of the defendant at the request of the surety by the
officer originally charged with his detention on the original commitment.  When the surety
has requested the surrender of the defendant, the officer shall acknowledge the surrender by
a certificate of surrender signed by him and delivered to the surety.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-311__subsec_4">
          <num>(4)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A constructive surrender is the detention of the defendant in another parish of the
state of Louisiana or a foreign jurisdiction under the following circumstances:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-311__subsec_4__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A warrant for arrest has been issued for the defendant in the jurisdiction in which
the bail obligation is in place.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-311__subsec_4__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The surety has provided proof of the defendant's current incarceration to the court
in which the bail obligation is in place, to the prosecuting attorney, and to the officer
originally charged with the defendant's detention.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-311__subsec_4__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The surety agrees to pay reasonable or actual costs of returning the defendant to
the jurisdiction where the warrant for arrest was issued.  If the surety fails to pay a set amount
of the reasonable or actual costs, the recovery shall be through a summary proceeding against
both the principal and the surety, as provided in Code of Civil Procedure Article 2592</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-311__subsec_5">
          <num>(5)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A surety's motion and affidavit for issuance of warrant may be filed when the
defendant is found incarcerated in another parish of the state of Louisiana or a foreign
jurisdiction and a warrant has not been issued by the court or in which the bail obligation is
in place.  In such instances, the surety may file a motion with the court requesting a warrant
be issued when the following conditions have been met:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-311__subsec_5__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>There has been a breach of the bail undertaking.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-311__subsec_5__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The surety provides proof of the defendant's current incarceration outside of the
state of Louisiana. The defendant's incarceration may be used as evidence of a breach of the
bail undertaking.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-311__subsec_5__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The defendant did not have written permission from the court to leave the state
of Louisiana.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-311__subsec_5__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon presentation of evidence of the breach of the bail undertaking, the court
may issue a warrant for the defendant's violation of the conditions of the bail undertaking.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-311__subsec_5__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The surety may then file the constructive surrender in accordance with this
Article and Article 331.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-311__subsec_6">
          <num>(6)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A personal surety is a natural person domiciled in the state of Louisiana who
owns property in this state that is subject to seizure and is of sufficient value to satisfy,
considering all his property, the amount specified in the bail undertaking.  The value of the
property shall exclude the amount exempt from execution, and shall be over and above all
other liabilities including the amount of any other bail undertaking on which he may be
principal or surety.  If there is more than one personal surety, then the requirements shall
apply to the aggregate value of their property.  A personal surety shall not charge a fee or
receive any compensation for posting a bail undertaking.  A bail undertaking of a personal
surety may be unsecured or secured.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-311__subsec_7">
          <num>(7)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Bail enforcement is the apprehension or surrender by a natural person of a
principal who is released on bail or who has failed to appear at any stage of the proceedings
to answer the charge before the court in which the principal may be prosecuted.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-311__subsec_8">
          <num>(8)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A bail enforcement agent is a licensed bail agent who engages in the
apprehension or surrender by a natural person of a principal who is released on bail or who
has failed to appear at any stage of the proceedings to answer the charge before the court in
which the principal  may be prosecuted.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-311__subsec_9">
          <num>(9)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The originating jurisdiction is the jurisdiction where the warrant for the arrest
was issued and where the charges are pending.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-311__subsec_10">
          <num>(10)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The executing jurisdiction is the jurisdiction where the defendant is arrested and
incarcerated on a warrant for arrest.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-311__subsec_11">
          <num>(11)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Electronic bond is a commercial bail bond contract executed digitally as
security given by a surety to assure a defendant's appearance before the proper court
whenever required.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112429</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>