<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-625"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-625"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 625"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-625/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-625/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-625/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-625/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-625">
        <num>CHC 625</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-625__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the child is continued in the custody of the state, the court shall advise the
parents of:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-625__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The child's need to have a safe and stable relationship with caretakers, either his
parents or, if necessary, others who are willing and able to assume parental responsibility and
provide a permanent home, and to have these caretaker decisions made as quickly as
possible.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-625__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Their responsibility to cooperate in preparing a case plan and otherwise in
meeting the needs of their child, and if their child cannot return home safely, to assist the
child's adjustment to other caretakers, and their obligation to contribute to the cost of care
and treatment of their child as provided in Article 685.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-625__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Their responsibility to notify the department and their counsel in writing of their
current whereabouts, including their address, cellular number, telephone number, and any
other contact information, and that if they fail to do so, the law authorizes hearings to be held
in their absence.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-625__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon receipt of information regarding a parent's change of address, the
department and the parent's counsel shall promptly inform the court of the new address.
D.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-625__subsec_C__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The court shall direct all persons before the court to identify the name, address,
and whereabouts of each parent and any suitable relative or other suitable individual willing
and able to offer a stable and safe home for the child.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-625__subsec_C__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The court shall advise all persons before the court of their responsibility in
achieving timely permanency for the child, and further shall direct all such individuals to
identify the name, address, and whereabouts of all grandparents, all parents of a sibling
where such parent has legal custody of such sibling, and all other adult relatives of the child.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-625__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If at the time of the hearing a petition has been filed, the court may also call upon
the parent to answer its allegations in accordance with Chapter 9 of this Title.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=73218</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>