<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-716"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-716"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 716"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-716/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-716/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-716/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-716/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-716">
        <num>CCRP 716</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-716__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon written motion of the defendant, the court shall order the district attorney to disclose to the defendant, and to permit or authorize the defendant to inspect and copy, photograph or otherwise reproduce any relevant written or recorded confession or statement of any nature, including recorded testimony before a grand jury, or copy thereof, of the defendant in the possession, custody, control, or knowledge of the district attorney.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-716__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as provided by Paragraph C of this Article, upon written motion of the defendant, the court shall order the district attorney to inform the defendant of the existence, but not the contents, of any oral confession or statement of any nature made by the defendant or any codefendant which the district attorney intends to offer in its case in chief at the trial, with the information as to when, where, and to whom such oral confession or statement was made.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-716__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon written motion of the defendant, the court shall order the district attorney to inform the defendant of the substance of any oral statement made by the defendant or any codefendant which the state intends to offer in its case in chief at the trial, whether before or after arrest, in response to interrogation by any person then known to the defendant or the codefendant to be a law enforcement officer.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-716__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon written motion of the defendant, the court shall order the district attorney to disclose to the defendant, and to permit or authorize the defendant to inspect and copy any written or recorded statements of any witness the state intends to call in its case in chief at the trial. For purposes of this Article:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-716__subsec_D__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>&quot;written or recorded statement of a witness&quot; shall mean any audio or audio-video recording of an oral statement or interview of a witness, and any statement a witness writes or signs;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-716__subsec_D__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>for the purposes of this Article, &quot;trial&quot; shall mean the phase of the case at which the state attempts to meet its burden as to guilt, and specifically does not extend to pretrial matters or hearings, or to the penalty phase in capital prosecutions. The state need not provide the defendant any written or recorded statement of its witnesses until immediately prior to the opening statement at trial.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-716__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nothing in this Chapter shall be construed to require that testimony before a grand jury be recorded.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-716__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nothing contained in this Chapter shall obligate the state to provide to any defendant a witness list for any trial or pretrial matter.
Added by</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112723</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>