<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1405-1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1405-1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 1405.1"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1405-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1405-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1405-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1405-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-1405-1">
        <num>CHC 1405.1</num>
        <heading>1405.1.  Child Advocacy Program; establishment within Mental Health Advocacy Service; duties</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1405-1__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The Child Advocacy Program, referred to hereafter in this Article as the &quot;program&quot;, is hereby established within the Mental Health Advocacy Service authorized pursuant to R.S. 28:64.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1405-1__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The program shall provide qualified legal counsel to children in child abuse and neglect cases, subject to availability as determined by the director of the program, in those jurisdictions designated by the Louisiana Supreme Court and pursuant to Children's Code Article 560.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1405-1__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The program shall be governed by the board of trustees established pursuant to R.S. 28:64(A)(3).</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1405-1__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The duties of the board of trustees shall include those enumerated in R.S. 28:64(C) and all of the following specific duties:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1405-1__subsec_D__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To establish general policy guidelines for the operation of the program to provide legal counsel and representation for children in child abuse and neglect cases of this state in order to ensure that their legal rights are protected; however, the board shall not have supervisory power over the conduct of particular cases.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1405-1__subsec_D__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To review and evaluate the operations of the program and emphasize special training for attorneys hired by the service.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1405-1__subsec_D__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To review and approve an annual budget for the program.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1405-1__subsec_D__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To review and approve an annual report on the operation of the program and submit such report to the legislature, the governor, and the chief justice of the Louisiana Supreme Court.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1405-1__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The duties of the director of the program shall include those enumerated in R.S. 28:64(E) and all of the following specific duties:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1405-1__subsec_E__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To organize and administer a program to provide legal counsel and representation for children in child abuse and neglect cases subject to the approval of the board of trustees and in accordance with a plan for service delivery approved by the Louisiana Supreme Court.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1405-1__subsec_E__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To identify the needs of children in child abuse and neglect cases for legal counsel and representation within the state and the resources necessary to meet those needs, subject to the approval of the board of trustees.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1405-1__subsec_E__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To institute or cause to be instituted such legal proceedings as may be necessary to enforce and give effect to any of the duties or powers of the program.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1405-1__subsec_E__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To hire and train attorneys and other professional and nonprofessional staff that may be necessary to carry out the functions of the program.  All attorneys representing children through this program shall be licensed to practice law in Louisiana and be qualified in accordance with Louisiana Supreme Court Part J, Special Rules for Cases Involving the Protection of Children.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1405-1__subsec_E__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To establish official rules and regulations for the conduct of work of the program, subject to the approval of the board of trustees.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1405-1__subsec_E__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To take such actions as he deems necessary and appropriate to secure private and state, federal, or other public funds to help support the program, subject to the approval of the board of trustees.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1405-1__subsec_E__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To have the ability to contract with organizations or individuals for the provision of legal services for children in child abuse and neglect cases, subject to the approval of the board of trustees and in accordance with a plan for service delivery approved by the Louisiana Supreme Court.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=921041</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>