<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-3604"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-3604"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCP 3604"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-3604/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-3604/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-3604/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-3604/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCP-3604">
        <num>CCP 3604</num>
        <heading>3604.  Form, contents, and duration of restraining order</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCP-3604__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A temporary restraining order shall be endorsed with the date and hour of
issuance; shall be filed in the clerk's office and entered of record; shall state why the order
was granted without notice and hearing; and shall expire by its terms within such time after
entry, not to exceed ten days, as the court prescribes.  A restraining order, for good cause
shown, and at any time before its expiration, may be extended by the court for one or more
periods not exceeding ten days each.  The party against whom the order is directed may
consent that it be extended for a longer period.  The reasons for each extension shall be
entered of record.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-3604__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nevertheless, in a suit for divorce, a temporary restraining order issued in
conjunction with a rule to show cause for a preliminary injunction shall remain in force until
a hearing is held on the rule for the preliminary injunction prohibiting a spouse from:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-3604__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Disposing of or encumbering community property;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-3604__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Harming the other spouse or a child; or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-3604__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Removing a child from the jurisdiction of the court.
C.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-3604__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A temporary restraining order issued in conjunction with a rule to show cause
for a protective order filed in an action pursuant to the Protection from Family Violence Act,
R.S. 46:2121 et seq., and pursuant to the Protection From Dating Violence Act, R.S.
46:2151, shall remain in force until a hearing is held on the rule for the protective order or
for thirty days, whichever occurs first.  If the initial rule to show cause is heard by a hearing
officer, the temporary restraining order shall remain in force for fifteen days after the hearing
or until the judge signs the protective order, whichever occurs last.  At any time before the
expiration of a temporary restraining order issued pursuant to this Paragraph, it may be
extended by the court for a period not exceeding thirty days.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-3604__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In the event that the hearing on the rule for the protective order is continued by
the court because of a declared state of emergency made in accordance with R.S. 29:724, any
temporary restraining order issued in the matter shall remain in force for five days after the
date of conclusion of the state of emergency.  When a temporary restraining order remains
in force under this Paragraph, the court shall reassign the rule for a protective order for
hearing at the earliest possible time, but no later than five days after the date of conclusion
of the state of emergency.  The reassignment of the rule shall take precedence over all
matters except older matters of the same character.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-3604__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>To be effective against a federally insured financial institution, a temporary
restraining order or preliminary injunction issued in accordance with Subparagraph (B)</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-3604__subsec_D__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Article shall be served in accordance with the provisions of R.S. 6:285(C).  A
temporary restraining order or preliminary injunction granted pursuant to the provisions of
this Article shall be effective only against accounts, safe deposit boxes, or other assets listed
or held in the name of the following:</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-3604__subsec_D__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>One or both of the spouses named in the injunction.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-3604__subsec_D__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Another party or business entity specifically named in the injunction.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-3604__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A federally insured financial institution shall not be liable for loss or damages
resulting from its actions to comply with a temporary restraining order or preliminary
injunction provided that the requirements of this Article have been met.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=111806</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>