<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-927-1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-927-1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 927.1"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-927-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-927-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-927-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-927-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-927-1">
        <num>CCRP 927.1</num>
        <heading>927.1.  Abandonment of application</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-927-1__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>After filing an application for post conviction relief, the petitioner is responsible
for seeking a ruling on his application and pursuing his claims.  Failure to actively seek a
ruling on an application for post conviction relief after it has been filed shall constitute
abandonment of the application, resulting in the dismissal of the application.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-927-1__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>An application for post conviction relief shall be deemed to be abandoned when
the petitioner fails to file any pleading in furtherance of disposition of the application for a
period of two years following the filing of the application, irrespective of the stage of the
proceedings.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-927-1__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>This Article shall be operative without a formal order when an abandonment of
an application pursuant to Paragraph B of this Article has occurred.  On ex parte motion of
the district attorney or the attorney general, accompanied by an affidavit that states that
action has not been timely taken, the court shall enter a formal order of dismissal as of the
date of the application's abandonment.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-927-1__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the petitioner has a shell petition pending as of July 1, 2025, he shall submit a
fully-briefed petition to the court no later than July 1, 2026, unless a shorter period of time
has been established by the court.  Any application for post conviction relief filed before July
1, 2023, shall be dismissed, set for a hearing, or otherwise adjudicated no later than July 1,
2026, unless the court has good cause to establish a later date, provided however that the
claims shall be fully adjudicated no later than January 1, 2027.  The district attorney or the
attorney general shall have a right to seek mandamus to enforce this Paragraph.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-927-1__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the purposes of this Article, &quot;pleading in furtherance of disposition of the
application&quot; means a filing that seeks the trial court's ruling on the merits of the application
or a claim asserted therein, such as a motion to set the case on the docket, a motion seeking
an order, or an application for writ of mandamus seeking a ruling on the application.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=1429003</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>