<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-14-3-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-14-3-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CA 14 3(D)"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-14-3-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-14-3-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-14-3-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-14-3-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CA-14-3-D">
        <num>CA 14 3(D)</num>
        <heading>PAROCHIAL AND MUNICIPAL AFFAIRS</heading>
        <content>
          <p>Art.  XIV.  PAROCHIAL AND MUNICIPAL AFFAIRS
ยง3(d).  Acquisition and financing of sewerage improvements
Section 3(d).  The governing authority of East Baton Rouge Parish may
create within such parish sewerage districts, including one or more
consolidated sewerage districts comprised of one or more existing sewerage
districts, together with, if so determined by the governing authority, territory
not within the boundaries of an existing sewerage district.  Consolidated
sewerage districts so created shall constitute sewerage districts within the
meaning of sub-section c of Section 14 of Article XIV of the Constitution and
as such shall enjoy all rights, powers and privileges enjoyed by other sewerage
districts under the provisions of said section, including the right to issue bonds,
and shall also have the right to issue certificates of indebtedness secured by
local or special assessments.
Before any such consolidated district shall be finally created the
governing authority of the parish shall publish in the official journal of the
parish at least once not less than fifteen days prior to the date of hearing a
notice of its intention to create such district and fixing a date for the holding
of a public hearing in which all persons interested may be heard on the
question of benefit accruing to their property by reason of the creation of the
district.  The governing authority in determining the boundaries of any such
consolidated district shall take into consideration the question of benefits
accruing to the property therein.  Such notice of hearing shall set forth the
proposed name and boundaries of the district, list the districts to be so
consolidated and state the amount of outstanding indebtedness of each and
shall state the time and place fixed for the hearing.  Following the hearing on
the creation of any such district the resolution creating such district shall be
published one time in the official journal of the parish.  Thirty days after such
publication the creation of the district shall become incontestable and no court
shall have any right to entertain litigation questioning the legality of the
creation of such district.  If the governing authority shall desire to call an
election in any such district on the issuance of bonds, the levy of special taxes
or the assumption of indebtedness, notice of such election may be published
during the expiration of such thirty day period.
At the expiration of such thirty day period, sewerage districts included
in any such consolidated district shall no longer have the right to issue bonds
and all books and records and assets thereof shall be transferred to the
consolidated district.  Unless such consolidated district shall vote to assume
the indebtedness of each underlying district as hereinafter provided, it shall be
the duty of the governing authority of the consolidated district to cause taxes
to continue to be levied for the payment of the outstanding indebtedness except
that where such indebtedness of any underlying district consists of revenue
bonds payable from service charges or obligations payable from the proceeds
of special assessments, the governing authority shall continue to impose and
collect such service charges and assessments.  Such taxes as may be levied by
the governing authority of the consolidated district in the underlying districts
shall be entitled to the benefit of the exemption and reimbursal authorized by
R.S.  39:253.
Consolidated sewerage districts created hereunder shall have all rights,
powers and privileges granted to and enjoyed by other sewerage districts under
the Constitution and laws of Louisiana.
The creation of any consolidated sewerage district hereunder shall not
affect or impair in any manner contract rights enjoyed by the holders of any
outstanding bonds of the underlying districts and to the extent required by such
contract rights, taxes, special assessments and service charges on the property
subject to the payment of principal of and interest on such bonds shall continue
to be levied as above provided, provided however, that any consolidated
sewerage district may assume all indebtedness of its underlying districts in the
manner and with the effect provided by R.S.  39:661 et seq.  for the
assumption of indebtedness by parishes.  In the event indebtedness is so
assumed, taxes for the payment thereof shall be levied by the governing
authority on all taxable property in the consolidated district.  Where sewerage
districts consolidated into any consolidated district hereunder have been in
existence prior to August 1, 1956, the creation of the consolidated district will
be solely for the purpose of continuing the sewer improvement programs for
which the districts so consolidated were originally created and the provisions
of R.S.  39:253 shall be regarded as applicable in all respects to all taxes levied
by any such consolidated district and such district shall be considered to be a
district created prior to August 1, 1956, for all purposes of said section.
For the purpose of this section, any sewerage district which may have
been theretofore created and which does not at the time of consolidation have
outstanding any indebtedness or unexpired special taxes may be considered by
the governing authority to be an existing district for purposes of consolidation
or such district may be abolished by the governing authority and the territory
therein contained regarded as unorganized territory for sewerage purposes.
Any consolidated sewerage district created hereunder in addition to its
right to issue bonds for improvement purposes payable from sewer revenues
is hereby empowered to issue its refunding bonds for the purpose of refunding
any outstanding bonds of one or more of its underlying districts, or in its
discretion, may authorize and deliver a single issue of revenue bonds for both
improvement and refunding purposes.  Nothing in this paragraph shall be
construed to authorize the refunding of any bonds which have not matured or
been properly called for redemption under a right of redemption therein
reserved or which the holders thereof may not voluntarily surrender. 
Refunding bonds so authorized shall be authorized and issued in the manner
provided by law for the issuance of other bonds of sewerage districts and shall
be secured in the manner so provided by law, except that the governing
authority may, in its discretion, provide for changes in the source of payment
of such bonds as it may consider desirable and except that any refunding bonds
so authorized may be either sold or may be delivered in exchange for a like
principal amount of the bonds refunded or may be sold in part or exchanged
in part.  Where any such refunding bonds are issued for the purpose of
refunding bonds which are maturing or have been called for redemption within
a period of six months from the issuance of such refunding bonds, such bonds
may be sold and the proceeds thereof escrowed to be used in paying the bonds
refunded on the date on which they so become payable through maturity or call
for redemption.  No election shall be necessary to the issuance of such
refunding bonds.  The provisions of law applicable to maturities and interest
rates borne by other revenue bonds of sewerage districts shall be applicable to
such refunding bonds.  Refunding bonds so issued shall not exceed in principal
amount the principal amount of the bonds to be so refunded.  Where any such
underlying district has outstanding bonds payable from ad valorem taxes and
the indebtedness represented by such bonds is assumed by the consolidated
district as herein authorized, the bonds of such underlying district may be
refunded into bonds of the consolidated district in the manner provided in this
paragraph for the refunding of revenue bonds.
The governing authority may, in its discretion, pledge the full faith,
credit and resources of the issuing sewerage district or of East Baton Rouge
Parish to the payment of principal and interest on any bonds, certificates or
other obligations authorized by any sewerage district in said parish whether or
not such bonds, certificates or obligations are payable, under the law pursuant
to which they are issued, solely from sewerage service charges, from special
assessments, from the proceeds of ad valorem taxes or any combination
thereof.  Where the full faith, credit and resources of any such district or of the
parish is so pledged, it shall be the duty of the governing body to provide by
appropriate resolution for the manner in which the general revenues and tax
proceeds of such district or of the parish, as the case may be, shall be made
applicable to the remedying of any deficits which may exist in the revenues
pledged to the payment of such bonds, certificates or other obligations.  Said
resolution may provide that the governing body of the parish will to the extent
necessary to make certain the prompt and full payment of all principal and
interest due on such bonds, certificates or obligations of any district issued
pursuant hereto, set aside, dedicate and pledge so much of the general revenues
of the parish in each year for the years through which the bonds, certificates
or obligations are payable as may be necessary to pay them promptly in
principal and interest as they mature, and to apply to the payment of such
bonds, certificates or obligations such other tax revenues as may be lawfully
levied and collected by the said parish to pay the said debt.  Where as the result
of pledging of such full faith, credit and resources general revenues or tax
proceeds are used for the purpose of remedying any such deficit or deficits the
parish shall be entitled to reimbursement from the first revenues pledged to the
payment of such bonds, certificates or obligations thereafter received and not
currently required for the payment of pr</p>
        </content>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=67975</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>