<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1161"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1161"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 1161"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1161/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1161/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1161/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1161/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-1161">
        <num>CHC 1161</num>
        <heading>1161.  Official Safe Haven symbol</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1161__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The legislature hereby creates an official Safe Haven symbol for use in identifying
to the public those sites which are classified as designated emergency care facilities pursuant
to the provisions of this Chapter, and for any other use which the department deems
necessary or advantageous in fulfilling the purposes set forth in this Chapter.  The design and
promulgation of the symbol shall be in accordance with the provisions of this Article.
B.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1161__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The general design of the Safe Haven symbol shall be as follows:  Two solid
lines, each oriented diagonally, meeting to form an apex in the style of a gable roof;
superimposed upon and just underneath the image of the roof being a stylized figure
symbolic of an infant, oriented almost horizontally, consisting of a circle representing the
infant's head proximate to or adjoining an oval representing the infant's body; superimposed
upon and just underneath the figure of the infant being a stylized figure symbolic of the lower
two-thirds of an arm and a hand of a person, oriented almost horizontally and opposite the
direction in which the infant's head lies, with the figure of the arm bent in curvilinear form
upward from the position of the elbow in a cradling posture; the design elements,
collectively, giving the appearance of an infant cradled in the arm of a person under the
shelter of a roof. The color of these design elements shall be black.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1161__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The department shall promulgate in rule the image that shall constitute the
official Safe Haven symbol.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1161__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The department is hereby authorized, but is not required, to produce electronic
and physical copies of the Safe Haven symbol with any of the following features individually
or in any combination:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1161__subsec_C__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Text reading &quot;SAFE BABY SITE&quot; in all capital letters appearing above the
symbol.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1161__subsec_C__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A background that is either white or a shade of yellow typically used for traffic
warning signs indicating necessity of caution.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=1015843</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>