<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-328"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-328"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 328"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-328/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-328/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-328/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-328/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-328">
        <num>CCRP 328</num>
        <heading>328.  Bail undertaking</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-328__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The bail undertaking shall:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-328__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Be in writing.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-328__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>State the court before which the defendant is bound to appear.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-328__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Be entered into before an officer who is authorized to take it.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-328__subsec_A__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>State a single amount of bail for each charge.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-328__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The bail undertaking shall be enforceable if the above requirements are met; and
no officer may refuse to accept the posting of a bail undertaking and releasing a defendant
on bail if the conditions set by this Title are met.  A person shall not be discharged from his
bail undertaking, nor shall a judgment of forfeiture be stayed, set aside, or reversed, nor the
collection of any such judgment be barred or defeated by reason of any defect of form,
omission of a recital, or of a condition of the undertaking, by reason of a failure to note or
record the default of any defendant or surety, or because of any other irregularity.  The bail
undertaking shall run, subject to the provisions of Article 626, in favor of the state of
Louisiana, or the city or parish whose ordinance is charged to have been violated, with the
proceeds to be disposed of according to law.  No error, inaccuracy, or omission in naming
the obligee on the bail undertaking is a defense to an action thereon.
C.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-328__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An electronic bond may be executed in a parish where the sheriff has electronic
bond software in place.  Agents may be approved by the sheriff to execute an electronic
bond.  A licensed bail bond producer applying for electronic bond authority may make an
application to the sheriff and shall be domiciled and maintain a principal place of business
in this state and possess a Louisiana bail bond producer license for at least three years
preceding the date of application.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-328__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The approving sheriff authority may require any documents deemed necessary
to verify the information contained in the application.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112449</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>