<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-404"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-404"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CE 404"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-404/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-404/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-404/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-404/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CE-404">
        <num>CE 404</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="CE-404__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Character evidence generally.  Evidence of a person's character or a trait of his
character, such as a moral quality, is not admissible in a civil or criminal proceeding for the
purpose of proving that he acted in conformity therewith on a particular occasion, except:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CE-404__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Character of accused.  Evidence of a pertinent trait of his character, such as a
moral quality, offered by an accused, or by the prosecution to rebut the character evidence;
provided that such evidence shall be restricted to showing those moral qualities pertinent to
the crime with which he is charged, and that character evidence cannot destroy conclusive
evidence of guilt.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-404__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Character of victim.</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-404__subsec_A__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Except as provided in Article 412, evidence of a
pertinent trait of character, such as a moral quality, of the victim of the crime offered by an
accused, or by the prosecution to rebut the character evidence; provided that in the absence
of evidence of a hostile demonstration or an overt act on the part of the victim at the time of
the offense charged, evidence of his dangerous character is not admissible; provided further
that when the accused pleads self-defense and there is a history of assaultive behavior
between the victim and the accused and the accused lived in a familial or intimate
relationship such as, but not limited to, the husband-wife, parent-child, or concubinage
relationship, it shall not be necessary to first show a hostile demonstration or overt act on the
part of the victim in order to introduce evidence of the dangerous character of the victim,
including specific instances of conduct and domestic violence; and further provided that an
expert's opinion as to the effects of the prior assaultive acts on the accused's state of mind is
admissible; or</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-404__subsec_A__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Evidence of a character trait of peacefulness of the victim offered by the
prosecution in a homicide case to rebut evidence that the victim was the first aggressor;</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-404__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Character of witness.  Evidence of the character of a witness, as provided in
Articles 607, 608, and 609.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-404__subsec_A__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In any prosecution for a violation of R.S. 14:71.1 or 72.2, the prosecution may
enter as evidence any of the following of a perpetrator's intent to deceive or defraud:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-404__subsec_A__subsec_4__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any previously cashed or deposited counterfeit or forged check or other monetary
instrument.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-404__subsec_A__subsec_4__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Evidence regarding any previous attempt to cash or deposit a counterfeit or
forged check or other monetary instrument.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-404__subsec_A__subsec_4__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Evidence of a verbal or written communication, including but not limited to a
warning, by a law enforcement agent with the perpetrator regarding the cashing or depositing
of a forged or counterfeit check or other monetary instrument suspected of being part of a
fraudulent scheme or warning the perpetrator that such transaction could be in violation of
state or federal criminal laws.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CE-404__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Other crimes, wrongs, or acts; creative or artistic expression.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CE-404__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In the absence of evidence of a hostile demonstration or an overt act on the part
of the victim at the time of the offense charged, evidence of the victim's prior threats against
the accused or the accused's state of mind as to the victim's dangerous character is not
admissible; provided that when the accused pleads self-defense and there is a history of
assaultive behavior between the victim and the accused and the accused lived in a familial
or intimate relationship such as, but not limited to, the husband-wife, parent-child, or
concubinage relationship, it shall not be necessary to first show a hostile demonstration or
overt act on the part of the victim in order to introduce evidence of the dangerous character
of the victim, including specific instances of conduct and domestic violence; and further
provided that an expert's opinion as to the effects of the prior assaultive acts on the accused's
state of mind is admissible.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=72458</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>