<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-228-2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-228-2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 228.2"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-228-2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-228-2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-228-2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-228-2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-228-2">
        <num>CCRP 228.2</num>
        <heading>228.2.  Disposal of property of prisoners; Orleans Parish excepted</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-228-2__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any property taken from a prisoner in any of the penal institutions under
the jurisdiction of any sheriff, Orleans excepted, which is in the possession of the
sheriff on July 31, 2001, shall, after ninety days from the release of said prisoner, be
disposed of, if unclaimed, in the following manner:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-228-2__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>There shall be notice of the sheriff's right to dispose of the property in
ninety days on the entry of the list of property made at the time the person was
incarcerated.  Provided however, this provision shall not apply to property in
possession of the sheriff on September 12, 1975.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-228-2__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>After the passage of ninety days from the release of the prisoner, any
sheriff may petition the court having proper jurisdiction for the disposal of said
property in any lawful manner, at his discretion.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-228-2__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Before any sheriff petitions said court, he shall cause an advertisement
of his intention to seek approval of the court to be placed in the newspaper
designated as the official journal of the parish one time at least ten days prior to filing
of his petition and shall mail a copy of the advertisement to the prisoner at his last
known address, postage prepaid.  In the petition for disposal the sheriff shall set forth
a brief description of the items to be disposed of, the court in which the proceedings
will be filed, the title of the proceedings, and method or methods of intended
disposal.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-228-2__subsec_A__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The petition of the sheriff shall make specific recommendations as to the
method of disposal for each item of unclaimed property and pray for the court to
order its disposal.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-228-2__subsec_A__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The court shall order the property disposed of in the manner contained
in the sheriff's petition or order the disposal of the property in any legal manner
within the sole discretion of the court.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-228-2__subsec_A__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The costs of the proceedings to dispose of unclaimed property shall be
derived from the disposal of the property as provided under this Paragraph.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-228-2__subsec_A__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any funds remaining after payment of the cost of the proceedings to
dispose of unclaimed property shall be deposited in the sheriff's salary fund.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-228-2__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any property taken from a prisoner in any of the penal institutions under
the jurisdiction of any sheriff, Orleans excepted, after July 31, 2001, shall be
disposed of after ninety days from the release or transfer of the prisoner, if
unclaimed, in the following manner:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-228-2__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The sheriff shall make a notation on the property list of the prisoner at the
time of incarceration that he has the right to dispose of unclaimed property as
provided in this Paragraph.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-228-2__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The sheriff or an officer acting on his behalf shall provide written notice
of the sheriff's right to dispose of unclaimed property to each prisoner upon the
release or transfer of such prisoner.  The sheriff or officer shall require the prisoner
to sign the written notice acknowledging the sheriff's right to dispose of such
property.  In the event that the prisoner refuses to sign the acknowledgment, the
sheriff or officer shall make a notation on the written notice that the prisoner refused
to sign the acknowledgment of such right.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-228-2__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>After notice is given to the prisoner and after the expiration of ninety days
from the date of release or transfer of the prisoner, if the property of the prisoner
remains unclaimed, the sheriff may dispose of such property in any lawful manner
at his discretion, including but not limited to authorizing the unclaimed property to
be destroyed, donated to a charitable organization, or put into lawful use within the
institution from which the inmate was released or transferred.  Any legal tender
which remains unclaimed shall be placed in a fund for the benefit of all inmates at
such institution.  A record of the disposition of all unclaimed property shall be
maintained for a period of two years from the date of disposal.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-228-2__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the purposes of this Article, &quot;unclaimed property&quot; means property that
a prisoner leaves at a correctional institution or fails to take upon his release or
transfer from the institution and to which no claim is made within ninety days of his
release or transfer from the institution.
Added by</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112383</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>