<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-804"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-804"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 804"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-804/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-804/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-804/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-804/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-804">
        <num>CHC 804</num>
        <heading>804.  Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-804__subsec_2">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Child care institution&quot; means a nonprofit, licensed private or public institution
which accommodates no more than twenty-five children and which is not a detention facility,
a forestry camp, a training school, or any other facility operated primarily for the detention
of children who are determined to be delinquent.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-804__subsec_3">
          <num>(3)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Delinquent act&quot; means an act committed by a child of ten years of age or older
which if committed by an adult is designated an offense under the statutes or ordinances of
this state, or of another state if the offense occurred there, or under federal law, except traffic
violations.  It includes an act constituting an offense under R.S. 14:95.8, an act constituting
an offense under R.S. 14:81.1.1(A)(2), and a direct contempt of court committed by a child. 
&quot;Delinquent act&quot; shall not include a violation of R.S. 14:82, 83.3, 83.4, 89, or 89.2 for a child
who, during the time of the alleged commission of the offense, was a victim of trafficking
of children for sexual purposes pursuant to R.S. 14:46.3(E).</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-804__subsec_4">
          <num>(4)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Delinquent child&quot; means a child who has committed a delinquent act.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-804__subsec_5">
          <num>(5)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Felony-grade delinquent act&quot; means an offense that if committed by an adult,
may be punished by death or by imprisonment at hard labor.  &quot;Felony-grade delinquent act&quot;
shall not include a violation of R.S. 14:82, 83.3, 83.4, 89, or 89.2 for a child who, during the
time of the alleged commission of the offense, was a victim of trafficking of children for
sexual purposes pursuant to R.S. 14:46.3(E).</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-804__subsec_6">
          <num>(6)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Insanity&quot; means a mental disease or mental illness which renders the child
incapable of distinguishing between right and wrong with reference to the conduct in
question, as a result of which the child is exempt from criminal responsibility.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-804__subsec_7">
          <num>(7)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Mental incapacity to proceed&quot; means that, as a result of mental illness or
developmental disability, a child presently lacks the capacity to understand the nature of the
proceedings against him or to assist in his defense.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-804__subsec_8">
          <num>(8)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Misdemeanor-grade delinquent act&quot; means any offense which if committed by
an adult is other than a felony and includes the violation of an ordinance providing a penal
sanction.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-804__subsec_9">
          <num>(9)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Sexually exploited child&quot; means any person under the age of eighteen who has
been subject to sexual exploitation because the person:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-804__subsec_9__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Is a victim of trafficking of children for sexual purposes under R.S. 14:46.3.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-804__subsec_9__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Is a victim of child sex trafficking under 18 U.S.C. 1591.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=73392</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>