<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-684"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-684"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 684"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-684/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-684/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-684/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-684/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-684">
        <num>CHC 684</num>
        <heading>684.  Judgment of disposition</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-684__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court shall enter into the record a written judgment of disposition specifying
the following:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-684__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The nature of the disposition.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-684__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The maximum duration of the disposition.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-684__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The agency, institution, or person to whom the child is assigned, including the
responsibilities of any other agency, institution, or person having legal responsibility to
secure or provide services to the child which the court has determined are needed.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-684__subsec_A__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any other applicable terms and conditions regarding the disposition.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-684__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court shall enter a written order approving the case plan or specific written
reasons why the court finds the plan does not protect the health, welfare, and safety of the
child or is otherwise not in the best interest of the child.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-684__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>When the child is to be removed from the custody of the parent, the court shall
enter findings that continuation in the home would be contrary to the health, welfare, and
safety of the child.  Except as otherwise provided in Article 672.1, when the child is to be
removed from the custody of the parent, in support of its determination of whether
reasonable efforts, as defined in Article 603, have been made to prevent removal, the court
shall enter findings, including a description of what preventive and reunification efforts, or
both, were made and why additional efforts would not keep the child safe from identified
threats of danger.  If a child is to be or has been placed out-of-state, the court shall determine
and enter findings on whether the placement is safe, appropriate, and in the best interest of
the child.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-684__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>When a parent is absent, the court shall enter findings regarding diligent efforts
by the curator, the department, and others to locate that parent.  In the absence of findings
to the contrary, efforts to locate the parent shall be presumed sufficient.  If the court
determines additional search efforts are needed, it shall specifically identify those efforts.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-684__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In all cases in which the child is removed from his parents' custody and assigned
to the department, the court shall advise the parties and all persons before the court of the
following:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-684__subsec_E__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Procedures governing the case plan, case review, and permanency review
procedure, as provided for in Chapters 15 and 16 of this Title.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-684__subsec_E__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The obligation of the parents to cooperate with the department, comply with the
requirements of the case plan, including their duty to keep the department and their counsel
apprised in writing of their current whereabouts, including address, cellular number,
telephone number, and any other contact information, and correct the conditions requiring
the child to be in care.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-684__subsec_E__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The possibility that a petition to terminate parental rights may be filed based on
the parents' failure to comply with the case plan, failure to make significant measurable
progress toward achieving case plan goals and to correct the conditions requiring the child
to be in care, or on any other ground authorized by Article 1015.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-684__subsec_E__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The continuing responsibility of all persons before the court to advise the
department and the court in writing of the whereabouts, including the address, cellular
number, telephone number, and any other contact information, of an absent parent and the
identity and the whereabouts, including address, cellular number, telephone number, and any
other contact information, of any relative or other individual willing and able to offer a
wholesome and stable home for the child.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-684__subsec_E__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The continuing responsibility of all persons before the court to support the
achievement of timely permanency for the child and the requirement that those persons
advise the department and the court in writing of the whereabouts, including the address,
cellular number, telephone number, and any other contact information, of all grandparents,
all parents of a sibling where such parent has legal custody of such sibling, and all other adult
relatives of the child.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-684__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The date of entry of the judgment of disposition shall be recorded on the
judgment.  The advisement in Paragraph E of this Article shall be attached to the judgment
of disposition and any other orders of the court furnished to the parties.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-684__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>An extract of minutes of court specifying the information in Paragraph A of this
Article and signed by the court shall be considered a written judgment of disposition.  A copy
of the judgment of disposition shall be furnished to the parents, their counsel, or curator.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=73280</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>