<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-795"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-795"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 795"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-795/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-795/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-795/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-795/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-795">
        <num>CCRP 795</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-795__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A juror shall not be challenged for cause after having been temporarily accepted
pursuant to Article 788(A) unless the challenging party shows that the cause was not known
to him prior to that time.
B.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-795__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Peremptory challenges shall be exercised prior to the swearing of the jury
panel.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-795__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Peremptory challenges of jurors shall be made and communicated to the court
in a side bar conference of the judge, the attorneys conducting the examination and selection
of jurors, and the defendant in a case in which the defendant chooses to represent himself. 
The conference shall be conducted in a manner that only the court, the attorneys, and the
defendant in a case in which the defendant chooses to represent himself, are aware of the
challenges made until the court announces the challenges without reference to any party or
attorney in the case.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-795__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>No peremptory challenge made by the state or the defendant shall be motivated 
in substantial part on the basis of the race or gender of the juror.  If an objection is made that
a challenge was motivated in substantial part on the basis of race or gender, and a prima facie
case supporting that objection is made by the objecting party, the court shall demand a
satisfactory race or gender neutral reason for the exercise of the challenge.  Such demand and
disclosure shall be made outside of the hearing of any juror or prospective juror. The court
shall then determine whether the challenge was motivated in substantial part on the basis of
race or gender.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-795__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court shall allow to stand each peremptory challenge exercised for a race or
gender neutral reason either apparent from the examination or disclosed by counsel when
required by the court.  The provisions of Paragraph C of this Article and this Paragraph shall
not apply when both the state and the defense have exercised a challenge against the same
juror.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-795__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court shall allow to stand each peremptory challenge for which a satisfactory
racially neutral or gender neutral reason is given.  Those jurors who have been peremptorily
challenged and for whom no satisfactory racially neutral or gender neutral reason is apparent
or given may be ordered returned to the panel, or the court may take such other corrective
action as it deems appropriate under the circumstances.  The court shall make specific
findings regarding each such challenge.
Amended by</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112792</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>