<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-894"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-894"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 894"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-894/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-894/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-894/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-894/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-894">
        <num>CCRP 894</num>
        <heading>894.  Suspension and deferral of sentence; probation in misdemeanor cases</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-894__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nothing contained herein shall be construed as being a basis for destruction of
records of the arrest and prosecution of any person convicted of a misdemeanor.
D.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-894__subsec_C__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department of Public Safety and Corrections, office of motor vehicles,
shall serve as a repository for the records referred to in Subparagraph (A)</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-894__subsec_C__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Article
for any plea for operating a vehicle while intoxicated entered pursuant to the provisions of
this Article.  The department shall maintain records for a period of ten years.  The department
shall respond by certified mail to a request by any court, prosecuting agency, or defendant
seeking certified copies of the records or verification that the records are in the possession
of the department.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-894__subsec_C__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The records maintained by the department pursuant to this Article shall be
confidential, except as otherwise provided in this Article.  Certified copies of the records
maintained by the department shall be admissible only in a subsequent prosecution for
operating a vehicle while intoxicated and shall not be used for any other purpose.
(3)</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-894__subsec_C__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The Department of Insurance is hereby authorized to expend from any surplus
it derives from a fiscal year an amount not to exceed three hundred thousand dollars to the
office of motor vehicles to fully implement and maintain the electronic database established
in this Paragraph.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-894__subsec_C__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The Department of Insurance is further authorized to enter into cooperative
endeavor agreements with the Louisiana State Supreme Court, any district attorney's office,
or any clerk of court's office for training and usage of the database created by this Paragraph.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112888</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>