<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-895"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-895"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 895"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-895/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-895/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-895/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-895/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-895">
        <num>CCRP 895</num>
        <heading>895.  Conditions of probation</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-895__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>When the court places a defendant on probation, it shall require the defendant to
refrain from criminal conduct and to pay a supervision fee to defray the costs of probation
supervision, and it may impose any specific conditions reasonably related to his
rehabilitation, including any of the following.  That the defendant shall:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Make a full and truthful report at the end of each month;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Meet his specified family responsibilities, including any obligations imposed in
a court order of child support;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Report to the probation officer as directed;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895__subsec_A__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Permit the probation officer to visit him at his home or elsewhere;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895__subsec_A__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Devote himself to an approved employment or occupation;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895__subsec_A__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Refrain from owning or possessing firearms or other dangerous weapons;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895__subsec_A__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Make reasonable reparation or restitution to the aggrieved party for damage or
loss caused by his offense in an amount to be determined by the court;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895__subsec_A__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Refrain from frequenting unlawful or disreputable places or consorting with
disreputable persons;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895__subsec_A__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Remain within the jurisdiction of the court and get the permission of the
probation officer before making any change in his address or his employment; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895__subsec_A__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Devote himself to an approved reading program at his cost if he is unable to
read the English language.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895__subsec_A__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Perform community service work.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895__subsec_A__subsec_12">
            <num>(12)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Submit himself to available medical, psychiatric, mental health, or substance
abuse examination or treatment or both when deemed appropriate and ordered to do so by
the probation and parole officer.
(13)</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-895__subsec_A__subsec_12__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Agree to searches of his person, his property, his place of residence, his
vehicle, or his personal effects, or any or all of them, at any time, by the probation or parole
officer assigned to him or by any probation or parole officer who is subsequently assigned
or directed by the Department of Public Safety and Corrections to supervise the person,
whether the assignment or directive is temporary or permanent, with or without a warrant of
arrest or with or without a search warrant, when the probation officer or the parole officer
has reasonable suspicion to believe that the person who is on probation is engaged in or has
been engaged in criminal activity.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-895__subsec_A__subsec_12__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For those persons who have been convicted of a &quot;sex offense&quot; as defined in R.S.
15:541, agree to searches of his person, his property, his place of residence, his vehicle, or
his personal effects, or any or all of them, at any time, by a law enforcement officer, duly
commissioned in the parish or municipality where the sex offender resides or is domiciled,
designated by his agency to supervise sex offenders, with or without a warrant of arrest or
with or without a search warrant, when the officer has reasonable suspicion to believe that
the person who is on probation is engaged in or has been engaged in criminal activity for
which the person has not been charged or arrested while on probation.
B.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In felony cases, an additional condition of the probation may be that the
defendant shall serve a term of imprisonment without hard labor for a period not to exceed
two years.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In felony cases assigned to the drug division probation program pursuant to the
provisions of R.S. 13:5304, the court may impose as a condition of probation that the
defendant successfully complete the intensive incarceration program established pursuant to
R.S. 15:574.4.4.  If the defendant is not accepted into the intensive incarceration program or
fails to successfully complete the intensive incarceration program, the court shall reconsider
the sentence imposed as provided in Article 881.1.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In felony cases, an additional condition of the probation may be that the
defendant be ordered to be committed to the custody of the Department of Public Safety and
Corrections and be required to serve a sentence of not more than twelve months without
diminution of sentence in the intensive incarceration program pursuant to the provisions of
R.S. 15:574.4.4.  Upon successful completion of the program, the defendant shall return to
supervised probation for a period of time as ordered by the court, subject to any additional
conditions imposed by the court and under the same provisions of law under which the
defendant was originally sentenced.  If an offender is denied entry into the intensive
incarceration program for physical or mental health reasons or for failure to meet the
department's suitability criteria, the department shall notify the sentencing court, and the
offender shall be resentenced in accordance with the provisions of Article 881.1.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-895__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In cases of violations of the Uniform Controlled Dangerous Substances Law, the
court may order the suspension or restriction of the defendant's driving privileges, if any, for
all or part of the period of probation.  In such cases, a copy of the order shall be forwarded
to the Department of Public Safety and Corrections, which shall suspend the defendant's
driver's license or issue a restricted license in accordance with the orders of the court. 
Additionally, the court may order the defendant to:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895__subsec_C__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Submit to and pay all costs for drug testing by an approved laboratory at the
direction of his probation officer.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895__subsec_C__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Perform not less than one hundred sixty hours nor more than nine hundred sixty
hours of community service work.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-895__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court may, in lieu of the monthly supervision fee provided for in Paragraph
A, require the defendant to perform a specified amount of community service work each
month if the court finds the defendant is unable to pay the supervision fee provided for in
Paragraph A.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-895__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Before the court places a sexual offender on probation, it shall order the offender
who has not previously been tested to submit to a blood and saliva test in accordance with
R.S. 15:535.  All costs shall be paid by the offender.  Serial sexual offenders sentenced
pursuant to R.S. 15:537(B) shall not be eligible for parole or probation.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-895__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In cases of any violation of Subpart (A)</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895__subsec_F__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of Part V of Chapter 1 of Title 14 of
the Louisiana Revised Statutes of 1950 or R.S. 14:92(7), the court may order the defendant
to submit to psychological evaluation and, if indicated, order him to obtain psychiatric or
psychological counseling for all or part of the period of probation.  All costs shall be paid by
the defendant.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-895__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Before the court places the defendant on probation, it shall determine if the
defendant has a high school degree or its equivalent and, if the defendant does not, it shall
order the defendant to take a reading proficiency test.  If the defendant scores below a sixth
grade level on the reading proficiency test, the court shall condition probation upon the
defendant's enrolling in and attending an adult education or reading program until he attains
a sixth grade reading level or until his term of probation expires, whichever occurs first.  All
costs shall be paid by the defendant.  If the court finds that there are no adult education or
reading programs in the parish in which the defendant is domiciled, the defendant is unable
to afford such a program, or attendance would create an undue hardship on the defendant,
the court may suspend this condition of probation.  The provisions of this Paragraph shall not
apply to those defendants who are mentally, physically, or by reason of age, infirmity,
dyslexia or other such learning disorders unable to participate.
H.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895__subsec_G__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In cases where the defendant has been convicted of or adjudication has been
deferred or withheld for the perpetration or attempted perpetration of a sex offense as defined
in R.S. 15:541, and probation is permitted by law and when the court places a defendant on
probation, the court shall order the offender to register as a sex offender and to provide
notification in accordance with the provisions of R.S. 15:540 et seq.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895__subsec_G__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The defendant must state under oath where he will reside after sentencing and
that he will advise the court of any subsequent change of address during the probationary
period.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895__subsec_G__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>No offender who is the parent, stepparent, or has legal custody and physical
custody of the child who is the victim shall be released on probation unless the victim has
received psychological counseling prior to the offender's release if the offender is returning
to the residence or community in which the child resides.  Such psychological counseling
shall include an attempt by the health care provider to ease the psychological impact upon
the child of the notice required under Subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895__subsec_G__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Paragraph, including assisting
the child in coping with potential insensitive comments and actions by the child's neighbors
and peers.  The cost of such counseling shall be paid by the offender.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895__subsec_G__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Repealed by</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112892</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>