<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-1002"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-1002"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 1002"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-1002/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-1002/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-1002/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-1002/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-1002">
        <num>CCRP 1002</num>
        <heading>1002.  Transfer of firearms</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-1002__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>At the same time an order to prohibit a person from possessing a firearm or
carrying a concealed weapon is issued, the court shall also cause all of the following to occur:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-1002__subsec_C__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Require the person to state in open court or complete an affidavit stating the
number of firearms in his possession and the location of all firearms in his possession.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-1002__subsec_C__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Require the person to complete a firearm information form that states the number
of firearms in his possession, the type of each firearm, and the location of each firearm.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-1002__subsec_C__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Transmit a copy of the order to transfer firearms and a copy of the firearm
information form to the sheriff of the parish or the sheriff of the parish of the person's
residence.
D.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-1002__subsec_C__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The court shall, on the record and in open court, order the person to transfer
all firearms in his possession to the sheriff no later than forty-eight hours, exclusive of legal
holidays, after the order is issued and a copy of the order and firearm information form
required by Paragraph C of this Article is sent to the sheriff. If the person is incarcerated at
the time the order is issued, he shall transfer his firearms no later than forty-eight hours after
his release from incarceration, exclusive of legal holidays.  At the time of transfer, the sheriff
and the person shall complete a proof of transfer form. The proof of transfer form shall
contain the quantity of firearms transferred.  The sheriff shall retain a copy of the form and
provide the person with a copy.  The proof of transfer form shall attest that the person is not
currently in possession of firearms in accordance with the provisions of this Title and is
currently compliant with state and federal law, but shall not include the date on which the
transfer occurred.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-1002__subsec_C__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Within ten days of transferring his firearms, exclusive of legal holidays, the
person shall file the proof of transfer form with the clerk of court of the parish in which the
order was issued.  The proof of transfer form shall be maintained by the clerk of court under
seal.
E.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-1002__subsec_C__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the person subject to the order to transfer firearms and suspend a concealed
handgun permit issued pursuant to Paragraph A of this Article does not possess firearms, at
the time the order is issued, the person shall complete a declaration of nonpossession form
which shall be filed in the court record and a copy shall be provided to the sheriff.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-1002__subsec_C__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Within five days of the issuance of the order pursuant to Paragraph A of this
Article, exclusive of legal holidays, the person shall file the declaration of nonpossession
with the clerk of court of the parish in which the order was issued.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-1002__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of Paragraph E of this Article or any other
provision of law to the contrary, if the person subject to the order to transfer firearms and
suspend a concealed handgun permit issued pursuant to Paragraph A of this Article possessed
firearms at the time of the qualifying incident giving rise to the duty to transfer his firearms
pursuant to this Title, but transferred or sold his firearms to a third party prior to the court's
issuance of the order, that third-party transfer shall be declared in open court.  The person
subject to the order to transfer firearms and suspend a concealed handgun permit shall within
ten days after issuance of the order, exclusive of legal holidays, execute along with the third
party and a witness a proof of transfer form that complies with the provisions of Paragraph
D of this Article and with Article 1003(A)(1)(a).  The proof of transfer form need not be
signed by the sheriff and shall be filed, within ten days after the date on which the proof of
transfer form is executed, by the person subject to the order with the clerk of court of the
parish in which the order was issued.  The proof of transfer form shall be maintained by the
clerk of court under seal.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-1002__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The failure to provide the information required by this Title, the failure to timely
transfer firearms in accordance with the provisions of this Title, or both, may be punished
as contempt of court.  Information required to be provided in order to comply with the
provisions of this Title cannot be used as evidence against that person in a future criminal
proceeding, except as provided by the laws on perjury or false swearing.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-1002__subsec_H">
          <num>H.</num>
          <content>
            <p>On motion of the district attorney or of the person transferring his firearms, and
for good cause shown, the court shall conduct a contradictory hearing with the district
attorney to ensure that the person has complied with the provisions of this Title.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-1002__subsec_I">
          <num>I.</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the purposes of this Title, a person shall be deemed to be in possession of a
firearm if that firearm is subject to his dominion and control.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=1106499</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>