<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-510"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-510"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CE 510"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-510/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-510/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-510/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-510/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CE-510">
        <num>CE 510</num>
        <heading>510.  Health care provider-patient privilege</heading>
        <subsection eId="CE-510__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Definitions. The definitions of health care provider, physician, psychotherapist,
and their representatives as provided in this Article include persons reasonably believed to
be such by the patient or his representative. As used in this Article:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>&quot;Health care provider&quot; is a person or entity defined as such in R.S. 13:3734(A),
and includes a physician and psychotherapist as defined below, and also includes a person
who is engaged in any office, center, or institution referred to as a rape crisis center, who has
undergone at least forty hours of sexual assault training and who is engaged in rendering
advice, counseling, or assistance to victims of sexual assault.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>&quot;Health condition&quot; is a physical, mental, or emotional condition, including a
condition induced by alcohol, drugs, or other substance.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>&quot;Patient&quot; is a person who consults or is examined or interviewed by another for
the purpose of receiving advice, diagnosis, or treatment in regard to that person's health.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>&quot;Physician&quot; is a person licensed to practice medicine in any state or nation.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>&quot;Psychotherapist&quot; is:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_6__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A physician engaged in the diagnosis or treatment of a mental or emotional
condition, including a condition induced by alcohol, drugs, or other substance.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_6__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A person licensed or certified as a psychologist under the laws of any state or
nation.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_6__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A person licensed as a licensed professional  counselor or social worker under
the laws of any state or nation.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>&quot;Representative&quot; of a physician, psychotherapist, or other health care provider
is:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_7__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A person acting under the supervision, direction, control, or request of a
physician, psychotherapist, or health care provider engaged in the diagnosis or treatment of
the patient.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_7__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Personnel of a &quot;hospital&quot;, as defined in R.S. 13:3734(A)</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>&quot;Representative of a patient&quot; is any person who makes or receives a confidential
communication for the purpose of effectuating diagnosis or treatment of a patient.
B.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>General rule of privilege in civil proceedings.  In a non-criminal proceeding,
a patient has a privilege to refuse to disclose and to prevent another person from disclosing
a confidential communication made for the purpose of advice, diagnosis or treatment of his
health condition between or among himself or his representative, his health care provider,
or their representatives.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Exceptions.  There is no privilege under this Article in a noncriminal proceeding
as to a communication:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When the communication relates to the health condition of a patient who brings
or asserts a personal injury claim in a judicial or worker's compensation proceeding.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When the communication relates to the health condition of a deceased patient in
a wrongful death, survivorship, or worker's compensation proceeding brought or asserted as
a consequence of the death or injury of the deceased patient.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When the communication is relevant to an issue of the health condition of the
patient in any proceeding in which the patient is a party and relies upon the condition as an
element of his claim or defense or, after the patient's death, in any proceeding in which a
party deriving his right from the patient relies on the patient's health condition as an element
of his claim or defense.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_2__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When the communication relates to the health condition of a patient when the
patient is a party to a proceeding for custody or visitation of a child and the condition has a
substantial bearing on the fitness of the person claiming custody or visitation, or when the
patient is a child who is the subject of a custody or visitation proceeding.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_2__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When the communication made to the health care provider was intended to assist
the patient or another person to commit or plan to commit what the patient knew or
reasonably should have known to be a crime or fraud.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_2__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When the communication is made in the course of an examination ordered by the
court with respect to the health condition of a patient, the fact that the examination was so
ordered was made known to the patient prior to the communication, and the communication
concerns the particular purpose for which the examination was made, unless the court in its
order directing the examination has stated otherwise.
(g)</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_2__subsec_i">
              <num>(i)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When the communication is made by a patient who is the subject of an
interdiction or commitment proceeding to his current health care provider when such patient
has failed or refused to submit to an examination by a health care provider appointed by the
court regarding issues relating to the interdiction or commitment proceeding, provided that
the patient has been advised of such appointment and the consequences of not submitting to
the examination.
(ii)  Notwithstanding the provisions of Subitem</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_2__subsec_i">
              <num>(i)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this Item, in any commitment
proceeding, the court-appointed physician may review the medical records of the patient or
respondent and testify as to communications therein, but only those which are essential to
determine whether the patient is dangerous to himself, dangerous to others, or unable to
survive safely in freedom or protect himself from serious harm.  However, such
communications shall not be disclosed unless the patient was informed prior to the
communication that such communications are not privileged in any subsequent commitment
proceedings.  The court-appointed examination shall be governed by Item B</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_2__subsec_h">
              <num>(h)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When the communication is relevant in proceedings held by peer review
committees and other disciplinary bodies to determine whether a particular health care
provider has deviated from applicable professional standards.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_2__subsec_i">
              <num>(i)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When the communication is one regarding the blood alcohol level or other test
for the presence of drugs of a patient and an action for damages for injury, death, or loss has
been brought against the patient.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_2__subsec_j">
              <num>(j)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When disclosure of the communication is necessary for the defense of the health
care provider in a malpractice action brought by the patient.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_2__subsec_k">
              <num>(k)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When the communication is relevant to proceedings concerning issues of child
abuse, elder abuse, or the abuse of persons with disabilities or persons who are incompetent.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_2__subsec_l">
              <num>(l)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When the communication is relevant after the death of a patient, concerning the
capacity of the patient to enter into the contract which is the subject matter of the litigation.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_2__subsec_m">
              <num>(m)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When the communication is relevant in an action contesting any testament
executed or claimed to have been executed by the patient now deceased.
C.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>General rule of privilege in criminal proceedings.  In a criminal proceeding,
a patient has a privilege to refuse to disclose and to prevent another person from disclosing
a confidential communication made for the purpose of advice, diagnosis or treatment of his
health condition between or among himself, his representative, and his physician or
psychotherapist, and their representatives.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Exceptions.  There is no privilege under this Article in a criminal case as to a
communication:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When the communication is relevant to an issue of the health condition of the
accused in any proceeding in which the accused relies upon the condition as an element of
his defense.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When the communication was intended to assist the patient or another person to
commit or plan to commit what the patient knew or reasonably should have known to be a
crime or fraud.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When the communication was made in the course of an examination ordered by
the court in a criminal case to determine the health condition of a patient, provided that a
copy of the order was served on the patient prior to the communication.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_2__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When the communication is a record of the results of a test for blood alcohol
level or drugs taken from a patient who is under arrest, or who was subsequently arrested for
an offense related to the test.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_2__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When the communication is in the form of a tangible object, including a bullet,
that is removed from the body of a patient and which was in the body as a result of the crime
charged.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-510__subsec_A__subsec_2__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When the communication is relevant to an investigation of or prosecution for
child abuse, elder abuse, or the abuse of persons with disabilities or persons who are
incompetent.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CE-510__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Who may claim the privilege.  In both civil and criminal proceedings, the
privilege may be claimed by the patient or by his legal representative.  The person who was
the physician, psychotherapist, or health care provider or their representatives, at the time of
the communication is presumed to have authority to claim the privilege on behalf of the
patient or deceased patient.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CE-510__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Waiver.  The exceptions to the privilege set forth in Paragraph B</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CE-510__subsec_E__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>shall
constitute a waiver of the privilege only as to testimony at trial or to discovery of the
privileged communication by one of the discovery methods authorized by Code of Civil
Procedure Article 1421 et seq.,  or pursuant to R.S. 40:1165.1 or R.S. 13:3715.1.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CE-510__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Medical malpractice.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CE-510__subsec_F__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>There shall be no health care provider-patient privilege
in medical malpractice claims as defined in R.S. 40:1231.1 et seq. as to information directly
and specifically related to the factual issues pertaining to the liability of a health care
provider who is a named party in a pending lawsuit or medical review panel proceeding.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-510__subsec_F__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In medical malpractice claims information about a patient's current treatment or
physical condition may only be disclosed pursuant to testimony at trial, pursuant to one of
the discovery methods authorized by Code of Civil Procedure Article 1421 et seq., pursuant
to R.S. 40:1165.1 or R.S. 13:3715.1.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CE-510__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Sanctions.  Any attorney who violates a provision of this Article shall be subject
to sanctions by the court.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=72481</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>