<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1302-7"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1302-7"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 1302.7"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1302-7/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1302-7/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1302-7/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1302-7/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-1302-7">
        <num>CHC 1302.7</num>
        <heading>1302.7.  Determination of controlling child support order</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1302-7__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a proceeding is brought under this Chapter and only one tribunal has issued a
child support order, the order of that tribunal controls and must be recognized.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1302-7__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a proceeding is brought under this Chapter, and two or more child support
orders have been issued by tribunals of this state, another state, or a foreign country with
regard to the same obligor and same child, a tribunal of this state having personal jurisdiction
over both the obligor and individual obligee shall apply the following rules and by order shall
determine which order controls and must be recognized:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1302-7__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If only one of the tribunals would have continuing, exclusive jurisdiction under
this Chapter, the order of that tribunal controls.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1302-7__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If more than one of the tribunals would have continuing, exclusive jurisdiction
under this Chapter:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-1302-7__subsec_B__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An order issued by a tribunal in the current home state of the child controls, or</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-1302-7__subsec_B__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If an order has not been issued in the current home state of the child, the order
most recently issued controls.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1302-7__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If none of the tribunals would have continuing, exclusive jurisdiction under this
Chapter, the tribunal of this state shall issue a child support order, which controls.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1302-7__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If two or more child support orders have been issued for the same obligor and
same child, upon request of a party who is an individual or that is a support enforcement
agency, a tribunal of this state having personal jurisdiction over both the obligor and the
obligee who is an individual shall  determine which order controls under Paragraph B of this
Article. The request may be filed with a registration for enforcement or registration for
modification pursuant to Section 6, or may be filed as a separate proceeding.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1302-7__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A request to determine which is the controlling order  must be accompanied by
a copy of every child support order in effect and the applicable record of payments.  The
requesting party shall give notice of the request to each party whose rights may be affected
by the determination.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1302-7__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The tribunal that issued the controlling order under Paragraph A, B, or C of this
Article has continuing jurisdiction to the extent provided in Article 1302.5 or 1302.6.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1302-7__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A tribunal of this state that determines by order which is the controlling order
under Subparagraph (B)</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1302-7__subsec_F__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1302-7__subsec_F__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>or Paragraph C of this Article, or that issues a new
controlling order under Subparagraph (B)</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1302-7__subsec_F__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Article, shall state in that order:</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1302-7__subsec_F__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The basis upon which the tribunal made its determination;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1302-7__subsec_F__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The amount of prospective support, if any; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1302-7__subsec_F__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The total amount of consolidated arrears and accrued interest, if any, under all
of the orders after all payments made are credited as provided by Article 1302.9.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1302-7__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Within thirty days after issuance of an order determining which is the controlling
order, the party obtaining the order shall file a certified copy of it in each tribunal that issued
or registered an earlier order of child support.  A party or support enforcement agency
obtaining the order that fails to file a certified copy is subject to appropriate sanctions by a
tribunal in which the issue of failure to file arises.  The failure to file does not affect the
validity or enforceability of the controlling order.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1302-7__subsec_H">
          <num>H.</num>
          <content>
            <p>An order that has been determined to be the controlling order, or a judgment for
consolidated arrears of support and interest, if any, made pursuant to this Article must be
recognized in proceedings under this Chapter.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=72805</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>