<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-14-15-1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-14-15-1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CA 14 15.1"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-14-15-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-14-15-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-14-15-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-14-15-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CA-14-15-1">
        <num>CA 14 15.1</num>
        <heading>1.  Fire and police civil service; municipalities of 13,000 to 250,000</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง15.1.  Fire and police civil service; municipalities of 13,000 to 250,000
1.  Applicability.  This Section applies to any municipality which operates a regularly
paid fire and police department and which has a population of not less than thirteen thousand
nor more than two hundred fifty thousand according to the latest regular federal census for
which the official figures have been made public.
2.  Short Title.  This Section shall be known and may be cited as &quot;The Municipal Fire
and Police Civil Service Law.&quot;
3.  Definitions.  The following words and phrases when used in this Section shall
have the following meaning, unless the context clearly requires otherwise:
a.  &quot;Allocation&quot; means the official determination of the class to which a position in
the classified service belongs.
b.  &quot;Appointing authority&quot; means any official, officer, board, commission, council,
or person having the power to make appointments to positions in the municipal fire and
police service.
c.  &quot;Appointment&quot; means the designation of a person, by due authority, to become an
employee in a position, and his induction into employment in the position.
d.  &quot;Board&quot; means the municipal fire and police civil service board.
e.  &quot;Class&quot; or &quot;class of position&quot; means a definitely recognized kind of employment
in the classified service, designated to embrace positions that are so nearly alike in the
essential character of their duties, responsibilities, and consequent qualification requirements,
that they can fairly and equitably be treated alike under like conditions for all personnel
purposes.
f.  &quot;Classification plan&quot; means all the classes of positions established for the
classified service.
g.  &quot;Classified service&quot; means every appointive office and position of trust or
employment in the municipal government which has as its primary duty one of the functions
specifically set forth to be included in the classified service by the provisions of this Section;
and excludes all elective and appointive offices and positions of trust or employment which
have a primary duty specifically set forth to be included in the unclassified service by the
provisions of this Section.
h.  &quot;Demotion&quot; means a change of an employee in the classified service from a
position of one class to a position of a lower class which generally affords less responsibility
and pay.
i.  &quot;Department service&quot; means employment in the public service offered and
performed separately by the fire and by the police departments of the municipality.
j.  &quot;Eligible&quot; means a person whose name is on the list.
k.  &quot;Employee&quot; means a person legally occupying a position.
l.  &quot;Employment list&quot; or &quot;lists&quot; means a reinstatement employment list, a promotional
employment list, a competitive employment list, and a reemployment list.
m.  &quot;Position&quot; means any office and employment in the municipal fire and police
services, the duties of which call for services to be rendered by one person.
n.  &quot;Promotion&quot; means a change of an employee in the classified service from a
position of one class to a position of a higher class which generally affords increased
responsibilities and pay.
o.  &quot;Promotion employment list&quot; or &quot;promotion list&quot; means an employment list
containing the names of eligible persons established from the results of promotion tests given
for a particular class of positions which is not specifically required by this Section to be
established from the results of a competitive test.
p.  &quot;Promotion test&quot; means a test for positions in a particular class which is not
specifically required by this Section to be filled by competitive tests, admission to which is
limited to regular employees of the next lower class, or the next lower classes when
authorized by the rules, in the classified service.
q.  &quot;Reemployment list&quot; means an employment list for the entrance or lowest ranking
class in the classified service, or in any group of classes as may have been grouped in the
classification plan, containing names of regular employees who have been laid off under the
&quot;lay off&quot; provisions of this Section.  This list shall not be applicable to persons who have
resigned or have been discharged.
r.  &quot;Regular employee&quot; or &quot;permanent employee&quot; means an employee who has been
appointed to a position in the classified service in accordance with this Section after
completing his working test period.
s.  &quot;Reinstatement employment list&quot; or &quot;reinstatement list&quot; means an employment list
containing names of persons eligible for reinstatement in positions of a class from which they
have been demoted for reasons other than disciplinary action.
t.  Repealed by</p>
        </content>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=67949</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>