<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-988"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-988"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 988"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-988/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-988/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-988/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-988/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-988">
        <num>CCRP 988</num>
        <heading>988.  Motion for fee exemption form to be used</heading>
        <content>
          <p>Art. 988.  Motion for fee exemption form to be used
&quot; STATE OF LOUISIANA
JUDICIAL DISTRICT FOR THE PARISH OF
______________________________
No.: ______________Division: &quot;_______&quot;
State of Louisiana
vs.
_______________________________________________________
CERTIFICATION OF FEE WAIVER
To be completed by defendant and submitted to the District Attorney's Office prior
to filing. Append completed form to Motion of Expungement at filing only if eligible.
DEFENDANT NAME
DATE OF BIRTH
SSN (last 4 digits)#
XXX-XX-
DATE OF ARREST
DOCKET NUMBER
CHARGE
In accordance with Louisiana Code of Criminal Procedure Article 983, the Office of
the District Attorney has reviewed the available databases and determined that (Check all that apply. To be completed by authorized personnel from the District
Attorney's Office and returned within 15 days to defendant.) :
□ The arrestee listed above has NO FELONY CONVICTIONS.
AND
□ The arrestee listed above has NO PENDING FELONY CHARGES UNDER
A BILL OF INDICTMENT OR INFORMATION.
AND
□ The arrestee listed above WAS ACQUITTED after trial of all charges derived
from the arrest listed above, including any lesser and included offense.
OR
□ The arrestee listed above WAS NOT PROSECUTED WITHIN THE TIME
LIMITATIONS prescribed in Chapter 1 of Title XVII of the Code of
Criminal Procedure and the arrestee did not participate in a pretrial diversion
program for the arrest listed above.
OR
□ The case involving the arrestee listed above was dismissed or the district
attorney declined to prosecute the case prior to the time limitations prescribed
in Chapter 1 of Title XVII of the Code of Criminal Procedure, and the
arrestee did not participate in a pretrial diversion program.
OR
□ The arrestee listed above has been determined to be factually innocent and
entitled to compensation for a wrongful conviction pursuant to the provisions
of R.S. 15:572.8.
OR
□ The arrestee listed above is a juvenile who has successfully completed any
juvenile drug court program and is exempt from fees pursuant to Code of
Criminal Procedure Article 983(G).
_____________________________________
District Attorney or his designee - Print Name
_______________________________________________________, 20____&quot;
District Attorney or his designee - SignatureDate</p>
        </content>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=919681</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>