<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-639"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-639"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 639"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-639/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-639/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-639/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-639/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-639">
        <num>CHC 639</num>
        <heading>639.  Notice of nature of proceedings; parental rights; form</heading>
        <content>
          <p>Art. 639.  Notice of nature of proceedings; parental rights; form
The following notice shall be served with a petition and summons on every parent
whose child is the subject of a child in need of care proceeding:
&quot;NOTICE
Louisiana law provides that the health, welfare, and safety of your child or children
are of paramount importance and you can lose some or all of your parental rights regarding
your children under certain circumstances.
The state has filed a petition that claims that your child is abused or neglected or is
otherwise in need of care and asks the court to hold a hearing to determine whether these
circumstances exist.  If the court rules that your child is being abused or neglected or is
otherwise in need of care, as defined by Louisiana law, your rights to have custody of your
child, to visit your child, or to make decisions affecting your child will be seriously affected. 
You may also become liable for paying the costs of your child's care if custody is awarded
to some other individual or to the state.  If your child cannot be safely returned home and the
court grants custody to some other suitable individual or to the state, a petition to terminate
your parental rights may be filed.
You have the right to hire an attorney and are encouraged to do so.  When you come
to court, if you cannot afford to hire an attorney, you may qualify to have the court appoint
one for you at state expense.
Whether or not you decide to hire an attorney, you have the right to attend all
hearings of your case and must attend as summoned, and the right to call witnesses on your
behalf, and to question those witnesses brought against you.&quot;</p>
        </content>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=73232</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>