<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-13-78"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-13-78"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="SRULE 13.78"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-13-78/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-13-78/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-13-78/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-13-78/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_SRULE-13-78">
        <num>SRULE 13.78</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-13-78__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>When a committee holds a public hearing on an instrument or other matter,
opportunity to appear before the committee shall be provided to a representative number
of proponents and opponents on each issue which the instrument or matter presents. The
author of an instrument on which a hearing is held, or his designee, or, if the hearing is
not on an instrument, the member offering the motion under discussion shall be entitled to
make opening and closing remarks.
B.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="SRULE-13-78__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Persons desiring to appear before a committee shall notify the committee
chairman or the committee secretary no later than the beginning of the meeting. However,
to assure that an opportunity is afforded all persons who desire to be heard, the chairman
shall inquire at the beginning of the hearing on each matter if there are additional persons
who wish to be heard. The chairman shall allot the time available for the hearing in an
equitable manner among those persons who are to be heard.
(2)</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="SRULE-13-78__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Each person appearing before a committee shall identify himself and the
group, organization, or company he represents, if any. Before being allowed to testify
before the committee, he shall also be required to file with the committee chairman or the
committee secretary a sworn written statement in the form of a signed witness card
swearing or affirming that his testimony is true and correct. He shall then be considered to
be under oath while providing such testimony before the committee.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="SRULE-13-78__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A public employee who is a designee of an elected official appearing before a
committee shall identify himself and the elected official for whom he is the designee.
Before being allowed to present testimony on behalf of an elected official, the designee
shall be required to file with the committee chairman a written statement from the elected
official evidencing the designation and a written certification from the designee that he is
acting in the performance of his official public duties. The written statement and
certification shall be made on forms promulgated by the Secretary of the Senate.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-13-78__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whenever a committee or the President finds it necessary or desirable to invite
or request the appearance before a committee of any person to present testimony, the
President shall have authority to invite or request such appearance and to determine and
approve the expenditure of funds available to the Senate to pay reasonable compensation
and expenses of such witnesses.
Amended by SR 78 of 2010 RS; SR 87 of 2016 RS.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=180447</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>