<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-3433"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-3433"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCP 3433"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-3433/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-3433/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-3433/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-3433/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCP-3433">
        <num>CCP 3433</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="CCP-3433__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>When it is not necessary in accordance with the provisions of Article 3431 to open
judicially a small succession, at least two persons, including the surviving spouse, if any, and
one or more legatees of the deceased, may execute one or more multiple originals of an
affidavit, duly sworn before any officer or person authorized to administer oaths in the place
where the affidavit is executed, setting forth all of the following:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-3433__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The date of death of the deceased, and his domicile at the time thereof.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-3433__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The fact that the deceased died testate.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-3433__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The marital status of the deceased, the location of the last residence of the
deceased, and the name of the surviving spouse, if any, and the surviving spouse's address,
domicile, and location of last residence, together with the names and last known addresses
of the heirs of the deceased, and identifying those of the heirs who are also forced heirs of
the deceased.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-3433__subsec_A__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The names and last known addresses of the legatees of the deceased, and the
statement that a legatee not signing the affidavit was given thirty days' notice by United
States mail of the affiants' intent to execute an affidavit for small succession and did not
object.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-3433__subsec_A__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A description of the property left by the deceased in Louisiana, including whether
the property is community or separate, and which, in the case of immovable property, shall
be sufficient to identify the property for purposes of transfer.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-3433__subsec_A__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A showing of the value of each item of property subject to the jurisdiction of the
courts of Louisiana, and the aggregate value of the property, at the time of the death of the
deceased.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-3433__subsec_A__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A statement describing the respective interests in the property that each legatee
has inherited and whether a usufruct of the surviving spouse attaches to the property.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-3433__subsec_A__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An attachment consisting of a copy of the testament and a certified copy of the
probate order of the court of another jurisdiction or the equivalent thereof.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-3433__subsec_A__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An affirmation that, by signing the affidavit, the affiant, if a legatee, has accepted
the legacy of the deceased.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-3433__subsec_A__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An affirmation that, by signing the affidavit, the affiants swear under penalty of
perjury that the information contained in the affidavit is true, correct, and complete to the
best of their knowledge, information, and belief.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-3433__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the deceased had no surviving spouse, the affidavit shall be signed by at least
two persons who have actual knowledge of the matters stated in the affidavit.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-3433__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition to the powers of a natural tutor or curator otherwise provided by law,
a natural tutor may also execute the affidavit on behalf of a minor child without the necessity
of filing a petition pursuant to Article 4061, and a curator may also execute the affidavit on
behalf of an interdict without the necessity of court authorization.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=111769</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>