<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-14-38-1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-14-38-1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CA 14 38.1"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-14-38-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-14-38-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-14-38-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-14-38-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CA-14-38-1">
        <num>CA 14 38.1</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="CA-14-38-1__subsec_15">
          <num>(15)</num>
          <content>
            <p>days before the date fixed for the hearing, in a newspaper published in the
Parish.  At the place and time specified in the notice, the Police Jury shall hear
all objections which may be interposed to the boundaries of the district and to
the inclusion of the property proposed to be included in the district, and after
disposing of all objections, the Police Jury shall, if it decides to create the
district, adopt a resolution fixing the boundaries of the district and giving it a
numerical designation and name.
(a-2).  To accomplish the purpose hereinafter enumerated in this Section
any Public Improvement District created as provided in this Section shall have
the power to incur obligations and to levy taxes upon only the land included
within such district under and in accordance with the authority of Chapter 4,
Title 39 of the Louisiana Revised Statutes of 1950 as amended.  Any other
provision to the contrary notwithstanding, such power to tax shall not extend
to oil, gas or other minerals or mineral rights or to any equipment used for the
exploration, production, storage, refining or transportation thereof, and all
rights to property acquired hereunder to which the mineral rights are reserved
to the state in paragraph d hereof shall be subordinate to the right of the state
to lease, explore and develop such property for oil, gas and other minerals. 
Such districts shall also have the right to contract for legal, financial,
engineering and other services which may be necessary or required to carry out
the provisions of this Section.
(a-3).  Public Improvement Districts hereafter created within the parish
of St. Charles having a frontage of land on Lake Pontchartrain within said
district, in addition to the powers now conferred on such districts by law, shall
have the power to construct and undertake reclamation projects as herein
provided, to locate, relocate, construct, maintain, extend and improve levees,
embankments, seawalls, jetties, brea</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CA-14-38-1__subsec_1">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any and all lands reclaimed or to be reclaimed, or otherwise
acquired by said Districts as part of said development, except such part of said
land as is required by the provisions hereof to be reserved and dedicated for
public parks, parkways, boulevards, playgrounds or places of amusement, or
beach purposes, together with all buildings or improvements made or
constructed, or to be made or constructed thereon, and all rights, ways,
privileges, servitudes or appurtenances, thereunto belonging, or in anywise
appertaining, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CA-14-38-1__subsec_2">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Cash, notes, or other evidences of indebtedness received, or to be
received, by said Districts in consideration for the sale or sales of any lands,
lots, and improvements forming part of said development; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CA-14-38-1__subsec_3">
          <num>(3)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any lease or leases and the rents, incomes and other advantages
arising out of any lease or leases, made or granted by said Districts in
connection with said development; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CA-14-38-1__subsec_4">
          <num>(4)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Generally any and all rights of said Districts and to any lands,
property, incomes, revenues, claims and other choses in action, forming part
of and arising out of said development.
Said Districts shall have the power and authority to sign, execute and
deliver any act or acts of mortgage and pledge containing all such terms,
conditions and stipulations, not inconsistent herewith, as they may deem
proper to secure any bonds, notes or other certificates of indebtedness issued,
or to be issued by it in pursuance hereof.  The said bonds, notes or certificates
of indebtedness shall be exempt from all taxation for state, parish and
municipal purposes, and savings banks and insurance companies shall be
authorized to invest funds in their hands therein and said bonds, notes and
certificates of indebtedness may be used for deposit with any officer, board,
municipality or other political subdivision of the State of Louisiana, in any
case in which any present or future laws deposit of security may be required. 
Said bonds, notes and certificates of indebtedness shall be deemed to be
negotiable instruments and incontestable in the hands of bona fide holders for
value; provided, however, nothing herein contained shall be construed as
pledging the credit of the State of Louisiana for the payment of said bonds,
notes or certificates of indebtedness, nor shall said bonds, notes or certificates
of indebtedness be construed as obligations of the State of Louisiana.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CA-14-38-1__subsec_4__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The power and authority hereby conferred shall be in addition to any
power to issue bonds, or other evidences of indebtedness and to borrow
money, now or hereafter conferred by law upon said Districts.  Anything
herein contained to the contrary notwithstanding, the aggregate principal
amount of all bonds, notes and certificates of indebtedness issued hereunder
at any time outstanding, together with the total maximum liability, whether or
not due, then unpaid, on all contracts for any work and material in connection
with the project herein authorized, shall never exceed the sum of Thirty
Million Dollars, and any contract made, or any bond, note or certificate of
indebtedness issued in violation of this provision shall be null and void.
For a period of sixty</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CA-14-38-1__subsec_60">
          <num>(60)</num>
          <content>
            <p>days from the date of publication of the
proceedings of the Board of Commissioners of any District hereunder,
authorizing the issuance of any bonds, notes or certificates of indebtedness,
any person in interest shall have the right to contest the legality of such
proceedings, the bonds, notes or certificates of indebtedness provided for, for
any cause; after which time no one shall have any cause or right of action to
contest the regularity, formality or legality of said proceedings or authorization
for any cause whatsoever.  If the validity of any proceedings or issue
authorized or provided for, held under the provisions of this Section, is not
raised within sixty</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CA-14-38-1__subsec_60">
          <num>(60)</num>
          <content>
            <p>days from the date of publication of the proceedings
taken in connection therewith, the legality thereof shall be conclusively
presumed, and no court shall have authority to inquire into such proceedings.
(j).  The provisions hereof are self-executing and the District is
authorized and empowered to carry same into effect, and no further legislation
shall be required to effect the same.
(Added by</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=67981</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>