<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-408"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-408"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 408"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-408/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-408/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-408/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-408/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-408">
        <num>CHC 408</num>
        <heading>408.  Duty of court to control proceedings; use of restraints on a child</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-408__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court shall require that the proceedings be conducted with dignity and
in an orderly and expeditious manner, and shall control the proceedings so that
justice is done.  The court may exclude any person whose conduct is disruptive if the
person fails promptly to heed the court's admonition to refrain from such conduct.
B.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-408__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Restraints shall not be used upon a child during any juvenile court
proceeding except in a delinquency proceeding as specifically provided in this
Paragraph.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-408__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A court may permit a child to be restrained in the courtroom only upon
the court's individualized determination that the use of restraints is necessary because
the child presents a particularized risk of physical harm to himself or another or
presents a particularized substantial risk of flight from the courtroom, and that there
are no less restrictive alternative measures to prevent flight or physical harm.  The
fact that the child is detained is insufficient to warrant a finding that the use of
restraints is necessary.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-408__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If it is alleged that the use of restraints upon a child is necessary, the
district attorney or law enforcement shall inform the judge and the attorney for the
child prior to the proceeding.  The attorney for the child shall be given an opportunity
to be heard and object on the record.  If the use of restraints is ordered, the judge shall
state on the record the reasons therefor.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-408__subsec_A__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In accordance with Paragraph A of this Article, a court may authorize the
use of restraints when the conduct of the child during a hearing presents an imminent
threat, risk of flight, or physical harm.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-408__subsec_A__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>This Paragraph does not apply when the child is in a detention center,
when the child is in transport from a detention center to the courthouse, or when the
child is held in the courthouse outside of the room where the juvenile delinquency
proceeding will occur.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=108416</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>