<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1154"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1154"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 1154"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1154/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1154/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1154/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1154/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-1154">
        <num>CHC 1154</num>
        <heading>1154.  Safe haven continued custody hearing; instanter order</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1154__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Immediately after notification that an infant has been relinquished, the department
shall request an oral instanter order of custody from the court in accordance with Article 620
and shall take physical custody of the infant within twelve hours of notice that the infant is
ready to be discharged from the hospital.  The department shall exercise due diligence in
attempting to identify and locate any nonrelinquishing parent, including but not limited to
performing a missing children search, which shall include contacting the Missing and
Exploited Children Information Clearinghouse, as defined in R.S. 46:1431, for information
on missing endangered adults and missing children to determine if the child has been
reported missing.
B.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1154__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A hearing shall be held by the court within three days after the infant's entry
into the custody of the department.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1154__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>No notice to a parent or other caretaker shall be required.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1154__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The court shall order the appointment of counsel for the child and may also
appoint a CASA volunteer for the child.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1154__subsec_A__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Hearsay evidence shall be admissible at this hearing.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1154__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>At this hearing, the department has the burden to prove all of the following:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1154__subsec_C__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>There are reasonable grounds to believe that the infant has been relinquished to
the state for adoption in accordance with this Chapter.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1154__subsec_C__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>There is no evidence that the infant was abused or neglected prior to his
relinquishment.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1154__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the court finds that the department has satisfied the requirements of Paragraph
C of this Article and that removal of the child is necessary in order to safeguard his welfare,
it shall order continued custody of the infant in the department prior to final entry of an order
declaring parental rights terminated and enter a finding that the department is deemed to have
made reasonable efforts to prevent or eliminate the need for removal and that reunification
efforts are not required.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1154__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the court determines that the infant was abused or neglected prior to its
relinquishment, the court shall direct that a child in need of care investigation be commenced
by the department in accordance with Title VI.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=180652</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>