<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-884-1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-884-1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 884.1"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-884-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-884-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-884-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-884-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-884-1">
        <num>CHC 884.1</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>When the child has admitted the allegations of the petition or when adjudicated
delinquent for any of the following offenses, the court shall provide him with written notice
of the requirements for registration as a sex offender:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Aggravated or first degree rape as defined in R.S. 14:42.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Forcible or second degree rape as defined in R.S. 14:42.1.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Second degree sexual battery as defined in R.S. 14:43.2.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_A__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Aggravated kidnapping of a child who has not attained the age of thirteen years
pursuant to either R.S. 14:44 or 44.2.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_A__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Second degree kidnapping of a child who has not attained the age of thirteen
years as defined in R.S. 14:44.1.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_A__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Aggravated crime against nature defined by R.S. 14:89.1(A)</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>involving
circumstances defined by R.S. 15:541 as an aggravated offense.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_A__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Aggravated crime against nature as defined in R.S. 14:89.1(A)(1).</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court shall use this form for the notice:
STATE IN THE INTEREST OF _________
_________ JUDICIAL DISTRICT COURT
DOCKET # __________                    PARISH OF _________________________
DIVISION  __________                    STATE OF LOUISIANA
Notification to Sex Offender in accordance with Children's Code Article 884.1, this Court
has the duty to provide _______________________ (name of juvenile) with the information
necessary for awareness of sex offender and child predator registration requirements. 
_______________________ (name of juvenile) has admitted the allegations of the petition
or has been adjudicated of a violation of R.S. ________.  Based on the provisions of Chapter
3-B of Title 15 of the Louisiana Revised Statutes of 1950 and the substance of the statute
violated, IT IS ORDERED that ___________________ shall register for the period of
___________ from the date of his release from confinement being placed on aftercare,
supervised release or probation, or from the date of his adjudication, if the disposition does
not involve a term of confinement.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>You shall initially register with the sheriff and chief of police, if any, of the parish
of the juvenile court in which you were adjudicated.  Additionally, you shall update your
registration, in person, every ninety days from the date of initial registration, with the sheriff
and chief of police, if any, of the parish of your residence and the parish where you attend
school or are employed.
Within three business days of establishing residence in Louisiana or if a current
resident, within three business days after adjudication if not immediately committed to
confinement or taken into custody, or within three business days after release from
confinement, you shall obtain and provide all of the following information to each sheriff or
police department (except in Orleans Parish where registration shall take place with the New
Orleans Police Department):</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Name and any aliases.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Physical address or addresses of residence.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Name and physical address of place of employment.  If you do not have a fixed
place of employment, you shall provide information with as much specificity as possible
regarding the places where you work, including but not limited to travel routes.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Name and physical address of the school in which you are a student.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Two forms of proof of residence for each residential address provided, including
but not limited to a driver's license, bill for utility service, and bill for telephone service.  If
those forms of proof are not available, you may provide an affidavit of an adult resident
living at the same address.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The offense for which you were adjudicated and the date and place of the
adjudication, and if known, the court in which the adjudication was obtained, the docket
number of the case, the specific statute violated, and the disposition imposed.  Note that this
information is all contained at the beginning of this form.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A current photograph, fingerprints, palm prints, and a DNA sample.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_h">
              <num>(h)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Your telephone numbers, including fixed location phone, mobile phone numbers,
or telephone number associated with any residence address.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_i">
              <num>(i)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A description of every vehicle registered to or operated by you, including license
plate number and a copy of your driver's license or identification card.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_j">
              <num>(j)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Your social security number and date of birth.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_k">
              <num>(k)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A description of your physical characteristics, including but not limited to sex,
race, hair color, eye color, height, age, weight, scars, tattoos, or other identifying marks.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_l">
              <num>(l)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Every e-mail address, online screen name, or other online identity you use or have
used to communicate on the Internet.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_m">
              <num>(m)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Temporary lodging information regarding any place where you plan to stay for
seven or more days and the length of the planned stay.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_n">
              <num>(n)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Travel and immigration documents, including but not limited to passports and
documents establishing immigration status.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If you are committed to the office of juvenile justice, you shall provide this
information to that office within ten days prior to release from confinement.  You shall still
appear in person at the sheriff's office within three business days of release from
confinement.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>During the declaration of an emergency if you enter an emergency shelter, you
shall, within the first twenty-four hours of admittance, notify the management of the shelter,
the chief of police of the municipality, and the sheriff of the parish in which the shelter is
located of your sex offender status.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_B__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>You have a duty to provide notice of change of address or other registration
information to the sheriff of the parish of residence within three business days.  If the new
or additional residence is located in a different parish, then you shall register with the sheriff
of the parish in which the new or additional residence is located.  You shall also send written
notice within three business days of re-registering in the new parish to the sheriff of the
parish of former registration.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_B__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If you provide recreational instruction to persons under the age of seventeen, you
shall post a notice in the building or facility where such instruction is being given.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_B__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Within ten days prior to release from confinement in a correctional facility, you
shall provide a photograph and other relevant information noted in this Article to the office
of juvenile justice for purposes of the State Sex Offender and Child Predator Registry.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_B__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If you change your place of residence or establish a new or additional residence,
you shall appear in person at the office of the sheriff of your parish of residence where you
are currently registered within three business days of the change to register the new address. 
If the new address is located in a different parish, then you shall also appear in person at the
office of the sheriff of your new parish of residence within the same time period.  If your
parish of residence is in Orleans Parish, then the registration shall take place at the New
Orleans Police Department and not with the Orleans Parish Sheriff's Office.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_B__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If you are absent from your current address of registration for more than thirty
consecutive days or an aggregate of thirty days or more in a calendar year, and are physically
present at another address during that same period of time, you shall register the new address
in person as one of your addresses of residence.  If the new address is in a parish different
from your current address, you shall also register in person with the sheriff of the new parish
within three business days of the tolling of the time periods listed.  This requirement
notwithstanding, you shall still notify the sheriff of one of your parishes of residence in
person if you are to take up temporary lodging for seven or more days.  It is only after the
thirty-day limit is exceeded that the new registration shall occur.  If your address of residence
is in Orleans Parish, this registration update shall take place at the New Orleans Police
Department and not with the Orleans Parish Sheriff's Office.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_B__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>You shall also appear in person at the office of the sheriff of any of your parishes
of residence when there is a change in your name, place of employment, or enrollment.  This
appearance shall occur within three business days of the change.  If your address of residence
is in Orleans Parish, this registration update shall take place at the New Orleans Police
Department and not with the Orleans Parish Sheriff's Office.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_B__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>You shall also timely sign and return the periodic address verification form sent
to you by the Louisiana Bureau of Criminal Identification and Information according to the
instructions on the verification form.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_B__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>You shall update your registration annually on the anniversary of the initial
registration by appearing in person at the office of each law enforcement agency with which
you are required to register and shall pay an annual registration fee of sixty dollars ($60.00).</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_B__subsec_12">
            <num>(12)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Failure to comply with any of these registration and notification requirements
is a felony for which you may be punished by a fine of up to one thousand dollars
($1,000.00) and imprisonment at hard labor for not less than two years nor more than ten
years without benefit of parole, probation, or suspension of sentence.  Upon a second or
subsequent conviction, you may be punished by a fine of up to three thousand dollars
($3,000.00) and imprisonment at hard labor for not less than five years, nor more than twenty
years without benefit of parole, probation, or suspension of sentence.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-884-1__subsec_B__subsec_13">
            <num>(13)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If you have been adjudicated of a sex offense as defined in R.S. 15:541
involving a victim who was under the age of thirteen at the time of the offense, you are
prohibited from residing or being present in certain locations.  A copy of this statute is
provided to you with this notification, if applicable.
THUS DONE AND SIGNED this ____ day of _____________, 20___ in open court,
in _____________, Louisiana.
______________________________________
Judge, _____ Juvenile Court
I hereby certify that the above requirements have been explained to me, that I have
received a copy of the above notice of sex offender registration and notification
requirements, and a copy of the statutes providing for such requirements.  I also understand
that I will be subject to any changes made by the legislature to the registration laws from this
day forward.
___________________________________________
Signature of Juvenile
____________________________________________
Defense Counsel Signature</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=725513</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>