<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-7-91"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-7-91"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CA 7 91"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-7-91/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-7-91/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-7-91/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-7-91/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CA-7-91">
        <num>CA 7 91</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="CA-7-91__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In all cases where the amount involved is less than twenty-five
dollars, the pleadings need not be in writing, but the court shall preserve a
record of the proceedings in the manner provided by law for trials before
justices of the peace.  The judges of the court shall assign one of their number
to try, during stated periods, such cases under rules and regulations adopted
and prescribed by the court.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CA-7-91__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Until otherwise provided by the Legislature, the allotment, re-allotment, and trial of cases, the rules of procedure, the taking of evidence, the
rendition and execution of judgments, the service of process, the execution of
writs, and the manner of taking appeals shall remain as now provided by law. 
Costs in the first city court shall be fixed and regulated by the judges in control
of the judicial expense fund for the parish of Orleans.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CA-7-91__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Appeals from the first city court in cases where the amount in
dispute or the fund to be distributed does not exceed one hundred dollars,
exclusive of interest, shall be taken to the civil district court for the parish of
Orleans, where they shall be tried de novo, as provided in Article VII, Section
81 of this Constitution.  Appeals in all other cases shall be taken to the court
of appeal for the fourth circuit.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CA-7-91__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The judges of the first city court have authority to celebrate
marriages, to issue the necessary licenses therefor, to execute commissions to
take testimony, and to receive the fees allowed by law therefor.
The present judges, clerk, and constable for the first city court shall be
retained in their respective offices until the expiration of their respective terms,
or until their successors have been elected and have qualified.
(Amended by</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=67998</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>