<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-646-1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-646-1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 646.1"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-646-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-646-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-646-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-646-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-646-1">
        <num>CHC 646.1</num>
        <heading>646.1.  Prehearing conference</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-646-1__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>On its own motion or on motion of counsel, the court may convene a prehearing
conference attended by the district attorney, the department, counsel for all parties,
unrepresented parties, and such other persons as the court deems proper.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-646-1__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The prehearing conference may be conducted either in person or by telephone to
consider any of the following:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-646-1__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The consideration of alternatives to formal court proceedings when their use is
appropriate and in the best interests of the child.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-646-1__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Efforts to identify and locate an absent parent, and suitable relatives or other
suitable individuals willing and able to offer a stable and safe home for the child.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-646-1__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Whether there is an issue of paternity requiring the issuance of an order for
immediate blood or tissue sampling in accordance with the provisions of R.S. 9:396 et seq.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-646-1__subsec_B__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The simplification of the issues including the elimination of frivolous claims or
defenses.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-646-1__subsec_B__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The necessity or desirability of amendments to the petition.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-646-1__subsec_B__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>What material facts and issues exist without substantial controversy, and what
material facts and issues are actually and in good faith controverted.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-646-1__subsec_B__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Proof, stipulations regarding the authenticity of documents, and advance rulings
from the court on the admissibility of the evidence.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-646-1__subsec_B__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Limitations or restrictions on, or regulation of, the use of expert testimony.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-646-1__subsec_B__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The control and scheduling of discovery.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-646-1__subsec_B__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The identification of witnesses, documents, and exhibits.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-646-1__subsec_B__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Such other matters as may aid in the disposition of the action.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-646-1__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court shall render an order which recites the action taken at the prehearing
conference, the amendments allowed to the petition, and the agreements made by the parties
as to any of the matters considered, and which limits the issues for adjudication to those not
disposed of by admissions or agreements of counsel.  Such order controls the subsequent
course of the action, unless modified at the adjudication hearing to prevent manifest
injustice.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-646-1__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If counsel for any party fails to obey a prehearing order, or to appear at the
prehearing and scheduling conference, or is substantially unprepared to participate in the
conference, or fails to participate in good faith, the court, upon its own motion or on the
motion of a party, after hearing, may make orders as are just, including orders provided in
Code of Civil Procedure Article 1471(A)(2), (3), and (4).  In lieu of or in addition to any
other sanction, the court may require the party or counsel for the party, or both, to pay the
reasonable expenses incurred by noncompliance with this Paragraph, including attorney fees.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=73240</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>