<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-1458"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-1458"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCP 1458"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-1458/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-1458/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-1458/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-1458/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCP-1458">
        <num>CCP 1458</num>
        <heading>1458.  Interrogatories to parties; procedures for use</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCP-1458__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each interrogatory shall be answered separately and fully in writing under oath,
unless it is objected to, in which event the reasons for objection shall be stated in lieu of an
answer.  The written answer or reasons for objection to each interrogatory shall immediately
follow a restatement of the interrogatory to which the answer or objection is responding.  The
answers are to be signed by the person making them.  When interrogatories are served on a
specific party, that party shall verify he has read and confirmed the answers and objections. 
The party upon whom the interrogatories have been served shall serve a copy of the answers,
and objections if any, within thirty days after the service of the interrogatories, except as set
forth in Paragraph B of this Article.  The court may allow a shorter or longer time.  The party
submitting the interrogatories may move for an order under Article 1469 with respect to any
objection to or other failure to answer an interrogatory.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-1458__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The delay for serving a copy of the answers to interrogatories in family law cases,
including divorce, custody, spousal and child support, community property, and matters
incidental to family law proceedings, shall be fifteen days after service of the discovery,
unless the interrogatories are served with an original petition, in which case the party who
has been served shall have thirty days from the date of service to serve a copy of the answers
to interrogatories.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=111231</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>