<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-893"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-893"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 893"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-893/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-893/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-893/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-893/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-893">
        <num>CCRP 893</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-893__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the sentence consists of both a fine and imprisonment, the court may impose
the fine and suspend the sentence or place the defendant on probation as to the imprisonment.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-893__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as otherwise provided by law, the court shall not suspend a felony
sentence after the defendant has begun to serve the sentence.
E.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-893__subsec_D__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon motion of the defendant, if the court finds at the conclusion of the
probationary period that the probation of the defendant has been satisfactory, the court may
set the conviction aside and dismiss the prosecution.  The dismissal of the prosecution shall
have the same effect as acquittal, except that the conviction may be considered as a first
offense and provide the basis for subsequent prosecution of the party as a habitual offender
except as provided in R.S. 15:529.1(C)(3). The conviction may be considered as a prior
offense for purposes of any other law or laws relating to cumulation of offenses.  Dismissal
under this Paragraph shall occur only twice with respect to any person.
(3)</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-893__subsec_D__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When a case is accepted into a drug court division probation program pursuant
to the provisions of R.S. 13:5304 and at the conclusion of the probationary period the court
finds that the defendant has successfully completed all conditions of probation, the court with
the concurrence of the district attorney may set aside the conviction and dismiss prosecution,
whether the defendant's sentence was suspended under Paragraph A of this Article or
deferred under Subparagraph</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-893__subsec_D__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Paragraph.  The dismissal of prosecution shall have
the same effect as an acquittal, except that the conviction may be considered as a first offense
and provide the basis for subsequent prosecution of the party as a habitual offender except
as provided in R.S. 15:529.1(C)(3).  The conviction may be considered as a prior offense for
purposes of any other law or laws relating to cumulation of offenses.</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-893__subsec_D__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The court may extend the provisions of this Paragraph to any person who has
previously successfully completed a drug court program and satisfactorily completed all
other conditions of probation.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-893__subsec_D__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Dismissal under this Paragraph shall have the same effect as an acquittal for
purposes of expungement under the provisions of Title XXXIV of this Code and may occur
only twice with respect to any person.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-893__subsec_D__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>When a defendant, who has been committed to the custody of the Department of
Public Safety and Corrections to serve a sentence in the intensive incarceration program
pursuant to the provisions of Article 895(B)(3), has successfully completed the intensive
incarceration program as well as successfully completed all other conditions of parole or
probation, and if the defendant is otherwise eligible, the court with the concurrence of the
district attorney may set aside the conviction and dismiss prosecution, whether the
defendant's sentence was suspended under Paragraph A of this Article or deferred under
Subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-893__subsec_D__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Paragraph.  The dismissal of prosecution shall have the same effect
as an acquittal, except that the conviction may be considered as a first offense and provide
the basis for subsequent prosecution of the party as a habitual offender except as provided
in R.S. 15:529.1(C)(3).  The conviction may be considered as a prior offense for purposes
of any other law or laws relating to cumulation of offenses.  Dismissal under this
Subparagraph shall have the same effect as an acquittal  for  purposes  of  expungement 
under  the provisions of  Title XXXIV of this Code and may occur only twice with respect
to any person.
F.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-893__subsec_D__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, when it appears
that the best interest of the public and of the defendant will be served, after the conviction
of a defendant considered suitable for a drug or specialty court program pursuant to Article
904, the court may suspend, in whole or in part, the imposition or execution of the sentence
when all of the following conditions are met:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-893__subsec_D__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The district attorney consents to the suspension of sentence.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-893__subsec_D__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>There is an available drug or specialty court program recognized by the Louisiana
Supreme Court.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-893__subsec_D__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The court orders the defendant to enter and complete any drug or specialty court
program recognized by the Louisiana Supreme Court.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-893__subsec_D__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the district attorney does not consent to the suspension of the sentence, the
district attorney shall file his objection with written reasons into the record.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-893__subsec_D__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the district attorney files an objection into the record, or if the court determines
that a specialty court program is not available for the defendant, the court may sentence the
defendant to any sentence provided for the offense by law.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-893__subsec_D__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>When suspension of sentence is allowed pursuant to this Paragraph, the defendant
may be placed on probation under the supervision of the division of probation and parole,
or under the supervision of a probation office, agency, or officer designated by the court. 
The period of probation shall be specified and shall not exceed three years, except as
provided in Paragraph H of this Article.  The suspended sentence shall be regarded as a
sentence for the purpose of granting or denying a motion for new trial or appeal.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-893__subsec_D__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon motion of the defendant, if the court finds at the conclusion of the
probationary period that the probation of the defendant has been satisfactory, the court may
set the conviction aside and dismiss the prosecution.  The dismissal of the prosecution shall
have the same effect as an acquittal, except that the conviction may be considered as a first
offense and provide the basis for a subsequent prosecution of the party as a habitual offender,
except as provided in R.S. 15:529.1(C)(3).  The conviction also may be considered as a prior
offense for purposes of any other provision of law relating to cumulation of offenses. 
Dismissal pursuant to this Paragraph shall occur only once with respect to any person.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-893__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nothing contained in this Section shall be construed as being a basis for
destruction of records of the arrest and prosecution of any person convicted of a felony.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-893__subsec_H">
          <num>H.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the court, with the consent of the district attorney, orders a defendant to enter
and complete a program provided by the drug division of the district court pursuant to R.S.
13:5301, an established driving while intoxicated court or sobriety court program, a mental
health court program established pursuant to R.S. 13:5351 et seq., a Veterans Court program
established pursuant to R.S. 13:5361 et seq., a reentry court established pursuant to R.S.
13:5401, or the Swift and Certain Probation Pilot Program established pursuant to R.S.
13:5371, the court may place the defendant on probation for a period of not more than eight
years if the court determines that successful completion of the program may require that
period of probation to exceed the five-year limit.  The period of probation as initially fixed
or as extended shall not exceed eight years.
I.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-893__subsec_H__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a defendant is placed on supervised probation, the division of probation and
parole shall submit to the court a compliance report when requested by the court, or when
the division of probation and parole considers it necessary to have the court make a
determination with respect to modification of terms or conditions of probation, termination
of probation, revocation of probation, or other purpose proper under any provision of law.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-893__subsec_H__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For purposes of this Paragraph:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-893__subsec_H__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;Compliance&quot; means the full completion of the terms and conditions of probation
as imposed by the sentencing judge.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-893__subsec_H__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;Compliance report&quot; means a report generated and signed by the division of
probation and parole that contains clear and concise information relating to the defendant's
performance and may contain a recommendation as to early termination.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-893__subsec_H__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>After a review of the compliance report, if it is the recommendation of the
division of probation and parole that the defendant is in compliance with the conditions of
probation, in accordance with the compliance report, the court may terminate probation at
such time as &quot;satisfactorily completed&quot;, absent a showing of cause for a denial.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-893__subsec_H__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of Article 897(A), the court may terminate
probation at any time as &quot;satisfactorily completed&quot; upon the final determination that the
defendant is in compliance with the terms and conditions of probation.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-893__subsec_H__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the court determines that the defendant has failed to successfully complete the
terms and conditions of probation, the court may extend the probation for a period not to
exceed two years for the purpose of allowing the defendant additional time to complete the
terms of probation, additional conditions, the extension of probation, or the revocation of
probation.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-893__subsec_H__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Absent extenuating circumstances, the court shall, within ten days of receipt of
the compliance report, make an initial determination as to the issues presented and shall
transmit the decision to the probation officer.  The court shall disseminate the decision to the
defendant, the division of probation and parole, and the prosecuting agency within ten days
of receipt.  The parties shall have ten days from receipt of the initial determination of the
court to seek an expedited contradictory hearing for the purpose of challenging the court's
determination.  If no challenge is made within ten days, the court's initial determination shall
become final and shall constitute a valid order of the court.
Amended by</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112882</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>