<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-791"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-791"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 791"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-791/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-791/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-791/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-791/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-791">
        <num>CCRP 791</num>
        <heading>791.  Sequestration of jurors and jury</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-791__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A jury is sequestered by being kept together in the charge of an officer of the
court so as to be secluded from outside communication, except as permitted by R.S.
18:1307.2.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-791__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In capital cases, after each juror is sworn he shall be sequestered, unless the state
and the defense have jointly moved that the jury not be sequestered.
C.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-791__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In noncapital cases, the jury shall be sequestered during active deliberations
and may be sequestered at any time upon order of the court.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-791__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>At any time after the court's charge, and after notice to the parties and affording
the parties an opportunity to be heard on the record outside the presence of the jury, the court
may declare the deliberations to be in recess and may then direct the jury to suspend its
deliberations, to separate without sequestration, and to return for continued deliberations on
the next day of operation of the court.  Before each recess, the court shall admonish the jury
as provided in Subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-791__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Paragraph and direct it to not resume its deliberations
until all twelve jurors have reassembled in the designated place at the termination of the
declared recess.
(3)</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-791__subsec_B__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Upon the court's charge to suspend deliberations and to separate without
sequestration, the court shall admonish the jury as follows:</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-791__subsec_B__subsec_3__subsec_i">
              <num>(i)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Deliberations shall be conducted only in the jury room when all jurors are present. 
All deliberations shall cease and shall not resume until all of the jurors have returned to the
jury room.
(ii)  During the recess, jurors shall not converse with any person about anything
related to the case.
(iii)  Jurors remain under obligation to not request, accept, agree to accept, or discuss
with any person regarding the receiving or accepting of any payment or benefit in return for
supplying information concerning the trial.
(iv)  Jurors shall promptly report directly to the court any incident within their
knowledge involving an attempt by any person to improperly influence any member of the
jury.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-791__subsec_B__subsec_3__subsec_v">
              <num>(v)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Jurors shall not visit or view the premises or place where the charged crime was
allegedly committed or any other premises or place involved in the case.
(vi)  Jurors shall not read, view, or listen to any accounts or discussions of the case
reported by newspapers, television, radio, the internet, or any other news media outlet.
(vii)  Jurors shall not attempt to research any fact, issue, or law related to the case,
whether by discussion with others, by research in a library or on the internet, or by any other
means or source.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-791__subsec_B__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Upon the jurors returning from any recess, the court shall verify with each juror
on the record that he followed the admonition.
Amended by</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112788</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>