<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-624"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-624"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 624"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-624/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-624/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-624/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-624/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-624">
        <num>CHC 624</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-624__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the court issues an order pursuant to Article 619 or 620, a hearing shall be held
by the court within three days after the issuance of the order.  An order setting the hearing
shall provide for appointment of counsel for the child and notice to the entity approved to
represent children.  If an instanter safety plan order has been ordered, a hearing shall be held
by the court within three days from the issuance of the safety plan order.  The parents'
signature on the safety plan shall constitute evidence of their agreement with the plan.  The
continued safety plan hearing shall be conducted in accordance with the procedural and
evidentiary rules applicable to continued custody hearings.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-624__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>After notice to all parties and when a child is in foster care, to any foster parent,
pre-adoptive parent, and relative providing care, and upon a showing of good cause, the court
may grant, deny, or condition a requested continuance of the proceeding in accordance with
the best interests of the child.  The hearing may be continued for up to three additional days. 
If a continuance is granted, the court shall issue a written order identifying the mover and
reciting the particular facts justifying the continuance.
C.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-624__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If it appears from the record that, after diligent efforts by the department, the
parent cannot be found or has been served a summons or notified by the department to appear
at the continued custody or continued safety plan hearing and fails to appear at the hearing,
then the hearing may be held in the parent's absence.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-624__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a foster parent, pre-adoptive parent, adoptive parent, or relative providing care
for the child fails to appear at the hearing, the department shall report to the court whether
notice was given, or, if not, what diligent efforts were made to locate and notify the absent
person.  The court may permit the hearing to be held in the person's absence.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-624__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>At the commencement of the hearing, on the record, the court shall ask each
person before the court whether he knows or has reason to know that the child is an Indian
child.  Each person before the court shall be instructed to inform the court if he subsequently
discovers information indicating that the child is an Indian child.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-624__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>At this hearing, the state has the burden of proving the existence of a ground for
continued custody or the continued implementation of a safety plan pursuant to Article 626.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-624__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The child and the child's parents may introduce evidence, call witnesses, be heard
on their own behalf, and cross-examine witnesses called by the state.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-624__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Hearsay evidence shall be admissible at this hearing.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-624__subsec_H">
          <num>H.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A suitable relative or other suitable individual who seeks to become the custodian
of the child shall provide evidence of a willingness and ability to provide a stable and safe
environment for the child and to protect the health, welfare, and safety of the child pending
an adjudication hearing.  The suitable relative or other suitable individual shall affirm a
continued acceptance of the terms of the safety plan.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=73217</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>