<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-1-3"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-1-3"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="SRULE 1.3"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-1-3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-1-3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-1-3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-1-3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_SRULE-1-3">
        <num>SRULE 1.3</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-1-3__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>No person shall be admitted on the Senate Floor while the Senate is in session
or for thirty minutes before the time fixed for the convening of each session or for thirty
minutes after adjournment of each session. However, members of the senate and the
Secretary, officers and employees of the senate or of senators, members of the House of
Representatives, the Clerk of the House, officers and employees of the House or of
members of the House, the Legislative Auditor, the Legislative Fiscal Officer, and the
employees of any of these shall be admitted to the floor. For the purposes of these rules,
the Senate Floor is defined as that area so designated in the diagram of the Senate
Chamber included at the end of this rule.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-1-3__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>No member of any news media shall conduct any formal interview with a
senator on the Senate Floor while the Senate is in session.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-1-3__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>One chair, permanently affixed to the floor at the desk of each senator, and no
other chairs shall be permitted in Section A of the floor of the  Senate, except for the six
chairs at the news media desks, and the chairs at the President's desk and the Secretary's
desk, the number to be determined by the President.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-1-3__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Special permission to enter those portions of the Senate Floor designated as
Sections B, C, and D, the Senate Library, the office of the Secretary, and that portion of
the floor behind the Secretary's desk may be granted by the President to visiting officials
of other states or of the United States or of foreign countries, or to other dignitaries.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-1-3__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>No person shall bring food or drink on the Senate Floor within the areas
designated as Sections A, B, C, and D on the diagram contained in the rule, of a kind or in
a manner which is disruptive of the decorum of the  senate, without special permission of
the President.
&lt;IMAGE&gt;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=180353</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>