<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-983"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-983"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 983"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-983/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-983/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-983/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-983/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-983">
        <num>CCRP 983</num>
        <heading>983.  Costs of expungement of a record; fees; collection; exemptions; disbursements</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-983__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as provided for in Articles 894 and 984, the total cost to obtain a court
order expunging a record shall not exceed five hundred fifty dollars.  Payment may be made
by United States postal money orders or money orders issued by any state or national bank
or by checks issued by a law firm or an attorney.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-983__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The nonrefundable processing fees for a court order expunging a record shall be
as follows:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-983__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Louisiana Bureau of Criminal Identification and Information may charge a
processing fee of two hundred fifty dollars for the expungement of any record of arrest when
ordered to do so by the court in compliance with the provisions of this Title.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-983__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The sheriff may charge a processing fee of fifty dollars for the expungement of
any record of arrest when ordered to do so by the court in compliance with the provisions of
this Title.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-983__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The district attorney may charge a processing fee of fifty dollars for the
expungement of any record of arrest when ordered to do so by the court in compliance with
the provisions of this Title.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-983__subsec_B__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The clerk of court may charge a processing fee not to exceed two hundred dollars
to cover the clerk's costs of the expungement.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-983__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The clerk of court shall collect all processing fees at the time the motion for
expungement is filed.
D.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-983__subsec_C__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The clerk shall immediately direct the collected processing fee provided for
in Subparagraph (B)</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-983__subsec_C__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Article to the Louisiana Bureau of Criminal Identification and
Information, and the processing fee amount shall be deposited immediately upon receipt into
the Criminal Identification and Information Dedicated Fund Account.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-983__subsec_C__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The clerk shall immediately direct the collected processing fees provided for in
Subparagraphs (B)</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-983__subsec_C__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-983__subsec_C__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Article to the sheriff and the district attorney, and the
processing fee amount shall be remitted immediately upon receipt in equal proportions to the
office of the district attorney and the sheriff's general fund.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-983__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The processing fees provided for by this Article are nonrefundable and shall not
be returned even if the court does not grant the motion for expungement.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-983__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>An applicant for the expungement of a record shall not be required to pay any fee
to the clerk of court, the Louisiana Bureau of Criminal Identification and Information,
sheriff, the district attorney, or any other agency to obtain or execute an order of a court of
competent jurisdiction to expunge the arrest from the individual's arrest record if a
certification obtained from the district attorney is presented to the clerk of court which
verifies that the applicant has no felony convictions and no pending felony charges under a
bill of information or indictment and at least one of the following applies:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-983__subsec_F__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The applicant was acquitted, after trial, of all charges derived from the arrest,
including any lesser and included offense.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-983__subsec_F__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The district attorney consents, and the case against the applicant was dismissed
or the district attorney declined to prosecute the case prior to the time limitations prescribed
in Chapter 1 of Title XVII of this Code, and the applicant did not participate in a pretrial
diversion program.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-983__subsec_F__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The applicant was arrested and was not prosecuted within the time limitations
prescribed in Chapter 1 of Title XVII of this Code and did not participate in a pretrial
diversion program.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-983__subsec_F__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Repealed by</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=919675</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>