<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-978"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-978"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 978"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-978/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-978/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-978/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-978/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-978">
        <num>CCRP 978</num>
        <heading>978.  Motion to expunge record of arrest and conviction of a felony offense</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-978__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as provided in Paragraph B of this Article, a person may file a motion to
expunge his record of arrest and conviction of a felony offense if any of the following apply:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-978__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The conviction was set aside and the prosecution was dismissed pursuant to
Article 893(E).</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-978__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>More than ten years have elapsed since the person completed any sentence,
deferred adjudication, or period of probation or parole based on the felony conviction, and
the person has not been convicted of any other criminal offense for a period of at least ten
years preceding the motion and has no criminal charge pending against him. The motion filed
pursuant to this Subparagraph shall include a certification obtained from the district attorney
which verifies that, to his knowledge, the applicant has no convictions during the ten-year
period immediately preceding the motion, and no pending charges under a bill of information
or indictment.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-978__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The person is entitled to a first offender pardon for the offense pursuant to Article
IV, Section 5(E)</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-978__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of the Constitution of Louisiana, provided that the offense is not defined
as a crime of violence pursuant to R.S. 14:2(B) or a sex offense pursuant to R.S. 15:541.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-978__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>No expungement shall be granted nor shall a person be permitted to file a motion
to expunge the record of arrest and conviction of a felony offense if the person was convicted
of the commission or attempted commission of any of the following offenses:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-978__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A crime of violence as defined by or enumerated in R.S. 14:2(B), unless
otherwise authorized in Paragraph E of this Article.
(2)</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-978__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Notwithstanding any provision of Article 893, a sex offense or a criminal
offense against a victim who is a minor as each term is defined by R.S. 15:541, or any
offense which occurred prior to June 18, 1992, that would be defined as a sex offense or a
criminal offense against a victim who is a minor had it occurred on or after June 18, 1992.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-978__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any person who was convicted of carnal knowledge of a juvenile (R.S. 14:80)
prior to August 15, 2001, is eligible for an expungement pursuant to the provisions of this
Title if the offense for which the offender was convicted would be defined as misdemeanor
carnal knowledge of a juvenile (R.S. 14:80.1) had the offender been convicted on or after
August 15, 2001.  The burden is on the mover to establish that the elements of the offense
of conviction are equivalent to the current definition of misdemeanor carnal knowledge of
a juvenile as defined by R.S. 14:80.1.  A copy of the order waiving the sex offender
registration and notification requirements issued pursuant to the provisions of R.S. 15:542(F)
shall be sufficient to meet this burden.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-978__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A violation of the Uniform Controlled Dangerous Substances Law, except for any
of the following which may be expunged pursuant to the provisions of this Title:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-978__subsec_B__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A conviction for possession of a controlled dangerous substance as provided for
in R.S. 40:966(C), 967(C), 968(C), or 969(C), or 970(C).</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-978__subsec_B__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A conviction for possession of a controlled dangerous substance with the intent
to distribute.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-978__subsec_B__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A conviction for a violation of the Uniform Controlled Dangerous Substances
Law which is punishable by a term of imprisonment of not more than five years.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-978__subsec_B__subsec_3__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A conviction for a violation of the Uniform Controlled Dangerous Substances
Law which may be expunged pursuant to Article 893(E).</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-978__subsec_B__subsec_3__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A conviction for a violation of the Uniform Controlled Dangerous Substances
Law for which the person is entitled to a first offender pardon pursuant to Article IV, Section
5(E)</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-978__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of the Constitution of Louisiana.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-978__subsec_B__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The conviction was for domestic abuse battery.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-978__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The motion to expunge a record of arrest and conviction of a felony offense shall
be served pursuant to the provisions of Article 979.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-978__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Repealed by</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=919670</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>