<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-4873"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-4873"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCP 4873"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-4873/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-4873/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-4873/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-4873/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCP-4873">
        <num>CCP 4873</num>
        <heading>4873.  Transfer to district court; procedure; contest; effect</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCP-4873__subsec_1">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Within the delay allowed for answer in the trial court of the limited jurisdiction,
or within ten days after answer has been filed, the party shall file a motion to transfer with
the clerk of the court in which the suit is pending.  The motion shall include a declaration
that the matter is one to which the defendant would have been entitled to a trial by jury if
commenced in district court, and that the defendant desires a trial by jury.  If a party fails to
file a motion to transfer within the delays required by this Subparagraph, the matter shall not
be transferred.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-4873__subsec_2">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A plaintiff may oppose the transfer of the action to a district court only if the
plaintiff stipulates that the action does not exceed ten thousand dollars exclusive of interest
and costs.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-4873__subsec_3">
          <num>(3)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If no opposition is filed within ten days after the filing of the motion to transfer,
the judge of the court in which the suit is pending shall order the transfer to the district court. 
If an opposition is timely filed, it shall be tried summarily.
(4)</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-4873__subsec_3__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Where a transfer is ordered, the clerk of the court in which the action was
initially filed shall forward to the clerk of the court to which the action is transferred a
certified copy of the record in the initial court, including pleadings, minute entries, and all
other proceedings.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-4873__subsec_3__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The clerk of the district court shall file the action as a new proceeding in that
court, upon payment by the defendant of a filing fee as provided by rule of the district court. 
All costs accruing thereafter, however, shall be advanced in the same manner as though the
action had initially been commenced in the district court by the original plaintiff.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-4873__subsec_5">
          <num>(5)</num>
          <content>
            <p>When the matter is docketed by the clerk of the district court, the proceeding
shall continue in that court as though originally commenced therein.  In the event that
transfer is effected prior to answer, the defendant shall file the answer in the district court
within the delays provided by Article 1001, commencing from the date on which the
transferred proceeding is filed in that court.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-4873__subsec_6">
          <num>(6)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The disposition of a motion to transfer and any opposition thereto shall not be
appealable but shall be reviewable through the exercise of its supervisory jurisdiction by the
court of appeal having appellate jurisdiction over the case.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112107</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>