<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1405"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1405"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 1405"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1405/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1405/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1405/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1405/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-1405">
        <num>CHC 1405</num>
        <heading>1405.  Mental Health Advocacy Service (MHAS); representation; fees</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1405__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>MHAS shall provide legal counsel to all patients who request such service and who are admitted for treatment pursuant to this Title, including but not limited to voluntary or involuntary admission, commitment, legal competency, change of status, transfer, and discharge.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1405__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>MHAS shall provide legal counsel, as availability is determined by its executive director, to minors admitted for mental health or substance abuse treatment pursuant to the dispositional alternatives as provided in the other Titles of this Code, including but not limited to Titles VI and VIII.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1405__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nothing in this Title shall be construed to prohibit a person with mental illness or respondent from being represented by privately retained counsel.  If a MHAS attorney has been appointed by the court and the minor with mental illness or respondent secures his own counsel, the court shall discharge the MHAS attorney.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1405__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>MHAS shall establish official rules and regulations for evaluating a client's financial resources, for the purpose of determining whether a client has the ability to pay for services received.  A client found to have sufficient financial resources shall be required to pay in accordance with standards established by the executive director.  An indigent client shall be provided legal counsel and representation without charge.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1405__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>MHAS shall be empowered with all of the same rights and responsibilities to represent their clients whether appointed through the provisions of this Code or Title 28 of the Louisiana Revised Statutes of 1950.  These rights include but are not limited to:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1405__subsec_E__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A request for a judicial hearing pursuant to Article 1411.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1405__subsec_E__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An independent medical examination as requested and approved by the MHAS executive director.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=72901</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>