<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-966"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-966"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCP 966"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-966/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-966/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-966/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-966/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCP-966">
        <num>CCP 966</num>
        <heading>966.  Motion for summary judgment; procedure</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCP-966__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Unless extended by the court and agreed to by all of the parties, a motion for
summary judgment shall be filed, opposed, or replied to in accordance with the following
provisions:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-966__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except for any document provided for under Subsubparagraph (A)(4)</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CCP-966__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this
Article, a motion for summary judgment and all documents in support of the motion shall be
filed and served on all parties in accordance with Article 1313(A)</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-966__subsec_B__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>not less than sixty-five
days prior to the trial.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-966__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except for any document provided for under Subsubparagraph (A)(4)</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CCP-966__subsec_B__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this
Article, any opposition to the motion and all documents in support of the opposition shall be
filed and served in accordance with Article 1313(A)</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-966__subsec_B__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>not less than fifteen days prior to the
hearing on the motion.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-966__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any reply memorandum shall be filed and served in accordance with Article
1313(A)</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-966__subsec_B__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>not less than five days inclusive of legal holidays notwithstanding Article
5059(B)</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-966__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>prior to the hearing on the motion.  No additional documents may be filed with
the reply memorandum.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-966__subsec_B__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the deadline for filing and serving a motion, an opposition, or a reply
memorandum falls on a legal holiday, the motion, opposition, or reply is timely if it is filed
and served no later than the next day that is not a legal holiday.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-966__subsec_B__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The court shall not reconsider or revise the granting of a motion for partial
summary judgment on motion of a party who failed to meet the deadlines imposed by this
Paragraph, nor shall the court consider any documents filed after those deadlines.
C.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-966__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Unless otherwise agreed to by all of the parties and the court:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CCP-966__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A contradictory hearing on the motion for summary judgment shall be set not less
than thirty days after the filing and not less than thirty days prior to the trial date.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCP-966__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Notice of the hearing date shall be served on all parties in accordance with Article
1313(C) or 1314 not less than thirty days prior to the hearing.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-966__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For good cause shown, the court may order a continuance of the hearing.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-966__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The court shall render a judgment on the motion not less than twenty days prior
to the trial.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-966__subsec_B__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In all cases, the court shall state on the record or in writing the reasons for
granting or denying the motion.  If an appealable judgment is rendered, a party may request
written reasons for judgment as provided in Article 1917.
D.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-966__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The burden of proof rests with the mover.  Nevertheless, if the mover will not
bear the burden of proof at trial on the issue that is before the court on the motion for
summary judgment, the mover's burden on the motion does not require him to negate all
essential elements of the adverse party's claim, action, or defense, but rather to point out to
the court the absence of factual support for one or more elements essential to the adverse
party's claim, action, or defense.  The burden is on the adverse party to produce factual
support sufficient to establish the existence of a genuine issue of material fact or that the
mover is not entitled to judgment as a matter of law.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-966__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The court shall consider only those documents filed or referenced in support of
or in opposition to the motion for summary judgment but shall not consider any document
that is excluded pursuant to a timely filed objection.  Any objection to a document shall be
raised in a timely filed opposition or reply memorandum.  The court shall consider all
objections prior to rendering judgment.  The court shall specifically state on the record or in
writing whether the court sustains or overrules the objections raised.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-966__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a timely objection is made to an expert's qualifications or methodologies in
support of or in opposition to a motion for summary judgment, any motion in accordance
with Article 1425(F) to determine whether the expert is qualified or the expert's
methodologies are reliable shall be filed, heard, and decided prior to the hearing on the
motion for summary judgment.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-966__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A summary judgment may be rendered dispositive of a particular issue, theory of
recovery, cause of action, or defense, in favor of one or more parties, even though the
granting of the summary judgment does not dispose of the entire case as to that party or
parties.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-966__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A summary judgment may be rendered or affirmed only as to those issues set forth
in the motion under consideration by the court at that time.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-966__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>When the court renders judgment in accordance with the provisions of this Article
that a party or nonparty is not negligent, is not at fault, or did not cause in whole or in part
the injury or harm alleged, that party or nonparty shall not be considered in any subsequent
allocation of fault.  Evidence shall not be admitted at trial to establish the fault of that party
or nonparty, except that evidence may be admitted to establish the fault of a principal when
the party or nonparty acted pursuant to a mandate or procuration.  During the course of the
trial, no party or person shall refer directly or indirectly to any such fault, nor shall that party
or nonparty's fault be submitted to the jury or included on the jury verdict form except where
evidence is admitted of the acts of the party or nonparty for purposes of establishing the fault
of the party or nonparty's principal.  This Paragraph does not apply if the trial or appellate
court's judgment rendered in accordance with this Article is reversed.  If the judgment is
reversed by an appellate court, the reversal is applicable to all parties.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-966__subsec_H">
          <num>H.</num>
          <content>
            <p>On review, an appellate court shall not reverse a trial court's denial of a motion
for summary judgment and grant a summary judgment dismissing a case or a party without
assigning the case for briefing and permitting the parties an opportunity to request oral
argument.
Amended by</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112309</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>