<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-815-1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-815-1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 815.1"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-815-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-815-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-815-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-815-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-815-1">
        <num>CHC 815.1</num>
        <heading>815.1.  Alternative to detention programs</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-815-1__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each judicial district or parish may develop a program or programs to serve as
alternatives to secure detention of a child.  Such program shall be used only for a child taken
into custody for the commission of a delinquent act who is not released pursuant to Article
814.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-815-1__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>An alternative to detention program may be operated either by a nonprofit or
government entity.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-815-1__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>There shall be no fees associated with participation in an alternative to detention
program.  Funding may be provided by any source, including through a contract with the
office of juvenile justice.  Any program funded by the office of juvenile justice shall comply
with any requirements established by the office of juvenile justice for the purpose of
receiving and retaining such funding.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-815-1__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>An alternative to detention program shall be considered a form of detention and
the time periods set forth in Articles 854 and 877 shall apply unless waived by the child.  No
child shall remain enrolled in an alternative to detention program following a disposition
hearing, except as an alternative to placement in detention or other out-of-home placement.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-815-1__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>An alternative to detention program is intended to serve the same limited purpose
as secure detention as set forth in R.S. 15:1110.  The child's participation in an alternative
to detention program shall not be considered an adjudication nor shall it suspend delinquency
proceedings.  An alternative to detention program may include rehabilitative components,
but continued participation in the program shall not be required post-adjudication, except as
an alternative to detention of the child or other out-of-home placement.  Placement of a child
in an alternative to detention program does not preclude the child from being referred to
treatment programs that are not required as a condition of the child's release from detention.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=1147220</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>