<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-3601"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-3601"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCP 3601"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-3601/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-3601/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-3601/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-3601/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCP-3601">
        <num>CCP 3601</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="CCP-3601__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>An injunction shall be issued in cases where irreparable injury, loss, or damage
may otherwise result to the applicant, or in other cases specifically provided by law;
provided, however, that no court shall have jurisdiction to issue, or cause to be issued, any
temporary restraining order, preliminary injunction, or permanent injunction against any state
department, board, or agency, or any officer, administrator, or head thereof, or any officer
of the state of Louisiana in any suit involving the expenditure of public funds under any
statute or law of this state to compel the expenditure of state funds when the director of such
department, board, or agency or the governor shall certify that the expenditure of such funds
would have the effect of creating a deficit in the funds of said agency or be in violation of
the requirements placed upon the expenditure of such funds by the legislature.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-3601__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>No court shall issue a temporary restraining order in cases where the issuance
shall stay or enjoin the enforcement of a child support order when the Department of
Children and Family Services is providing services, except for good cause shown by written
reasons made a part of the record.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-3601__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>During the pendency of an action for an injunction the court may issue a
temporary restraining order, a preliminary injunction, or both, except in cases where
prohibited, in accordance with the provisions of this Chapter.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-3601__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as otherwise provided by law, an application for injunctive relief shall be
by petition.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-3601__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The irreparable injury, loss, or damage enumerated in Paragraph A of this Article
may result from:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-3601__subsec_E__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The isolation of an individual over the age of eighteen years by any other
individual, curator, or mandatary, including but not limited to violations of Article 4566 (J)
or Civil Code Article 2995.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-3601__subsec_E__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person being denied the use or enjoyment of immovable property in which the
person has an ownership, possessory, or lease interest by a person who does not have a legal
interest in the property.
F.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-3601__subsec_E__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of Article 3610, security shall not be required
for a temporary restraining order or preliminary injunction seeking removal of a person from
immovable property in which the person does not have a legal interest.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-3601__subsec_E__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Nothing in this Section shall prohibit a petitioner from pursuing any other remedy
provided by law.
Amended by</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=111802</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>