<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1131"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1131"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 1131"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1131/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1131/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1131/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1131/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-1131">
        <num>CHC 1131</num>
        <heading>1131.  Filing of surrender; institution of records check</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1131__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Within three days after the surrender becomes irrevocable under Article 1123,
exclusive of legal holidays, the agency or attorney for the prospective adoptive parents shall
file the authentic act of voluntary surrender, together with a preliminary estimate and
accounting of fees and charges in accordance with Article 1201 or 1223.1 and any
certification for adoption or court order approving the adoptive placement required by
Chapter 2 of Title XII in a court of proper venue as authorized by Article 1180.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1131__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the parent has previously executed an intent to surrender for adoption, pursuant
to Chapter 2-A of this Title, the surrender shall be filed in that same court.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1131__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The surrender, and certification for adoption or court order approving the adoptive
placement if required, may be filed later than three days after execution only with leave of
court for good cause shown.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1131__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon filing, the court shall promptly review the surrender and any accompanying
documents to ensure their sufficiency in accordance with Article 1104.  If any document fails
to comply with the requirements of this Title, the court shall immediately notify all counsel
of record and may refuse to accept the surrender until such time as the defects are remedied. 
If the surrender and documents are found to comply with the requirements of this Title, the
court shall enter an order approving the surrender and immediately notify all counsel of
record.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1131__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon the filing of any court order approving the adoptive placement pursuant to
Article 1178, the court shall immediately issue both of the following orders:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1131__subsec_E__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>That the sheriff or the office of state police, Louisiana Bureau of Criminal
Identification and Information, conduct a records check for all federal arrests and convictions
and all state arrests and convictions in this and any other states in which either of the
prospective adoptive parents has been domiciled.  Prospective adoptive parents shall submit
a set of fingerprints to the sheriff or the office of state police.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1131__subsec_E__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>That the department conduct a records check for validated complaints of child
abuse or neglect in this or any other state in which either of the prospective adoptive parents
has been domiciled since becoming a major, involving either prospective adoptive parent.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1131__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each order shall state the full name, date of birth, social security number, and
former and current state of domicile since becoming a major of each prospective adoptive
parent.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1131__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The sheriff or the office of state police, Louisiana Bureau of Criminal
Identification and Information, and the department shall accord priority to these orders and
shall provide a certificate indicating all information discovered or that no information has
been found.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1131__subsec_H">
          <num>H.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Failure to file within three days as required by Paragraph A of this Article shall
not affect the final adoption.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=72618</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>