<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1404"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1404"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 1404"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1404/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1404/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1404/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1404/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-1404">
        <num>CHC 1404</num>
        <heading>1404.  Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1404__subsec_1">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Caretaker&quot; means any person legally obligated to provide or secure adequate
care for a child, including a parent, tutor, guardian, legal custodian, foster home parent, or
other person providing a residence for the child.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1404__subsec_2">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Conditional discharge&quot; means the physical release of a judicially committed
minor from a treatment facility by the director or by the court.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1404__subsec_3">
          <num>(3)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Dangerous to others&quot; means the condition of a person whose behavior or
significant threats support a reasonable expectation that there is a substantial risk that he will
inflict physical harm upon another person in the near future.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1404__subsec_4">
          <num>(4)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Dangerous to self&quot; means the condition of a person whose behavior, significant
threats, or inaction supports a reasonable expectation that there is a substantial risk that he
will inflict physical or severe emotional harm upon his own person.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1404__subsec_5">
          <num>(5)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Department&quot; means the Louisiana Department of Health.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1404__subsec_6">
          <num>(6)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Diagnosis&quot; means the art and science of determining the presence of disease in
an individual and distinguishing one disease from another.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1404__subsec_7">
          <num>(7)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Director&quot; or &quot;superintendent&quot; means a person in charge of a treatment facility
or his deputy.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1404__subsec_8">
          <num>(8)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Discharge&quot; means the full or conditional release from a treatment facility of any
minor admitted or otherwise detained under this Title.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1404__subsec_9">
          <num>(9)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Family psychiatric mental health nurse practitioner&quot; means an individual who
maintains the credentials as such and meets the requirements of a &quot;psychiatric mental health
nurse practitioner&quot; as provided in R.S. 28:2.  Further, a family psychiatric mental health
nurse practitioner shall have been engaged in clinical practice for not less than three years.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1404__subsec_10">
          <num>(10)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Formal voluntary admission&quot; means the admission of a minor suffering from
mental illness or substance abuse desiring admission to a treatment facility for diagnosis or
treatment of such condition, or both, who may be formally admitted upon his written request.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1404__subsec_11">
          <num>(11)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Grave disability&quot; means the condition of a person who is unable to provide for
his own basic physical needs, such as essential food, clothing, medical care, and shelter, as
a result of serious mental illness or substance abuse and is unable to survive safely in
freedom or protect himself from serious harm; the term also includes incapacitation by
alcohol, which means the condition of a person who, as a result of the use of alcohol, is
unconscious or whose judgment is otherwise so impaired that he is incapable of realizing and
making a rational decision with respect to his need for treatment.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1404__subsec_12">
          <num>(12)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Informal voluntary admission&quot; means the admission of a minor suffering from
mental illness or substance abuse, desiring admission to a treatment facility for diagnosis or
treatment of such condition, or both, who may be admitted upon his request without making
formal application.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1404__subsec_13">
          <num>(13)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;MHAS&quot; means Mental Health Advocacy Service, as established by R.S. 28:64
and Article 1405.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1404__subsec_14">
          <num>(14)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Major surgical procedure&quot; means an invasive procedure of a serious nature
with incision upon the body or parts thereof under general, local, or spinal anesthesia,
utilizing surgical instruments, for the purpose of diagnosis or treatment of a medical
condition.  Diagnostic procedures, including but not limited to the following, shall not be
considered as major surgical procedures:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1404__subsec_14__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Endoscopy through natural body openings, such as the mouth, anus, or urethra,
to view the trachea, bronchi, esophagus, stomach, pancreas, small or large intestine, urethra,
urinary bladder, or ureters, and to obtain from such organs specimens of fluids or tissues for
chemical or microscopic analysis.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1404__subsec_14__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Subcutaneous percutaneous liver biopsy.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1404__subsec_14__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Punch biopsy of skeletal muscles.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1404__subsec_14__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Bone marrow biopsy.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1404__subsec_14__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Lumbar puncture.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1404__subsec_14__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Myelogram.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1404__subsec_14__subsec_g">
            <num>(g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Abdominocentesis.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1404__subsec_14__subsec_h">
            <num>(h)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Conization of the uterine cervix.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1404__subsec_14__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Renal angiography.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1404__subsec_14__subsec_j">
            <num>(j)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Femoral angiography.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1404__subsec_14__subsec_k">
            <num>(k)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Carotid angiography.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1404__subsec_14__subsec_l">
            <num>(l)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Vertebral angiography.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1404__subsec_15">
          <num>(15)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Mental Health Advocacy Service&quot; means a service established by the state of
Louisiana for the purpose of providing legal counsel and representation for persons with
mental disabilities and for children and to ensure that their legal rights are protected.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1404__subsec_16">
          <num>(16)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Patient&quot; means any person detained and taken care of as a person with mental
illness or person suffering from substance abuse.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1404__subsec_17">
          <num>(17)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Person with mental illness&quot; means any person with a psychiatric disorder which
has substantial adverse effects on his ability to function and who requires care and treatment. 
It does not include a person with, solely, an intellectual disability, or who suffers solely from
epilepsy, alcoholism, or drug abuse.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1404__subsec_18">
          <num>(18)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Psychologist&quot; means an individual licensed to practice psychology in Louisiana
in accordance with R.S. 37:2351 et seq., or licensed to practice medical psychology in
Louisiana in accordance with R.S. 37:1360.51 et seq., and who has been engaged in the
practice of a clinical specialty for not less than three years.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1404__subsec_19">
          <num>(19)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Respondent&quot; means a person alleged to be mentally ill or suffering from
substance abuse and for whom an application for commitment to a treatment facility has been
filed.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1404__subsec_20">
          <num>(20)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Restraint&quot; means the partial or total immobilization of any or all of the
extremities or the torso by mechanical means for psychiatric indications.  Restraint does not
include the use of mechanisms usually and customarily used during medical or surgical
procedures, including but not limited to body immobilization during surgery and arm
immobilization during intravenous administration.  Restraint does not include orthopedic
appliances used to posturally support the patient, such as posies.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1404__subsec_21">
          <num>(21)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Seclusion&quot; means the involuntary confinement of a patient alone in a room,
which the patient is physically prevented from leaving, for any period of time, except that
seclusion does not include the placement of a patient alone in a room or other area for no
more than thirty minutes at a time and no more than three hours in any twenty-four hour time
period pursuant to behavior-shaping techniques such as &quot;time-out&quot;.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1404__subsec_22">
          <num>(22)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Substance abuse&quot; means the condition of a person who uses narcotic, stimulant,
depressant, soporific, tranquilizing, or hallucinogenic drugs or alcohol to the extent that it
renders the person dangerous to himself or others or renders the person gravely disabled.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1404__subsec_23">
          <num>(23)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Treatment&quot; means an active effort to accomplish an improvement in the mental
condition or behavior of a patient or to prevent deterioration in his condition or behavior. 
Treatment includes but is not limited to hospitalization, partial hospitalization, outpatient
services, examination, diagnosis, training, the use of pharmaceutical, and other services
provided for patients by a treatment facility.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1404__subsec_24">
          <num>(24)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Treatment facility&quot; means any public or private hospital, retreat, institution,
mental health center, or facility licensed by the state of Louisiana in which any mentally ill
minor or minor suffering from substance abuse is received or detained as a patient except a
facility under the control or supervision of the Department of Public Safety and Corrections
unless otherwise provided in Title VIII of this Code.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=72900</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>