<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-306"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-306"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 306"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-306/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-306/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-306/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-306/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-306">
        <num>CHC 306</num>
        <heading>306.  Places of detention; juveniles subject to criminal court jurisdiction</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-306__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Prior to the divesting events specified in Paragraphs A and B of Article 305, the
child shall be held in custody in a juvenile detention center, except as hereinafter provided.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-306__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a detention facility for juveniles is not available, the child may be held in an
adult jail or lockup for identification or processing procedures or while awaiting
transportation only as long as necessary to complete these activities for up to six hours,
except that in nonmetropolitan areas, the child may be held for up to forty-eight hours if all
of the following occur:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-306__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The child meets the age and offense criteria set out in Article 305.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-306__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A continued custody hearing in accordance with Articles 820 and 821 is held
within forty-eight hours after his arrest.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-306__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>There is no acceptable alternative placement to the jail or lockup in which he is
being held.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-306__subsec_B__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The sheriff or the administrator of the adult jail or lockup has certified to the
court that facilities exist providing for sight and sound separation of the juvenile from adult
offenders and that he can be given continuous visual supervision while placed in the jail or
lockup.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-306__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If an indictment has not been returned, a bill of information filed, or a continued
custody hearing not held within forty-eight hours, the child held in an adult jail or lockup in
a nonmetropolitan area shall be released or removed to a juvenile detention facility.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-306__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If at the conclusion of the continued custody hearing, the court determines that
the child meets the age requirements and that there is probable cause that the child has
committed one of the offenses enumerated in Article 305, the court shall order him held for
trial as an adult for the appropriate court of criminal jurisdiction.  The appropriate court of
criminal jurisdiction may thereafter order that the child be held in any facility used for the
pretrial detention of accused adults and the child shall apply to the appropriate court of
criminal jurisdiction for a preliminary hearing, bail, and for any other rights to which he may
be entitled under the Code of Criminal Procedure.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-306__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If for any reason the court determines that the child is not subject to the
jurisdiction of the criminal courts, it may continue him in custody only in those places
authorized by Article 822.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-306__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court authorizing the detention of the child in an adult jail or lockup pursuant
to Paragraph B or D of this Article shall submit a written report delineating appropriate
reasons for the continued custody to the judicial administrator of the supreme court for
review and shall submit copies to the Louisiana Commission on Law Enforcement and
Administration of Criminal Justice and to the sheriff or chief of police of the facility in which
the child is being detained within seven working days of the court's decision.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-306__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, a child who is subject to
criminal jurisdiction pursuant to Article 305 and being held in a juvenile detention facility
before trial shall be transferred to the appropriate adult facility for continued pretrial
detention upon reaching the age of eighteen.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=73104</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>