<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-902"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-902"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CE 902"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-902/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-902/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-902/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-902/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CE-902">
        <num>CE 902</num>
        <heading>902.  Self-authentication</heading>
        <subsection eId="CE-902__subsec_1">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Domestic public documents under seal.  A document bearing a seal, including
electronically generated documents logically associated with electronically generated seals,
purporting to be that of the United States, or of any state, district, commonwealth, territory,
or insular possession thereof, or the Panama Canal Zone, or the Trust Territory of the Pacific
Islands, or of a political subdivision, department, officer, or agency thereof, and a signature
purporting to be an attestation or execution.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CE-902__subsec_2">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Domestic public documents not under seal.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CE-902__subsec_2__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Domestic public documents
generally.  A document purporting to bear the signature in his official capacity of an officer
or employee of any entity included in Paragraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CE-902__subsec_1">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this Article, having no seal, if a public
officer having a seal and having official duties in the district or political subdivision of the
officer or employee certifies under seal that the signer has the official capacity and that the
signature is genuine.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CE-902__subsec_1__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Certified Louisiana public documents.  A purported record, book, paper, or other
document of the State of Louisiana, or of a department, board, or agency thereof or of a
political subdivision of the state or a department, board, or agency of such a subdivision
when certified as being the original by an officer or employee who identifies his official
position and who either has custody of the document or who is otherwise authorized to make
such a certification.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CE-902__subsec_3">
          <num>(3)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Foreign public documents.  A document purporting to be executed or attested in
his official capacity by a person authorized by the laws of a foreign country to make the
execution or attestation, and accompanied by a final certification as to the genuineness of the
signature and official position</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CE-902__subsec_3__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of the executing or attesting person, or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-902__subsec_3__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of any foreign
official whose certificate of genuineness of signature and official position relates to the
execution or attestation or is in a chain of certificates of genuineness of signature and official
position relating to the execution or attestation.  A final certification may be made by a
secretary of embassy or legation, consul general, consul, vice consul, or consular agent of the
United States, or a diplomatic or consular official of the foreign country assigned or
accredited to the United States.  If reasonable opportunity has been given to all parties to
investigate the authenticity and accuracy of official documents, the court may, for good cause
shown, order that they be treated as presumptively authentic without final certification or
permit them to be evidenced by an attested summary with or without final certification.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CE-902__subsec_4">
          <num>(4)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Presumptions under Acts of Congress and the Louisiana Legislature.  Any
signature, document, or other matter declared by Act of Congress or by Act of the Louisiana
Legislature to be presumptively or prima facie genuine or authentic.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CE-902__subsec_5">
          <num>(5)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Official publications.  Books, pamphlets, or other publications purporting to be
issued by public authority.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CE-902__subsec_6">
          <num>(6)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Newspapers and periodicals.  Printed materials purporting to be newspapers or
periodicals.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CE-902__subsec_7">
          <num>(7)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Trade inscriptions and the like.  Inscriptions, signs, tags, or labels purporting to
have been affixed in the course of business and indicating ownership, control, or origin.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CE-902__subsec_8">
          <num>(8)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Authentic acts, acknowledged acts, and other instruments attested by witnesses.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CE-902__subsec_8__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Authentic acts, acts under private signature duly acknowledged, and instruments attested
by witnesses and accompanied by affidavits, as provided by Louisiana law, whether executed
in Louisiana or elsewhere.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-902__subsec_8__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Documents executed in a jurisdiction other than Louisiana
accompanied by a certificate of acknowledgment executed in the manner provided by the
laws of that jurisdiction by a notary public or other officer authorized by law to take
acknowledgments.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CE-902__subsec_9">
          <num>(9)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Commercial paper and related documents.  Commercial paper, signatures
thereon, and documents relating thereto to the extent provided by general commercial law.
NOTE:  Paragraph 10 eff. until October 1, 2027.  See</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=72518</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>