<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-562"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-562"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 562"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-562/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-562/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-562/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-562/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-562">
        <num>CCRP 562</num>
        <heading>562.  Use of simultaneous audio-visual transmission for certain proceedings</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-562__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In a case where the offense is a noncapital felony or a misdemeanor, the
defendant, who is confined in a jail, prison, or other detention facility in Louisiana, may, with
the court's consent and the consent of the district attorney, appear at the entry of his plea of
guilty, at any revocation hearing for a probation violation, including any hearing for a
contempt of court, and at sentencing by simultaneous audio-visual transmission if the court,
by local rule, provides for the defendant's appearance in this manner and the defendant
waives his right to be physically present at the proceeding.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-562__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In a capital case, the defendant may not enter his plea by simultaneous audio-visual transmission.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-562__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the defendant is represented by an attorney during the proceeding in which a
simultaneous audio-visual transmission system is used, the attorney may elect to be present
either in the courtroom with the presiding judicial officer or in the place where the defendant
is confined.  Upon request by the defendant or the attorney representing the defendant, the
court shall provide the opportunity for confidential communication between the defendant
and the attorney representing him at any time prior to or during the proceeding.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-562__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The law enforcement agency who has custody of the defendant at the time of the
proceeding shall obtain the fingerprints of the defendant for purposes of Article 871.  The
fingerprints may be taken electronically or in ink and converted to electronic format.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=1054258</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>