<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-906"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-906"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 906"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-906/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-906/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-906/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-906/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-906">
        <num>CHC 906</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-906__subsec_1">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The medical staff of a mental institution to which a child is committed or
placed by the Louisiana Department of Health after the child has been found not guilty by
reason of insanity or after a court determines that the child lacks mental capacity to proceed
shall review the child's record after the first sixty days, again after one hundred twenty days
of commitment, and every one hundred eighty days thereafter.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-906__subsec_2">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The purpose of these reviews is to determine the child's present mental condition
and whether he is presently capable of being discharged, conditionally or unconditionally,
or being placed on probation, without being a danger to others or himself, or is presently
capable of proceeding.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-906__subsec_3">
          <num>(3)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The department or the superintendent of the private institution shall make such
recommendations to the court as provided in Article 835 or 838.
B.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-906__subsec_1">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any child committed by a court to the custody of the office of juvenile justice
must be physically transported to the committing court for an in-person review hearing not
more than six months after the child's commitment, and at least every six months thereafter,
unless such an in-person hearing is waived by counsel for the child and by the committing
court. The date of the initial review hearing shall be set by the court at the time of
disposition.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-906__subsec_2">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The purpose of the hearing shall be to ensure the child is receiving necessary
treatment and services and all terms and conditions of his disposition are followed.  The
court may also consider any motions for modification of disposition pursuant to Article 909
et seq. at the hearings.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-906__subsec_3">
          <num>(3)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the purposes of this Paragraph, a child is deemed &quot;committed by a court to
the custody of the office of juvenile justice&quot; if he is judicially committed to the legal custody
of the office of juvenile justice, regardless of where the child is physically held, including but
not limited to state-run secure facilities, state-run nonsecure facilities, private facilities with
which the office of juvenile justice contracts, and detention centers.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-906__subsec_4">
          <num>(4)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The provisions of this Paragraph shall apply to all children in the custody of the
office of juvenile justice on and after August 1, 2018. If a child in the custody of the office
of juvenile justice on August 1, 2018, has not had a hearing scheduled pursuant to this
Paragraph, the court shall schedule a hearing no later than September 30, 2018, and, if a child
is eligible for a hearing, the hearing shall take place no later than October 30, 2018.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=73499</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>