<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1569"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1569"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 1569"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1569/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1569/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1569/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1569/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-1569">
        <num>CHC 1569</num>
        <heading>1569.  Temporary restraining order</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1569__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon good cause shown in an ex parte proceeding, the court may enter a
temporary restraining order, without bond, as the court deems necessary to protect from
abuse the petitioner, any children, or any person alleged to be incompetent.  Immediate and
present danger of abuse shall constitute good cause for purposes of this Article.  The order
may include but is not limited to the following:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1569__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Awarding to a party the use and possession of specified community property,
such as an automobile.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1569__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Granting possession to the petitioner of the residence or household to the
exclusion of the defendant, by evicting the defendant or restoring possession to the petitioner
when either:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-1569__subsec_A__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The residence is jointly owned in equal proportion or leased by the defendant and
the petitioner or the person on whose behalf the petition is brought.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-1569__subsec_A__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The residence is solely owned by the petitioner or the person on whose behalf the
petition is brought.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-1569__subsec_A__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The residence is solely leased by defendant and defendant has a duty to support
the petitioner or the person on whose behalf the petition is brought.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1569__subsec_A__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Prohibiting either party from the transferring, encumbering, or otherwise
disposing of property mutually owned or leased by the parties, except when in the ordinary
course of business or for the necessary support of the party or the children.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1569__subsec_A__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Awarding temporary custody of children or persons alleged to be incompetent.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1569__subsec_A__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Awarding or restoring possession to the petitioner of all separate property and all
personal property, including but not limited to telephones or other communication
equipment, computer, medications, clothing, toiletries, social security cards, birth certificates
or other forms of identification, tools of the trade, checkbook, keys, automobile,
photographs, jewelry, or any other items or personal effects of the petitioner and restraining
the defendant from transferring, encumbering, concealing, or disposing of the personal or
separate property of the petitioner.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1569__subsec_A__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Granting to the petitioner the exclusive care, possession, or control of any pets
belonging to or under the care of the petitioner or children residing in the residence or
household of either party, and directing the defendant to refrain from harassing, interfering
with, abusing or injuring any pet, without legal justification, known to be owned, possessed,
leased, kept, or held by either party or a child residing in the residence or household of either
party.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1569__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a temporary restraining order is granted without notice, the matter shall be set
within twenty-one days for a rule to show cause why the protective order should not be
issued, at which time the petitioner must prove the allegations of abuse by a preponderance
of the evidence.  The defendant shall be given notice of the temporary restraining order and
the hearing on the rule to show cause by service of process as required by law.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1569__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>During the existence of the temporary restraining order, a party shall have the
right to return to the family residence once to recover his or her personal clothing and
necessities, provided that the party is accompanied by a law enforcement officer to insure the
protection and safety of the parties.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1569__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If no temporary restraining order has been granted, the court shall issue a rule to
show cause why the protective order should not be issued, and set the rule for hearing on the
earliest day that the business of the court will permit, but in any case within ten days from
the date of service of the petition, at which time the petitioner must prove the allegations of
abuse by a preponderance of the evidence.  The defendant shall be given notice by service
of process as required by law.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1569__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the hearing pursuant to Paragraph B or D of this Article is continued, the court
shall make or extend such temporary restraining order as it deems necessary.  Any
continuance of a hearing ordered pursuant to Paragraph B or D of this Article shall not
exceed fifteen days, unless good cause is shown for further continuance.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1569__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court may, in its discretion, grant an emergency temporary restraining order
outside regular court hours.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1569__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Repealed by</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=73027</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>