<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-897"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-897"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 897"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-897/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-897/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-897/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-897/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-897">
        <num>CHC 897</num>
        <heading>897.  Disposition after adjudication of a felony-grade delinquent act</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-897__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>After adjudication of any felony-grade delinquent act other than those described
in Article 897.1, the court may:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-897__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Reprimand and warn the child and release him into the custody of his parents
either unconditionally or subject to such terms and conditions as deemed in the best interests
of the child and the public.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-897__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Reprimand and warn the child and release him into the custody of some other
suitable person either unconditionally or subject to such terms and conditions as deemed in
the best interests of the child and the public. The court shall, whenever practicable, select a
person of the same religious faith as the child or his parents.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-897__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Place the child on probation in the custody of his parents or other suitable person.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-897__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>As conditions of probation, if ordered pursuant to Subparagraph (A)</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-897__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this
Article:</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-897__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The court shall impose all of the following restrictions:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-897__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Prohibit the child from possessing any drugs or alcohol.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-897__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Prohibit the child from engaging in any further delinquent or criminal activity.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-897__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Prohibit the child from possessing a firearm or carrying a concealed weapon, if
he has been adjudicated for any of the following offenses and probation is not otherwise
prohibited:  first or second degree murder; manslaughter; aggravated battery; aggravated or
first degree rape, forcible or second degree rape, or simple or third degree rape; aggravated
crime against nature as defined by R.S. 14:89.1(A)</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-897__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The court may impose any other term and condition deemed in the best interests
of the child and the public, including:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-897__subsec_B__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A requirement that the child attend school, if the school admits the child.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-897__subsec_B__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A requirement that the child perform court-approved community service
activities.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-897__subsec_B__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A requirement that the child and his parent or legal guardian cooperate in
connection with any part of the disposition order, including but not limited to a
court-approved decisionmaking course necessary for his rehabilitation.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-897__subsec_B__subsec_2__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A requirement that the child make reasonable restitution to any victim for any
personal or property damage caused by the child in the commission of the delinquent act.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-897__subsec_B__subsec_2__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A requirement that the child participate in any program of medical or
psychological or other treatment found necessary for his rehabilitation.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-897__subsec_B__subsec_2__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A requirement suspending or restricting the child's driving privileges, if any, for
all or part of the period of probation.  In such cases, a copy of the order shall be forwarded
to the Department of Public Safety and Corrections, which shall suspend the child's driver's
license or issue a restricted license in accordance with the order of the court.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-897__subsec_B__subsec_2__subsec_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A requirement prohibiting the child from possessing a firearm or carrying a
concealed weapon.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-897__subsec_B__subsec_2__subsec_h">
              <num>(h)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A requirement that the child pay a supervision fee of not less than ten nor more
than one hundred dollars per month, payable to the Department of Public Safety and
Corrections or other supervising agency, to defray the costs of supervision.  The amount of
the fee shall be based upon the financial ability of the payor to pay such a fee.  The court may
order a parent, tutor, guardian, or other person who is financially responsible for the care of
the child to be responsible for payment of all or part of any supervision fee imposed.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-897__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as provided for in Article 897.1, the court may commit the child to the
custody of a private or public institution or agency.  When commitment is to be made to a
private institution or agency, the court shall:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-897__subsec_C__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Select one that has been licensed under state law, if licensure is required by law
for such an institution or agency.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-897__subsec_C__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Whenever practicable, select an agency or institution of the same religious faith
as the child or his parents.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-897__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as provided in Article 897.1, the court may commit the child to the
custody of the Department of Public Safety and Corrections, with or without a
recommendation that the child be placed in alternative care facilities through the
department's client placement process, or be referred to appropriate placement resources in
the state available through other public or private agencies.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-897__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as provided for in Article 897.1, the court may impose but suspend the
execution of the whole or part of any order of commitment and place the child on probation
subject to any of the terms and conditions authorized under Paragraph B of this Article.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=73488</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>