<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-230-1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-230-1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 230.1"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-230-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-230-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-230-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-230-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-230-1">
        <num>CCRP 230.1</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-230-1__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The sheriff or law enforcement officer having custody of an arrested person shall
bring him promptly, and in any case within seventy-two hours from the time of the arrest,
before a judge for the purpose of appointment of counsel.  Saturdays, Sundays, and legal
holidays shall be excluded in computing the seventy-two-hour period referred to herein.  The
defendant shall appear in person unless the court by local rule provides for such appearance
by telephone or audio-video electronic equipment.  However, upon a showing that the
defendant is incapacitated, unconscious, or otherwise physically or mentally unable to appear
in court within seventy-two hours, then the defendant's presence is waived by law, and a
judge shall appoint counsel to represent the defendant within seventy-two hours from the
time of arrest.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-230-1__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>At this appearance, if a defendant has the right to have the court appoint counsel
to defend him, the court shall assign counsel to the defendant.  The court may also, in its
discretion, determine or review a prior determination of the amount of bail.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-230-1__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the arrested person is not brought before a judge in accordance with the
provisions of Paragraph A of this Article, he shall be released on his own recognizance.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-230-1__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The failure of the sheriff or law enforcement officer to comply with the
requirements herein shall have no effect whatsoever upon the validity of the proceedings
thereafter against the defendant.
Added by</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112388</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>