<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-672-3"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-672-3"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 672.3"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-672-3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-672-3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-672-3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-672-3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-672-3">
        <num>CHC 672.3</num>
        <heading>672.3.  Diligent search for relatives; notice; failure to respond</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-672-3__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whenever custody of a child is assigned to the Department of Children and
Family Services, the department shall conduct a diligent search for adult relatives of the child
and for persons who have a significant relationship with the child. The diligent search shall
be completed no later than thirty days from the date the child was taken into custody and
include, at a minimum, all of the following:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-672-3__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Interviews with the child's parent during the course of an investigation, while
child protective services are provided, and while the child is in care.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-672-3__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Interviews with the child.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-672-3__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Interviews with identified relatives throughout the case.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-672-3__subsec_A__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Interviews with any other person who is likely to have information about the
identity or location of adult relatives of the child or persons who have a significant
relationship with the child.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-672-3__subsec_A__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Comprehensive searches of databases and other resources available to the
Department of Children and Family Services, which may include searches of schools,
employment, residence, utilities, vehicle registration, child support enforcement, law
enforcement, and corrections records or any other records likely to result in identifying and
locating adult relatives of the child or persons who have a significant relationship with the
child.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-672-3__subsec_A__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Appropriate inquiry during the course of hearings in the case in accordance with
Article 625(D).</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-672-3__subsec_A__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any other reasonable means that are likely to identify relatives or other persons
who have demonstrated an ongoing commitment to the child.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-672-3__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The Department of Children and Family Services shall file with the court
information regarding attempts made pursuant to Paragraph A of this Article ten days before
any scheduled disposition, case review, permanency hearing, or as otherwise required by the
court. Any additional information obtained by the department subsequent to the initial filing
shall be disclosed to the court during the hearing.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-672-3__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>All relatives of the child identified in the diligent search required by this Article,
subject to exceptions due to family or domestic violence or other safety concerns, shall be
provided with a notice that does all of the following:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-672-3__subsec_C__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Specifies that the child has been or is being removed from parental custody.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-672-3__subsec_C__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Explains the options that a relative has to participate in the care and placement
of the child and any options that may be lost by failing to respond to the notice.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-672-3__subsec_C__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Describes the process for becoming a licensed foster family home and the
additional services and supports available for children placed in approved foster homes.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-672-3__subsec_C__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Describes any financial assistance for which a relative may be eligible.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-672-3__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>After the completion of the diligent search required by this Article, the
Department of Children and Family Services shall have a continuing duty to search for
relatives or other persons who have demonstrated an ongoing commitment to a child and
with whom it may be appropriate to place the child until the relatives or persons are located,
the court excuses the department from conducting a diligent search, or permanency is
achieved.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-672-3__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a relative entitled to notice pursuant to this Article fails, after ninety days from
the date the relative receives the required notice, to demonstrate an interest in and willingness
to provide a permanent home for a child, the court may excuse the Department of Children
and Family Services from considering the relative as a placement.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=1238142</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>