<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1409"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1409"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 1409"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1409/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1409/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1409/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1409/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-1409">
        <num>CHC 1409</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1409__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each minor patient has a right to care provided in a dignified and humane manner,
and to such privacy as is possible consistent with the minor's treatment plan.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1409__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The confinement of a minor to an institution shall not of itself cause him to lose
any of the rights enjoyed by citizens of Louisiana and of the United States.  No minor patient
shall be deprived of these rights except when the determination is made by an appropriate
court.
C.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The minor patient in a treatment facility shall be permitted unimpeded, private,
and uncensored communication with persons of his choice by mail, telephone, and visitation. 
These rights may be restricted by the director of the treatment facility if sufficient cause
exists and is so documented in the minor's medical records.  The minor's legal counsel, as
well as his next of kin or responsible party, must be notified in writing of any such
restrictions and the reasons therefor.  When the cause for any restriction ceases to exist, the
minor's full rights shall be reinstated.  A minor shall have the right to communicate in any
manner in private with his attorney at all times.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The director of a treatment facility shall ensure that correspondence can be
conveniently received and mailed, that telephones are reasonably accessible, and that space
for visits is available.  Writing materials, postage, and telephone usage funds shall be
provided in reasonable amounts to minor patients who are unable to procure such items.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Reasonable times and places for the use of telephones and for visits may be
established in writing by the director of any treatment facility.  However, the times and
places established by the director must allow patients, at a minimum, reasonable daily
communication by telephone and visitation.  These rights may be restricted by the director
of the treatment facility if sufficient cause exists and is so documented in the patient's
medical records.  The patient's legal counsel, as well as his next of kin or responsible party,
must be notified in writing of any such restrictions and the reasons therefor.  When the cause
for any restriction ceases to exist, the patient's full rights shall be reinstated.
(4)</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_B__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The director of any substance abuse treatment facility may restrict the
visitation rights of a minor who is voluntarily admitted to such treatment facility for
substance abuse treatment under provisions of this Title for the initial phase of treatment but
no longer than seven days unless good cause exists to extend the restriction and is so
documented in the patient's record.  This restriction shall not apply to visitation by the
minor's attorney, or if he is not represented by counsel, the MHAS attorney or the minor's
minister.  This restriction shall also not apply to the parent or legal guardian of a minor
unless the director determines that good cause exists that such restriction shall be in the best
interests of the minor and is so documented in the minor's record.  When the facility director
determines the need to restrict visitation of new minor patients, he shall post notice of such
restriction in places prominent to all new admissions, and shall inform each new patient of
the restriction prior to his admission and the length and duration thereof, and further that
such restriction may be extended on an individual basis as determined to be in the minor's
interest by the treatment staff with the concurrence of the medical director.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_B__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Nothing herein shall be construed to further restrict other forms of patient
communication by and to minor patients as permitted in this Article nor shall this restriction
apply to mental health treatment facilities.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1409__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Physical restraints or seclusion shall only be used to prevent a minor patient from
physically injuring himself or others.  Physical restraints or seclusion may not be used to
punish or discipline a patient or used as a convenience to the staff of the treatment facility. 
Restraint and seclusion shall be used only in accordance with the following standards:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_D__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Restraint or seclusion shall only be used when verbal intervention or less
restrictive measures fail.  Use of restraint or seclusion shall require documentation in the
patient's record of the clinical justification for such use as well as the inadequacy of less
restrictive intervention techniques.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_D__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A written order from a physician or a psychologist acting within the scope of his
institutional privileges shall be required for any use of restraint or seclusion.  If, however, no
physician or psychologist is immediately available, a registered nurse who has been trained
in management of disturbed behavior may utilize restraint or seclusion.  The nurse or the
nursing supervisor shall then immediately notify a physician or a psychologist with
institutional authority to order seclusion and provide him with sufficient information to
determine whether restraints or seclusion are necessary and whether less restrictive
interventions have been tried or considered.  The physician or psychologist may then issue
a telephone order for seclusion or restraint, if such order is indicated.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_D__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Written orders for the use of restraint or seclusion shall be time limited and not
more than twelve hours in duration.  The written order shall include the date and time of the
actual examination of the patient, the date and time that the patient was placed in restraint
or seclusion, and the date and time that the order was signed.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_D__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A renewal order for up to twelve hours of restraint or seclusion may be issued by
a physician or a psychologist with institutional authority to order seclusion or restraint after
determining that there is no less restrictive means of preventing injury to the patient or
others. If any patient is held in restraint or seclusion for twenty-four hours, the physician or
psychologist with institutional authority shall conduct an actual examination of the patient
and document the reason why the use of seclusion or restraint beyond twenty-four hours is
necessary, and the parent, tutor, or caretaker shall be notified by the twenty-sixth hour.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_D__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Staff who implement written orders for restraints and seclusion shall have
documented training in the proper use of the procedure for which the order was written.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_D__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Periodic monitoring and care of the patient shall be provided by responsible staff. 
A patient in restraint or seclusion shall be evaluated every fifteen minutes, especially in
regard to regular meals, water, and snacks, bathing, the need for motion and exercise, and use
of the bathroom, and documentation of these evaluations shall be entered in the patient's
record.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_D__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Patients shall be released from restraint or seclusion as soon as the reasons
justifying the use of restraints or seclusion subside.  If at any time during the period of
restraint or seclusion a registered nurse determines that the emergency which justified the
seclusion or restraint has subsided and a physician or psychologist is not immediately
available, the patient shall be released.  At the end of the period of restraint or seclusion
ordered by the physician or psychologist the patient shall be released unless a renewal order
is issued.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_D__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Mechanical restraints shall be designed and used so as not to cause physical
injury to the patient and so as to cause the least possible discomfort.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_D__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Facilities using seclusion or restraint shall have written policies concerning their
use.  These policies shall include standards and procedures for placing a patient in seclusion
or restraint, and for informing him of the reason he was put in seclusion or restraint and the
means of terminating such seclusion or restraint.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_D__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Nothing in this Article shall be construed to expand the scope of practice of
psychology as defined in R.S. 37:2351 et seq. to authorize the ordering, administering, or
dispensing of medications, or to authorize any practice not permitted under the privileges
granted by the institution.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_D__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The department shall adopt rules and regulations in accordance with the
Administrative Procedure Act to govern the use of seclusion and restraint.  Such rules and
regulations shall respect the minor patient's individual rights, protect the minor patient's
health, safety, and welfare, and be the least restrictive of the minor patient's liberty.  The
department shall adopt rules and regulations to provide for enforcement procedures and
penalties applicable to a person who violates the requirements of this Section.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1409__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A patient may be placed alone in a room or other area pursuant to behavior
shaping techniques such as &quot;time-out&quot;.  Such placement may only be used as part of a written
treatment plan, shall not be used for the convenience of staff, and may be used only
according to the following standards and procedures:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_E__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Placement alone in a room or other area shall be imposed only when less
restrictive measures are inadequate.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_E__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Placement alone in a room or other area shall only be ordered by a qualified
professional trained in behavior-shaping techniques and authorized in accordance with
written policies and procedures of the facility to order the use of behavior-shaping
techniques.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_E__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The period of placement alone in a room or other area shall not exceed thirty
minutes.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_E__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The patient shall be observed and supervised by a staff member.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_E__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The period of placement alone in a room or other area shall not exceed a total of
three hours in any twenty-four hour time period.  If the placement alone in a room or other
area exceeds a total of three hours in any twenty-four hour time period, it shall then be
considered seclusion and shall be governed by the procedures and standards set forth in
Paragraph D of this Article.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_E__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The date, time, and duration of the placement shall be documented.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_E__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In treatment facilities where patients are placed alone in a room or other area as
a behavior-shaping technique, there shall be written policies and procedures governing use
of such behavior-shaping technique.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1409__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>No minor patient confined by emergency certificate, judicial commitment, court
order, or noncontested status shall receive major surgical procedures or electroshock therapy
without the written consent of a court of competent jurisdiction after a hearing.  However,
if the director of the treatment facility, in consultation with two physicians, determines that
the condition of the minor is of such a critical nature that it may be life-threatening unless
major surgical procedures or electroshock therapy are administered, such emergency
measures may be performed without the consent otherwise provided for in this Paragraph. 
No physician shall be liable for a good faith determination that a medical emergency exists.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1409__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Every minor patient shall have the right to wear his own clothes and keep and use
his personal possessions, including toilet articles, unless determined by a physician that these
are medically inappropriate and the reasons therefor are documented in his medical record. 
The minor shall also be allowed to spend a reasonable sum of his own money for canteen
expenses and small purchases, and to have access to individual storage spaces for his private
use.  If the minor is financially unable to provide these articles for himself, the treatment
facility shall provide a reasonable supply of clothing and toiletries.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1409__subsec_H">
          <num>H.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The following rules shall govern performance of work by minor patients:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_H__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>No minor shall be required to perform work of any kind that involves the
operation and maintenance of an institution, nor shall privileges or release from an institution
be conditioned upon performance of any work, except as follows:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_H__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A minor patient may be required to perform vocational training tasks, provided
each task is:</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_H__subsec_1__subsec_i">
              <num>(i)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Part of the minor's individual treatment plan and has been approved as a program
activity by a professional responsible for supervising the program.
(ii)  Supervised by a qualified professional.
(iii)  Not continued for longer than six months, unless it is specifically reinstated by
the minor's treatment plan.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_H__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A minor patient may be required to perform without compensation such
housekeeping tasks as would be performed by a minor in a natural home, foster home, or
group home, provided that nothing in the minor's individual treatment plan forbids such
work.  In no case, however, may a minor be required to perform housekeeping tasks for more
than twelve other people.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_H__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A minor may voluntarily engage in work during nonprogram hours, provided
that:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_H__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The minor's individual treatment plan does not forbid it.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_H__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The particular work has been approved by the qualified professional responsible
for supervising the implementation of the minor treatment plan.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_H__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The particular work is supervised by qualified staff.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_H__subsec_2__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The conditions of employment and the compensation are in full compliance with
all applicable federal laws.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1409__subsec_H__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>No minor patient shall be involved in the care, feeding, clothing, training, or
supervision of other minors unless the qualified professional responsible for supervising the
implementation of the treatment plan certifies in writing in the minor's record that the
particular task will not in any way endanger the life or health or be detrimental to the
development of the particular children who receive such care or of the minor patient
providing it.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1409__subsec_I">
          <num>I.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Under appropriate supervision, each minor patient shall be provided with suitable
opportunities for interaction with members of the opposite sex, except where a qualified
professional responsible for the formulation of a particular minor's treatment plan writes an
order to the contrary and explains the reasons therefor.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1409__subsec_J">
          <num>J.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Every minor patient shall have the right to be discharged from a treatment facility
when his condition has changed or improved to the extent that confinement and treatment
at the treatment facility are no longer required.  The director of the treatment facility shall
have the authority to discharge a patient admitted by judicial commitment pursuant to
Chapter 9 of this Title without the approval of the court which committed him to the
treatment facility.  The court shall be advised of any such discharge.  The director shall not
be legally responsible to any person for the subsequent acts of behavior of a patient
discharged by him in good faith.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1409__subsec_K">
          <num>K.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Every minor patient shall have the right to engage a private attorney.  If the minor
is indigent, he shall be provided an attorney by the MHAS, if he so requests.  The attorneys
provided by the MHAS or appointed by a court shall be interested in and qualified by
training or experience, or both, in the field of mental health statutes and jurisprudence.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1409__subsec_L">
          <num>L.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Every minor patient shall have the right to request a court hearing pursuant to
Article 1411.  The purpose of the hearing shall be to determine whether or not he should be
discharged from the treatment facility or transferred to a less restrictive and medically
suitable treatment facility.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1409__subsec_M">
          <num>M.</num>
          <content>
            <p>No provision hereof shall abridge or diminish the right of any minor patient to
avail himself of the right of habeas corpus at any time.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1409__subsec_N">
          <num>N.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Every minor patient shall have the right to be visited and examined at his own
expense by a physician designated by him, a member of his family, or an interested party. 
The physician may consult and confer with the medical staff of the treatment facility and
have the benefit of all information contained in the patient's medical record.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1409__subsec_O">
          <num>O.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Prefrontal lobotomy shall be prohibited as a treatment solely for medical or
emotional illness of a minor patient.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1409__subsec_P">
          <num>P.</num>
          <content>
            <p>No medication shall be administered to a minor patient unless a written order of
a physician prescribes it in writing.  The physician is responsible for all medications which
he has ordered and which are administered to a minor patient.  The medication prescribed
shall be noted in the minor patient's records.  At least monthly, the attending physician shall
review the drug regimen of each minor patient under his care.  All prescriptions shall be
written with a termination date, which shall not exceed thirty days.  The minor's records shall
state the effects of psychoactive medication on him.  Unnecessary or excessive medication
shall not be administered to any minor patient.  Medication shall not be used as punishment,
for the convenience of staff, as a substitute for a treatment program, or in quantities that
interfere with the minor's treatment program.  No medication shall be administered except
by persons who have been appropriately trained.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1409__subsec_Q">
          <num>Q.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A minor patient admitted to a treatment facility has the right to an individualized
treatment plan and periodic review to determine his progress.  The appropriate staff of the
facility shall review the minor's progress at least at intervals of thirty days.  The staff shall
enter into the minor's medical record his response to medical treatment, his current mental
status, and specific reasons why continued treatment is necessary in the current setting or
whether a treatment facility is available which is medically suitable and less restrictive of the
minor patient's liberty.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1409__subsec_R">
          <num>R.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A minor patient admitted to a treatment facility has the right to have available
such treatment as is medically appropriate to his condition.  Should the treatment facility be
unable to provide an active and appropriate medical treatment program, the minor shall be
discharged.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1409__subsec_S">
          <num>S.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each minor patient shall have the right to receive prompt and adequate medical
treatment for any physical ailments and for the prevention of any illness or disability.  Such
medical treatment shall meet the standards of medical practice in the community.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1409__subsec_T">
          <num>T.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The institution shall prohibit the mistreatment, neglect, or abuse of any child in
any way.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=72905</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>