<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-1702"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-1702"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCP 1702"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-1702/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-1702/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-1702/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-1702/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCP-1702">
        <num>CCP 1702</num>
        <heading>1702.  Default judgment</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCP-1702__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In those proceedings in which the sum due is on an open account or a promissory
note, other negotiable instrument, or other conventional obligation, or a deficiency judgment
derived therefrom, including those proceedings in which one or more mortgages, pledges,
or other security for the open account, promissory note, negotiable instrument, conventional
obligation, or deficiency judgment derived therefrom is sought to be enforced, maintained,
or recognized, or in which the amount sought is that authorized by R.S. 9:2782 for a check
dishonored for nonsufficient funds, a hearing in open court shall not be required unless the
judge, in his discretion, directs that such a hearing be held.  The plaintiff shall submit to the
court the proof required by law and the original and not less than one copy of the proposed
default judgment.  The judge shall, within seventy-two hours of receipt of such submission
from the clerk of court, sign the proposed default judgment or direct that a hearing be held. 
The clerk of court shall certify that no answer or other pleading has been filed by the
defendant.  The minute clerk shall make an entry showing the dates of receipt of proof,
review of the record, and rendition of the default judgment.  A certified copy of the signed
default judgment shall be sent to the plaintiff by the clerk of court, and notice of the signing
of the default judgment shall be given as provided in Article 1913.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-1702__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>When the demand is based upon a right acquired by assignment in an open
account, promissory note, or other negotiable instrument, the court may raise an objection
of prescription before entering a default judgment if the grounds for the objection appear
from the pleadings or from the evidence submitted by the plaintiff. If the court raises an
objection of prescription, it shall not enter the default judgment unless the plaintiff presents
prima facie proof that the action is not barred by prescription.  Upon the plaintiff's request,
the court shall hold a hearing for the submission of such proof.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-1702__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>When the demand is based upon a claim for a personal injury, a sworn narrative
report of the treating physician or dentist may be offered in lieu of his testimony.
F.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-1702__subsec_E__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding any other provisions of law to the contrary, when the demand
is for divorce under Civil Code Article 103</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-1702__subsec_E__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>or (5), whether or not the demand contains a
claim for relief incidental or ancillary thereto, a hearing in open court shall not be required
unless the judge, in his discretion, directs that a hearing be held.  The plaintiff shall submit
to the court an affidavit specifically attesting to and testifying as to the truth of all of the
factual allegations contained in the petition, the original and not less than one copy of the
proposed default judgment, a certification indicating the type of service made on the
defendant and the date of service, and a certification by the clerk that the record was
examined by the clerk, including the date of the examination, and a statement that no answer
or other pleading has been filed.  If the demand is for divorce under Civil Code Article
103(5), a certified copy of the protective order or injunction rendered after a contradictory
hearing or consent decree shall also be submitted to the court.  If no answer or other pleading
has been filed by the defendant, the judge shall review the submitted affidavit, proposed
default judgment, and certification and render and sign the proposed default judgment or
direct that a hearing be held.  The minutes shall reflect rendition and signing of the default
judgment.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-1702__subsec_E__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the demand is for divorce under Civil Code Article 103</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-1702__subsec_E__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and the defendant,
by sworn affidavit, acknowledges receipt of a certified copy of the petition and waives formal
citation, service of process, all legal delays, notice of trial, and appearance at trial, a default
judgment of divorce may be entered against the defendant two days, exclusive of legal
holidays, after the affidavit is filed.  The affidavit of the defendant may be prepared or
notarized by any notary public.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-1702__subsec_E__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The notice requirements contained in Paragraph A of this Article shall not apply
when the plaintiff intends to obtain a default judgment for a demand for divorce as provided
by this Paragraph.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=111285</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>