<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-926-2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-926-2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 926.2"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-926-2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-926-2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-926-2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-926-2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-926-2">
        <num>CCRP 926.2</num>
        <heading>926.2.  Factual innocence</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-926-2__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A petitioner who has been convicted of an offense may seek post conviction relief
on the grounds that he is factually innocent of the offense for which he was convicted. A
petitioner's first claim of factual innocence pursuant to this Article that would otherwise be
barred from review on the merits by the time limitation provided in Article 930.8 or the
procedural objections provided in Article 930.4 shall not be barred if the claim is contained
in an application for post conviction relief filed on or before December 31, 2022, and if the
petitioner was convicted after a trial completed to verdict.  This exception to Articles 930.4
and 930.8 shall apply only to the claim of factual innocence brought under this Article and
shall not apply to any other claims raised by the petitioner.  An application for post
conviction relief filed pursuant to this Article by a petitioner who pled guilty before August
1, 2025, or nolo contendere to the offense of conviction or filed by any petitioner after
December 31, 2022, shall be subject to Articles 930.4 and 930.8.  A petitioner who pled
guilty to the offense of conviction on or after August 1, 2025, shall not be entitled to assert
a claim of factual innocence.
B.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-926-2__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A recantation of prior sworn testimony may be considered if corroborated by the
evidence required by Subsubparagraph (1)</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-926-2__subsec_A__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this Paragraph. However, a recantation of
prior sworn testimony cannot form the sole basis for relief pursuant to this Article and shall
not be sufficient to overcome the presumption of a valid conviction.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-926-2__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the petitioner pled guilty before August 1, 2025, or nolo contendere to the
offense of conviction, in addition to satisfying all of the criteria in this Paragraph and in any
other applicable provision of law, the petitioner shall show both of the following to prove
entitlement to relief:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-926-2__subsec_A__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>That, by reliable evidence, he consistently maintained his innocence until his plea
of guilty or nolo contendere.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-926-2__subsec_A__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>That he could not have known of or discovered his evidence of factual innocence
prior to pleading guilty or nolo contendere.
C.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-926-2__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A grant of post conviction relief pursuant to this Article shall not prevent the
petitioner from being retried for the offense of conviction, for a lesser offense based on the
same facts, or for any other offense.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-926-2__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the petitioner waives his right to a jury trial and elects to be tried by a judge,
the district judge who granted post conviction relief pursuant to this Article shall be recused
and the case shall be allotted to a different judge in accordance with applicable law and rules
of court.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-926-2__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the district judge denied post conviction relief pursuant to this Article and an
appellate court later reversed the ruling of the district judge and granted post conviction relief
pursuant to this Article, and if the petitioner waives his right to a jury trial and elects to be
tried by a judge, upon the petitioner's motion the district judge who denied post conviction
relief shall be recused and the case shall be allotted to a different judge in accordance with
applicable law and rules of court.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=1239817</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>