<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1003"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1003"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 1003"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1003/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1003/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1003/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1003/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-1003">
        <num>CHC 1003</num>
        <heading>1003.  Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1003__subsec_1">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Abuse&quot; means any of the following acts that seriously endanger the physical,
mental, or emotional health, welfare, and safety of the child:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1003__subsec_1__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The infliction or attempted infliction, or, as a result of inadequate supervision,
the allowance or toleration of the infliction or attempted infliction of physical or mental
injury upon the child by a parent or any other person.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1003__subsec_1__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The exploitation or overwork of a child by a parent or any other person.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1003__subsec_1__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The involvement of the child in any sexual act with a parent or any other person,
or the aiding or toleration by the parent or the caretaker of the child's sexual involvement
with any other person or of the child's involvement in pornographic displays, or any other
involvement of a child in sexual activity constituting a crime under the laws of this state.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1003__subsec_2">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Agency&quot; shall include the Department of Children and Family Services, the
corresponding department of any other state, and those private agencies and institutions
licensed for the placement of children for adoption by the Department of Children and
Family Services or by the corresponding department of any other state.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1003__subsec_3">
          <num>(3)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Child in need of care&quot; means a child adjudicated as such under Title VI.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1003__subsec_4">
          <num>(4)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Dangerous to others&quot; means the condition of a person whose behavior or
significant threats support a reasonable expectation that there is a substantial risk that he will
inflict physical harm upon another person in the near future.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1003__subsec_5">
          <num>(5)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Dangerous to self&quot; means the condition of a person whose behavior, significant
threats, or inaction supports a reasonable expectation that there is a substantial risk that he
will inflict physical or severe emotional harm upon his own person.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1003__subsec_6">
          <num>(6)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Department&quot; means the Louisiana Department of Children and Family Services.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1003__subsec_7">
          <num>(7)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Grave disability&quot; means the condition of a person who is unable to provide for
his own basic physical needs, such as essential food, clothing, medical care, and shelter, as
a result of serious mental illness or substance abuse and is unable to survive safely in
freedom or protect himself from serious harm.  The term also includes incapacitation by
alcohol, which means the condition of a person who, as a result of the use of alcohol, is
unconscious or whose judgment is otherwise so impaired that he is incapable of realizing and
making a rational decision with respect to his need for treatment.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1003__subsec_8">
          <num>(8)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Mental deficiency&quot; means significantly subaverage intellectual functioning
existing concurrently with deficits in adaptive behavior, as determined by a psychiatrist or
psychologist and manifested during the developmental period.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1003__subsec_9">
          <num>(9)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Mental illness&quot; means  a psychiatric disorder which has substantial adverse
effects on the parent's ability to function and which requires care and treatment as determined
by a psychiatrist or psychologist.  It does not include a person who has, solely, one of the
following conditions:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1003__subsec_9__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An intellectual disability.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1003__subsec_9__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Epilepsy.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1003__subsec_9__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Alcoholism.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1003__subsec_9__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Drug abuse.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1003__subsec_10">
          <num>(10)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Neglect&quot; means the refusal or failure of a parent or caretaker to supply the child
with necessary food, clothing, shelter, care, treatment, or counseling for any injury, illness,
or condition of the child, as a result of which the child's physical, mental, or emotional
health, welfare, and safety is substantially threatened or impaired.  Whenever, in lieu of
medical care, a child is being provided treatment in accordance with the tenets of a
well-recognized religious method of healing that has a reasonable, proven record of success,
the child shall not, for that reason alone, be considered to be neglected or abused. 
Disagreement by the parent regarding the need for medical care shall not, by itself, be
grounds for termination of parental rights.  However, nothing in this Subparagraph shall
prohibit the court from ordering medical services for the child when there is substantial risk
of harm to the child's health, welfare, or safety.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1003__subsec_11">
          <num>(11)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Permanent placement&quot; means either placement of the child with a legal
guardian or placement of the child with adoptive parents pursuant to a final decree of
adoption.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1003__subsec_12">
          <num>(12)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Starvation&quot; means mistreatment causing suffering from extreme hunger or
malnourishment.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1003__subsec_13">
          <num>(13)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Substance abuse&quot; means the condition of a person who uses narcotic, stimulant,
depressant, soporific, tranquilizing, or hallucinogenic drugs or alcohol to the extent that it
renders the person dangerous to himself or others or renders the person gravely disabled.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1003__subsec_14">
          <num>(14)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Torture&quot; means  torment, maiming, mutilation, or ritualistic or malicious acts
causing extreme and unjustifiable physical or mental pain or suffering, disfigurement, or
injury.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=72526</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>