<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-622"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-622"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 622"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-622/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-622/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-622/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-622/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-622">
        <num>CHC 622</num>
        <heading>622.  Placement pending a continued custody hearing</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-622__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Prior to the continued custody hearing required in Article 624, a suitable relative
or other suitable individual may intervene or seek and obtain an ex parte court order to take
provisional custody of the child pending the continued custody hearing.  The provisions of
Code of Civil Procedure Article 3945 are inapplicable to an ex parte order rendered pursuant
to this Paragraph.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-622__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Unless the best interest of the child requires a different placement, a child who
appears to be a child in need of care and whose immediate removal is necessary shall be
placed, pending a continued custody hearing, in accordance with the following priorities of
placement:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-622__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In the home of a suitable relative who is of the age of majority and with whom
the child has been living in a stable and safe environment if the relative is willing and able
to continue to offer such environment for the child pending an adjudication hearing and if
the relative agrees to the safety plan.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-622__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In the home of a suitable relative who is of the age of majority if the relative is
willing and able to offer a stable and safe environment for the child pending an adjudication
hearing and if the relative agrees to the safety plan.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-622__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In the home of a suitable individual who is of the age of majority if the individual
is willing and able to offer a stable and safe environment for the child pending an
adjudication hearing and if the individual agrees to the safety plan.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-622__subsec_B__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In foster care under the supervision of the department until further orders of the
court.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-622__subsec_B__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In a shelter care facility if the child, who is not in the custody of the department,
has been the victim of human trafficking as provided for in R.S. 14:46.2 or trafficking of
children for sexual purposes as provided for in R.S. 14:46.3.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=73215</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>