<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-812"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-812"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 812"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-812/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-812/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-812/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-812/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-812">
        <num>CCRP 812</num>
        <heading>812.  Same; polling and disposition of jury</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-812__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In all cases, the court shall order the clerk to poll the jury if requested by the state
or the defendant.  The poll shall be conducted in writing by applying the procedures of
Paragraph B of this Article and shall be done in open court.
B.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-812__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In cases in which a verdict was reached, the procedure for the written polling
of the jury shall require that the clerk hand to each juror a separate piece of paper containing
the name of the juror and the words &quot;Is this your verdict?&quot; Each juror shall write on the slip
of paper the words &quot;Yes&quot; or &quot;No&quot; along with his signature.  The clerk shall collect the slips
of paper, make them available for inspection by the court and counsel, and record the results.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-812__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a sufficient number of jurors as required by law to reach a verdict answer &quot;yes&quot;
the clerk shall so inform the court.  Upon verification of the results, the court shall order the
clerk to record the verdict and order the jury discharged.  If an insufficient number required
to find a verdict answer &quot;Yes,&quot; the court may remand the jury for further deliberation, or the
court may declare a mistrial in accordance with Article 775.  The polling slips may be placed
under seal upon order of the court, which shall state the specific reasons for placing the
polling slips under seal.  If so ordered the polling slips shall not be released to the public
without a subsequent order of the court authorizing their release.  If the court orders the
release of the polling slips, the names of the jurors shall be redacted.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-812__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In cases for which no verdict could be reached and a mistrial has been declared
under Article 775(2), the court shall order the clerk to poll the jury if requested by the state
or the defendant.  The poll shall be conducted in writing by applying the procedures of
Paragraph D of this Article and shall be done in open court.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-812__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The procedure for the written polling of the jury shall require that the clerk hand
to each juror a separate piece of paper containing the name of the juror and the words &quot;What
was your verdict?&quot;.  Each juror shall write on the slip of paper the words &quot;guilty&quot; or &quot;not
guilty&quot; or &quot;guilty of a lesser offense&quot; along with his signature.  The clerk shall collect the
slips of paper, make them available for inspection by the court and counsel, and record the
results.  The polling slips may be placed under seal upon order of the court, which shall state
the specific reasons for placing the polling slips under seal.  If so ordered, the polling slips
shall not be released to the public without a subsequent order of the court authorizing their
release.  If the court orders the release of the polling slips, the names of the jurors shall be
redacted.
Amended by</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112810</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>