<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1037"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1037"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 1037"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1037/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1037/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1037/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1037/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-1037">
        <num>CHC 1037</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1037__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>After final submission, the court shall render its judgment within thirty days.
B.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1037__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>When the court finds that the alleged grounds set out in any Paragraph of
Article 1015 or 1015.1 are proven by the evidentiary standards required by Article 1035 and
that it is in the best interest of the child, it shall order the termination of the parental rights
of the parent against whom the allegations are proven.  The court shall enter written findings
on both issues.  The consideration of the best interest of the child shall include consideration
of the child's attachment to his current caretakers.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1037__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>When the grounds for termination set forth in Article 1015.1 have been
established, it shall be considered in the best interest of the child for the parental rights of the
perpetrator to be terminated.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1037__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court shall enter into the record a written, signed judgment.  The date of the
entry of the judgment shall be recorded on the judgment.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1037__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A judgment terminating the parental rights of the parent shall grant custody of the
child to the department, a relative who is of the age of majority and who is willing to adopt
the child without an adoption subsidy, or other suitable person, in accordance with the best
interest of the child.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1037__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A judgment terminating the parental rights of the parent shall inform the parent
of his right to use the services of the voluntary registry as provided in Chapter 15 of Title
XII, although failure to include such information shall not affect the validity of the
termination judgment.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1037__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The judgment shall also certify the child for adoption if, as a result of proceedings
pursuant to this Title or Titles XI and XII, the rights of all parents as defined by Article 1193
have been terminated or relinquished.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1037__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A copy of the judgment shall be furnished to all counsel of record and to all
unrepresented parties.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=72569</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>