<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-163"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-163"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 163"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-163/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-163/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-163/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-163/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-163">
        <num>CCRP 163</num>
        <heading>163.  Officer to whom directed; time for execution; electronic devices</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-163__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A search warrant shall be directed to any peace officer, who shall execute it and
bring any property seized into the court issuing the warrant.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-163__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A search or seizure shall not be made during the nighttime or on Sunday, unless
the warrant expressly so directs.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-163__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as authorized by Article 163.1 or 163.2, or as otherwise provided in this
Article, or as otherwise provided by law, a search warrant cannot be lawfully executed after
the expiration of the tenth day after its issuance.
D.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-163__subsec_C__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any examination or testing of any property seized pursuant to the provisions
of this Article shall be at the direction of the attorney general, the district attorney, or the
investigating agency.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-163__subsec_C__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, any examination or
testing of the seized property may be conducted at any time before or during the pendency
of any criminal proceeding in which the property may be used as evidence.
E.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-163__subsec_C__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, if a warrant is
issued to search for and seize data or information contained in or on a computer, disk drive,
flash drive, cellular telephone, or other electronic communication, or data storage device, the
warrant is considered to have been executed within the time allowed in Paragraph C of this
Article if the device was seized before the expiration of the time allowed, or if the device was
in law enforcement custody at the time of the issuance of the warrant.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-163__subsec_C__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, if a device described
in Subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-163__subsec_C__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Paragraph was seized before the expiration of the time allowed
in Paragraph C of this Article, or if the device was in law enforcement custody at the time
of the issuance of the warrant, any data or information contained in or on the device may be
recovered or extracted pursuant to the warrant at any time, and such recovery or extraction
shall not be subject to the time limitation in Paragraph C of this Article.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112334</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>