<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-13-22"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-13-22"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="SRULE 13.22"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-13-22/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-13-22/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-13-22/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-13-22/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_SRULE-13-22">
        <num>SRULE 13.22</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-13-22__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>There shall be a special committee to be called the Senate Executive Committee
which shall be composed of nine members as follows: ex officio, the President and the
President Pro Tempore; the chairs of the Senate Committee on Finance and the Senate
Committee on Senate and Governmental Affairs; and five members of the Senate
appointed by the President. The President, or one of the members of the committee
designated by him, shall chair the committee.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-13-22__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The committee shall have advisory authority to make recommendations to the
President, other officers, and the Committee on Senate and Governmental Affairs
concerning matters internal to the Senate including, without limitation, matters affecting
Senate space and facilities, officers and employees, rules, administration, and budgetary
and financial questions.
C.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="SRULE-13-22__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The committee shall have the authority to establish an annual vouchered
allotment for members of the Senate to be drawn by each member in monthly payments.
This vouchered allotment shall be used exclusively for expenses incurred in the course
and scope of duties as a member of the Senate such as rent for office space; electricity;
water; gas; telephone; communication services; stationery; supplies; mileage or expense
reimbursement for official travel in or out of state; and other expenses related to the
holding or conduct of office. The committee may authorize an unexpended allotment
amount to be carried forward from one fiscal year into the next fiscal year.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="SRULE-13-22__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The allotment shall be established no later than May fifteenth of the first
calendar year of each term of office to be effective for the succeeding four-year term,
until changed by the Executive  Committee pursuant to the adoption of a resolution as
provided in this Paragraph. This allotment shall be set or changed by the adoption of a
resolution of the Executive Committee in an open public hearing.
SR 177 of the 2004 RS; SR 3 of 2008, 2 nd EX; SR 43 of 2012 RS; SR 3 of the
2016, 1 st EX; SR 9 of 2020.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=284088</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>