<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-404"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-404"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 404"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-404/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-404/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-404/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-404/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-404">
        <num>CCRP 404</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-404__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as otherwise provided in this Article:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-404__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The jury commission of each parish shall consist of the clerk of court or a deputy
clerk designated by him in writing to act in his stead in all matters affecting the jury
commission, and four other members, each having the qualifications set forth in Article 401
and appointed by written order of the district court, who shall serve at the court's pleasure.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-404__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Before entering upon their duties, members of the jury commission shall take an
oath to discharge their duties faithfully.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-404__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Three members of the jury commission shall constitute a quorum.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-404__subsec_A__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Meetings of the jury commission shall be open to the public.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-404__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the parish of East Baton Rouge the function of the jury commission shall be
performed by the judicial administrator of the Nineteenth Judicial District Court or by a
deputy judicial administrator designated by him in writing to act in his stead in all matters
affecting the jury commission.  The judicial administrator or his designated deputy shall have
the same powers, duties and responsibilities, and be governed by those provisions of law as
presently pertain to jury commissioners which are applicable, including the taking of an oath
to discharge their duties faithfully.  The clerk of court of the parish of East Baton Rouge shall
perform the duties and responsibilities otherwise imposed upon him by law with respect to
jury venires, shall coordinate the jury venire process, and shall receive the compensation
generally authorized for a jury commissioner.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-404__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In Orleans Parish, the jury commission shall be appointed by the judges en banc
of the Criminal District Court of the parish of Orleans, and the jury commissioners shall
serve at the pleasure of the court.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-404__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the parish of Lafourche, the function of the jury commission may be performed
by the clerk of court of the parish of Lafourche or by a deputy clerk of court designated by
him in writing to act in his stead in all matters affecting the jury commission.  The clerk of
court or his designated deputy shall have the same powers, duties, and responsibilities, and
shall be governed by applicable provisions of law pertaining to jury commissioners.  The
clerk of court of the parish of Lafourche shall perform the duties and responsibilities
otherwise imposed upon him by law with respect to jury venires, shall coordinate the jury
venire process, and shall receive the compensation generally authorized for a jury
commissioner.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-404__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the parish of Terrebonne, the function of the jury commission shall be
performed by the clerk of court of Terrebonne Parish or by a deputy clerk of court designated
by him in writing to act in his stead in all matters affecting the jury commission.  The clerk
of court or his designated deputy shall have the same powers, duties, and responsibilities, and
shall be governed by all  applicable provisions of law pertaining to jury commissioners.  The
clerk of court of Terrebonne Parish shall perform the duties and responsibilities otherwise
imposed upon him by law with respect to jury venires, shall coordinate the jury venire
process, and shall receive the compensation generally authorized for a jury commissioner.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-404__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the parish of St. Charles, the function of the jury commission shall be
performed by the clerk of court of St. Charles Parish or by a deputy clerk of court designated
by him in writing to act in his stead in all matters affecting the jury commission.  The clerk
of court or his designated deputy shall have the same powers, duties, and responsibilities, and
shall be governed by all applicable provisions of law pertaining to jury commissioners.  The
clerk of court of St. Charles Parish shall perform the duties and responsibilities otherwise
imposed upon him by law with respect to jury venires, shall coordinate the jury venire
process, and shall receive the compensation generally authorized for a jury commissioner.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-404__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the parishes of East Feliciana and West Feliciana, the function of the jury
commission shall be performed by the clerks of court of East Feliciana Parish and West
Feliciana Parish or by a deputy clerk of court designated by the respective clerk in writing
to act in his stead in all matters affecting the jury commission.  The clerk of court or his
designated deputy shall have the same powers, duties, and responsibilities, and shall be
governed by all applicable provisions of law pertaining to jury commissioners.  The clerks
of court of  East Feliciana Parish and West Feliciana Parish shall perform the duties and
responsibilities otherwise imposed upon him by law with respect to jury venires, shall
coordinate the jury venire process, and shall receive the compensation generally authorized
for a jury commissioner.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-404__subsec_H">
          <num>H.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the parishes of Caldwell, Claiborne, DeSoto, Franklin, Red River, Union, and
Webster, the function of the jury commission shall be performed by the clerks of court of
Caldwell Parish, Claiborne Parish, DeSoto Parish, Franklin Parish, Red River Parish, Union
Parish, and Webster Parish or by a deputy clerk of court designated by the respective clerk
in writing to act in his stead in all matters affecting the jury commission.  The clerk of court
or his designated deputy shall have the same powers, duties, and responsibilities and shall
be governed by all applicable provisions of law pertaining to jury commissioners.  The clerks
of court of Caldwell Parish, Claiborne Parish, DeSoto Parish, Franklin Parish, Red River
Parish, Union Parish, and Webster Parish shall perform the duties and responsibilities
otherwise imposed upon him by law with respect to jury venires, shall coordinate the jury
venire process, and shall receive the compensation generally authorized for a jury
commissioner.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-404__subsec_I">
          <num>I.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the parish of Tangipahoa, the function of the jury commission shall be
performed by the clerk of court of Tangipahoa Parish or by a deputy clerk of court designated
by the respective clerk in writing to act in his stead in all matters affecting the jury
commission.  The clerk of court or his designated deputy shall have the same powers, duties,
and responsibilities, and shall be governed by all applicable provisions of law pertaining to
jury commissioners.  The clerk of court of Tangipahoa Parish shall perform the duties and
responsibilities otherwise imposed upon him by law with respect to jury venires, shall
coordinate the jury venire process, and shall receive the compensation generally authorized
for a jury commissioner.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-404__subsec_J">
          <num>J.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the parishes of Ascension, Assumption, Jackson, and St. James, the function of
the jury commission shall be performed by the clerks of court of Ascension Parish,
Assumption Parish, Jackson Parish, and St. James Parish or by a deputy clerk of court
designated by the respective clerk in writing to act in his stead in all matters affecting the jury
commission.  The clerk of court or his designated deputy shall have the same powers, duties,
and responsibilities and shall be governed by all applicable provisions of law pertaining to
jury commissioners.  The clerks of court of Ascension Parish, Assumption Parish, Jackson
Parish, and St. James Parish shall perform the duties and responsibilities otherwise imposed
upon him by law with respect to jury venires, shall coordinate the jury venire process, and
shall receive the compensation generally authorized for a jury commissioner.
Amended by</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112505</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>