<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-544"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-544"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 544"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-544/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-544/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-544/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-544/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-544">
        <num>CHC 544</num>
        <heading>544.  Request for information; order for release</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-544__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Within fifteen days after receipt of the written request, the agency or school board
in possession of the information may apply to a court of competent jurisdiction for an order
denying the request or limiting the scope of information to be released.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-544__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Unless a court order has been timely sought pursuant to Paragraph B of this
Article,  if the agency or school board in possession of the information fails or refuses to
release such information within fifteen days after receipt of the written request, the
requesting agency shall have the right to file a rule in a court of competent jurisdiction
requiring the agency or school board in possession of the requested information to show
cause why the requested information should not be released.
D.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-544__subsec_C__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A motion or rule to show cause filed pursuant to this Article shall state the
reasons why the applying agency is seeking the release of the information, or why the
information request should be limited, restricted, or denied, as applicable, and shall describe
with particularity the information that is the subject of the application.  No names or other
personal identifying information or data regarding a child or family shall be included.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-544__subsec_C__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If no opposition to the motion or rule is filed or no appearance in opposition is
made,  it shall be deemed to be unopposed and the court shall issue an ex parte order granting
the relief sought, unless the court finds that the relief requested is clearly contrary to law or
not in the best interest of the child, in which event the court shall have the authority to
fashion such relief as it deems appropriate.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-544__subsec_C__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The court shall give preference to proceedings filed pursuant to this Chapter in
order to expedite the provision of services to children and families.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-544__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a court is presently exercising juvenile jurisdiction over the child or his family,
such court shall be the court of competent jurisdiction for the purposes of this Article.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=321982</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>