<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-972"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-972"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 972"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-972/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-972/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-972/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-972/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-972">
        <num>CCRP 972</num>
        <heading>972.  Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-972__subsec_1">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Expedited expungement&quot; means an order of expungement that a judge may sign 
pursuant to Article 999 without the individual filing a motion to expunge with the clerk of
court.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-972__subsec_2">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Expunge a record&quot; means to remove a record of arrest or conviction,
photographs, fingerprints, disposition, or any other information of any kind from public
access pursuant to the provisions of this Title.  &quot;Expunge a record&quot; does not mean destruction
of the record.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-972__subsec_3">
          <num>(3)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Expungement by redaction&quot; provides for the expungement of records of a person
who is arrested or convicted with other persons who are not entitled to expungement and
involves the removal of the name or any other identifying information of the person entitled
to the expungement and otherwise retains the records of the incident as they relate to the
other persons.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-972__subsec_4">
          <num>(4)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Interim expungement&quot; means to expunge a felony arrest from the criminal
history of a person who was convicted of a misdemeanor offense arising out of the original
felony arrest.  Only the original felony arrest may be expunged in an interim expungement.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-972__subsec_5">
          <num>(5)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Records&quot; includes any incident reports, photographs, fingerprints, disposition,
or any other such information of any kind in relation to a single arrest event in the possession
of the clerk of court, any criminal justice agency, and local and state law enforcement
agencies but shall not include DNA records.  Records shall also include records of an arrest
based on a warrant or attachment for failure to appear in court for the same offense or
offenses for which the person is seeking an expungement.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=919663</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>