<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-17-8"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-17-8"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="SRULE 17.8"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-17-8/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-17-8/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-17-8/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-17-8/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_SRULE-17-8">
        <num>SRULE 17.8</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-17-8__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>When a resolution seeking the expulsion of or disciplinary action against a
senator is introduced, a motion to indefinitely postpone shall be in order. The motion shall
require the favorable vote of a majority of the elected members for adoption. If no such
motion is adopted, the Secretary shall direct the attention of the presiding officer to the
fact of its introduction. The presiding officer then shall announce to the Senate the day
and hour when the select committee shall commence its hearings on the resolution.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-17-8__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the senator who is the subject of the resolution is present in the chamber
when the resolution is introduced, the presiding officer shall cause the Sergeant at Arms
to deliver to him a copy of the resolution and a copy of these rules, together with written
notice of the day and hour when the committee will meet to commence its hearings.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-17-8__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the senator is not present in the chamber, the presiding officer shall inquire of
the Secretary whether or not he has answered roll call or cast any vote on that legislative
day. If the Secretary informs him and the Senate that the senator has not answered roll
call or cast any vote, the presiding officer shall</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="SRULE-17-8__subsec_C__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>appoint legal counsel to represent the
absent senator before the committee at all of its proceedings and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="SRULE-17-8__subsec_C__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>direct the Sergeant at
Arms to locate the senator and deliver to him, and also to the attorney appointed by the
presiding officer, a copy of the resolution, a copy of these rules, a written notice of the
day and hour when the select committee will commence its hearings on the resolution,
and the name, address, and telephone number of the legal counsel appointed to represent
him unless and until he designates legal counsel of his own choice.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-17-8__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If, after reasonable effort, the Sergeant at Arms is unable to locate the absent
senator or for any reason is unable to deliver to him the documents herein stipulated,
delivery to the attorney appointed by the presiding officer shall be deemed sufficient
notification to the senator. If at any time during the proceedings in the committee the
absent senator selects legal counsel to represent him or if he appears in person and
notifies the committee that he does not desire to be represented, the attorney appointed by
the presiding officer shall be discharged.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-17-8__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>An attorney appointed to represent an absent senator shall be compensated in
accordance with the terms and conditions and in the amount determined by the President
as chairman of the committee. Such compensation shall be an expense of the committee,
payable out of funds available to the Senate for expenses of the Senate and committees.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=180497</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>