<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-315"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-315"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 315"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-315/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-315/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-315/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-315/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-315">
        <num>CCRP 315</num>
        <heading>315.  Schedules of bail</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-315__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Unless the bail is fixed by a schedule in accordance with this Article, the amount
of bail shall be specifically fixed in each case. In noncapital felony cases, a bail schedule
according to the offense charged may be fixed by a district court. In misdemeanor cases, a
bail schedule according to the offense charged may be fixed by a district, parish or city court
for offenses committed within its trial jurisdiction. When more than one court has trial
jurisdiction, the applicable bail schedule shall be that of the court in which the case is to be
tried.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-315__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court order setting the bail schedule shall fix the amount of bail for each
offense listed, designate the officer or officers authorized to accept the bail, and order that
bail be taken in conformity with the schedule. It may also contain a general provision
designating the amount of bail for any noncapital felony and misdemeanor not listed in the
schedule.  A copy of the schedule shall be sent to all jails, sheriff's offices, and police stations
within the judicial district, parish, or city.  A bail schedule may be revised or rescinded at any
time.  The type or form of bail shall not be sent in a bail schedule.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-315__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A person charged with the commission of an offense for which bail is fixed by
a schedule may give bail according to the schedule or demand a special order fixing bail. 
The bail amount fixed by schedule may be modified by the court in accordance with Article
319.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112433</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>