<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-887"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-887"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 887"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-887/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-887/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-887/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-887/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-887">
        <num>CCRP 887</num>
        <heading>887.  Defendant's liability for costs; suspension of costs; no advance costs</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-887__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A defendant who is convicted of an offense or is the person owing a duty of
support in a support proceeding shall be liable for all costs of the prosecution or proceeding,
whether or not costs are assessed by the court, and such costs are recoverable by the party or
parties who incurred the expense.  However, such defendant or person shall not be liable for
costs if acquitted or if the prosecution or proceeding is dismissed.  In addition, any judge of
a district court, parish court, city court, traffic court, juvenile court, family court, or
magistrate of a mayor's court within the state shall be authorized to suspend court costs.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-887__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>All processes of the court shall issue without the payment of advance costs.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-887__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition to the costs provided in Paragraph A of this Article, a person convicted
of a violation of R.S. 14:98 or 98.6, or any municipal or parochial ordinance defining the
offense of operating a motor vehicle, aircraft, watercraft, vessel, or other motorized means
of conveyance under the influence of alcohol or drugs, who was subjected to a blood, breath,
or urine analysis for alcohol or any controlled dangerous substance listed in R.S. 40:964,
Schedule I, II, III, IV, or V, shall be assessed an additional one hundred twenty-five dollars
as special costs.  Such costs shall be paid in the following manner: seventy-five dollars to the
governing authority owning the instrument used to perform the analysis, and fifty dollars to
the governing authority whose agency performed the analysis.  If the office of state police
performed or participated in a blood, breath, or urine analysis for which these costs are
assessed, that portion of the costs applicable to the office of state police shall be forwarded
to the applied technology unit within the office of state police and forwarded for disposition
in accordance with R.S. 40:1379.7.  In the event the person is unable to pay the fine when
assessed, the court may allow payment within certain time limits, based on the person's
ability to pay such costs.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-887__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition to the costs provided in Paragraphs A and C, a person convicted of a
violation of R.S. 14:98, R.S. 14:98.1, or of any municipal or parochial ordinance defining
the offense of operating a motor vehicle while under the influence of alcohol or drugs, shall
be assessed an additional fifty dollars as special costs to be used to defray expenses of
administering conditions of probation or of incarceration.  If the offender is incarcerated,
such costs shall be paid to the sheriff or other custodian of the facility in which the offender
is incarcerated.  If the offender is placed on probation as provided in R.S. 14:98(B) or (C)
or R.S. 14:98.1(D) or (E), the court may order the apportionment and payment of all or a part
of such costs to the agencies or persons responsible for administering the prescribed
substance abuse program, driver improvement program, or community service activities.  In
addition, the person convicted of a violation of R.S. 14:98, R.S. 14:98.1, or of any such
municipal or parochial ordinance shall be assessed costs of the witness fee provided by R.S.
15:255.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-887__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Repealed by</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112871</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>