<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-10-7"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-10-7"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="SRULE 10.7"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-10-7/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-10-7/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-10-7/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-10-7/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_SRULE-10-7">
        <num>SRULE 10.7</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-10-7__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each legislative instrument shall be taken up and acted upon in the proper order
of business in the order numbered until it has been reported on by committee.  After being
reported by a committee, each instrument shall take precedence in the order of its
maturing, by day; that is, instruments shall take precedence in numerical order by day of
report by committee and thereafter in the order otherwise advanced to further action by
the Senate.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-10-7__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>As each instrument is advanced to each successive order of business, it shall be
placed on the calendar in the proper order of business in numerical order with other
instruments advanced to the same order on the same day, and these numerically ordered
listings of instruments shall in turn be arranged according to the day of advancement to
said order.  Each instrument then shall be considered during that order of business in the
order listed.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-10-7__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>On any legislative day on which at the time of adjournment the Senate is
engaged in the consideration of legislative instruments on final passage, but has not
finally acted upon all instruments listed for consideration in that order of business on that
day, the Secretary shall enter on the calendar for the next legislative day under the same
order of business each such instrument upon which final action has not been taken in the
same order in which said instruments have advanced.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=180370</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>