<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-701"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-701"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 701"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-701/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-701/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-701/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-701/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-701">
        <num>CCRP 701</num>
        <heading>PROCEDURES PRIOR TO TRIAL</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-701__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The state and the defendant have the right to a speedy trial.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-701__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The time period for filing a bill of information or indictment after arrest shall be
as follows:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-701__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Paragraph
shall result in release of the defendant if, after contradictory hearing with the district attorney,
just cause for the failure is not shown.  If just cause is shown, the court shall reconsider bail
for the defendant.  Failure to institute prosecution as provided in this Subparagraph shall
result in the release of the bail obligation if, after contradictory hearing with the district
attorney, just cause for the delay is not shown.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-701__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon filing of a bill of information or indictment, the district attorney shall set
the matter for arraignment within thirty days unless just cause for a longer delay is shown.
D.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-701__subsec_C__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A motion by the defendant for a speedy trial, in order to be valid, must be
accompanied by an affidavit by defendant's counsel certifying that the defendant and his
counsel are prepared to proceed to trial within the delays set forth in this Article.  Except as
provided in Subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-701__subsec_C__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Paragraph, after the filing of a motion for a speedy trial
by the defendant and his counsel, the time period for commencement of trial shall be as
follows:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-701__subsec_C__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The trial of a defendant charged with a felony shall commence within one
hundred twenty days if he is continued in custody and within one hundred eighty days if he
is not continued in custody.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-701__subsec_C__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The trial of a defendant charged with a misdemeanor shall commence within
thirty days if he is continued in custody and within sixty days if he is not continued in
custody.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-701__subsec_C__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Failure to commence trial within the time periods provided above shall result in
the release of the defendant without bail or in the discharge of the bail obligation, if after
contradictory hearing with the district attorney, just cause for the delay is not shown.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-701__subsec_C__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>After a motion for a speedy trial has been filed by the defendant, if the defendant
files any subsequent motion which requires a contradictory hearing, the court may suspend,
in accordance with Article 580, or dismiss upon a finding of bad faith the pending speedy
trial motion.  In addition, the period of time within which the trial is required to commence,
as set forth by Article 578, may be suspended, in accordance with Article 580, from the time
that the subsequent motion is filed by the defendant until the court rules upon such motion.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-701__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Just cause&quot; as used in this Article shall include any grounds beyond the control
of the State or the Court.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-701__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A motion for a speedy trial filed by the defendant, but not verified by the affidavit
of his counsel, shall be set for contradictory hearing within thirty days.
Amended by</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112708</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>