<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1308-2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1308-2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 1308.2"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1308-2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1308-2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1308-2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1308-2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-1308-2">
        <num>CHC 1308.2</num>
        <heading>1308.2.  Conditions of rendition</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1308-2__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Before making demand that the governor of another state surrender an individual
charged criminally in this state with having failed to provide for the support of an obligee,
the governor of this state may require a prosecutor of this state to demonstrate that at least
sixty days previously the obligee had initiated proceedings for support pursuant to this
Chapter or that the proceeding would be of no avail.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1308-2__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If, under this Chapter or a law substantially similar to this Chapter, the governor
of another state makes a demand that the governor of this state surrender an individual
charged criminally in that state with having failed to provide for the support of a child or
other individual to whom a duty of support is owed, the governor may require a prosecutor
to investigate the demand and report whether a proceeding for support has been initiated or
would be effective.  If it appears that a proceeding would be effective but has not been
initiated, the governor may delay honoring the demand for a reasonable time to permit the
initiation of a proceeding.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1308-2__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a proceeding for support has been initiated and the individual whose rendition
is demanded prevails, the governor may decline to honor the demand.  If the petitioner
prevails and the individual whose rendition is demanded is subject to a support order, the
governor may decline to honor the demand if the individual is complying with the support
order.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=72857</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>