<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-17-4"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-17-4"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="SRULE 17.4"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-17-4/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-17-4/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-17-4/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-SRULE-17-4/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_SRULE-17-4">
        <num>SRULE 17.4</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-17-4__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>All meetings of the Select Committee on Discipline and Expulsion shall be held
in the Senate Chamber. Notice of meetings, insofar as practicable, shall be given in
accordance with applicable rules of the Senate governing notice of meetings of standing
committees during legislative sessions.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-17-4__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A majority of the total members of the committee shall constitute a quorum.
The affirmative vote of a majority of those present and voting, assuming a quorum, shall
be required for actions of the committee.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="SRULE-17-4__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Prior to consideration of any resolution referred to it or undertaking any
business in connection therewith, except establishing a quorum, the members of the select
committee shall subscribe to the following oath, which shall be administered by the
Secretary or, in his absence, by a person qualified to administer oaths selected by the
chairman:
&quot;I do solemnly swear (affirm) that in all things appertaining to the matters referred
to this Select Committee and contained in Senate Resolution No.___________ of
_________________, I will do impartial justice according to the Constitution and laws. I
do solemnly swear that I will support the Constitution and laws of the United States and
of this State, and that I will faithfully and impartially discharge and perform all the duties
incumbent upon me as a member of the Senate Select Committee on Discipline and
Expulsion in the aforesaid matter, according to the best of my ability and understanding,
so help me God.&quot;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=180493</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>