<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-14-2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-14-2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 14.2"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-14-2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-14-2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-14-2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-14-2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-14-2">
        <num>CCRP 14.2</num>
        <heading>14.2. Facsimile filings</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-14-2__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Until January 1, 2026, any document in a traffic or criminal action may be filed
with the clerk of court by facsimile transmission pursuant to the policy of the clerk of court.
Filing shall be deemed complete at the time that the facsimile transmission is received by the
clerk of court. No later than on the first business day after receiving a facsimile filing, the
clerk of court shall transmit to the filing party via facsimile a confirmation of receipt and
include a statement of the fees for the facsimile filing and filing of the original document.
The facsimile filing fee and transmission fee are incurred upon receipt of the facsimile filing
by the clerk of court and payable as provided in Paragraph B of this Article. The facsimile
filing shall have the same force and effect as filing the original document, if the party
complies with Paragraph B of this Article.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-14-2__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Within seven days, exclusive of legal holidays, after the clerk of court receives
the facsimile filing, all of the following shall be delivered to the clerk of court:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-14-2__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The original document identical to the facsimile filing in number of pages and
in content of each page, including any attachments, exhibits, and orders. A document that is
not identical to the facsimile filing or that includes pages not included in the facsimile filing
shall not be considered the original document.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-14-2__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The fees for the facsimile filing and filing of the original document stated on the
confirmation of receipt, if any.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-14-2__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A transmission fee of five dollars, if the defendant has not been declared indigent
by the court.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-14-2__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the filing party fails to comply with any of the requirements of Paragraph B of
this Article, the facsimile filing shall have no force or effect.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-14-2__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A court may provide by court rule for any additional requirement or provisions
for filings by facsimile transmission.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-14-2__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In keeping with the clerk's policy, each clerk of court shall make available the
necessary equipment and supplies to accommodate facsimile filing in criminal actions.
Purchases for equipment and supplies necessary to accommodate facsimile filings may be
funded from any expense fund of the office of the clerk of court as the clerks deem
appropriate.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-14-2__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon adoption of uniform filing standards by the Louisiana Clerks' Remote
Access Authority, no clerk of court shall accept a filing not in accordance with the adopted
standards.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=1387221</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>