<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-973"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-973"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 973"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-973/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-973/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-973/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-973/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-973">
        <num>CCRP 973</num>
        <heading>973.  Effect of expunged record of arrest or conviction</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-973__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>An expunged record of arrest or conviction shall be confidential and no longer
considered to be a public record and shall not be made available to any person or other entity
except for the following:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-973__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To a member of a law enforcement or criminal justice agency or prosecutor who
shall request that information in writing, certifying that the request is for the purpose of
investigating, prosecuting, or enforcing criminal law, for the purpose of any other statutorily
defined law enforcement or administrative duties, or for the purposes of the requirements of
sex offender registration and notification pursuant to the provisions of R.S. 15:540 et seq.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-973__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>On order of a court of competent jurisdiction and after a contradictory hearing
for good cause shown.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-973__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To the person whose record has been expunged or his counsel.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-973__subsec_A__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To a member of a law enforcement or criminal justice agency, prosecutor, or
judge, who requests that information in writing, certifying that the request is for the purpose
of defending a law enforcement, criminal justice agency, or prosecutor in a civil suit for
damages resulting from wrongful arrest or other civil litigation and the expunged record is
necessary to provide a proper defense.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-973__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon written request therefor and on a confidential basis, the information
contained in an expunged record may be released to the following entities that shall maintain
the confidentiality of such record:  the Office of Financial Institutions, the Louisiana State
Board of Medical Examiners, the Louisiana State Board of Nursing, the Louisiana State
Board of Dentistry, the Louisiana State Board of Examiners of Psychologists, the Louisiana
Board of Pharmacy, the Louisiana State Board of Social Work Examiners, the Emergency
Medical Services Certification Commission, Louisiana Attorney Disciplinary Board, Office
of Disciplinary Counsel, the Louisiana Supreme Court Committee on Bar Admissions, the
Louisiana Department of Insurance, the Louisiana Licensed Professional Counselors Board
of Examiners, the Louisiana State Board of Chiropractic Examiners, or any person or entity
requesting a record of all criminal arrests and convictions pursuant to R.S. 15:587.1, or as
otherwise provided by law.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-973__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as to those persons and other entities set forth in Paragraph A of this
Article, no person whose record of arrest or conviction has been expunged shall be required
to disclose to any person that he was arrested or convicted of the subject offense, or that the
record of the arrest or conviction has been expunged.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-973__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any person who fails to maintain the confidentiality of records as  required by the
provisions of this Article shall be subject to contempt proceedings.
NOTE:  Paragraph E eff. until appropriation of monies by the Legislature. See</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=919664</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>