<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-329"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-329"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 329"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-329/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-329/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-329/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-329/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-329">
        <num>CCRP 329</num>
        <heading>329.  Declaration of residence; waiver of notice</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-329__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The defendant and personal surety signing a bail undertaking shall write the
address at which each can be served and mailing address, if different, under their respective
signatures and the last four digits of their social security number.  The defendant and his
counsel may, with the court's approval, by joint affidavit filed of record in the matter in
which the bail undertaking was given, appoint his counsel as his agent to whom notice to
appear can be sent.  The appointment shall be conclusively presumed to continue until the
defendant, with court approval, files of record an affidavit revoking or changing the
appointment.  The affidavit shall include the address to which notice to appear can be sent. 
A commercial surety shall place its proper mailing address and electronic address on the face
of the power of attorney used to execute the bail undertaking.  The agent or bondsman
posting the bail undertaking shall place his proper mailing address under his signature.  A
bond forfeiture judgment shall not be denied or set aside because of the invalidity of the
information required by this Article or for the failure to include the information required by
the provisions of this Article.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-329__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>When a person who is required to sign his name or to make a declaration in
writing under the provisions of this Title swears that he cannot sign or write, the officer
authorized to receive the signature or declaration in writing may, at the request of the person,
sign for him or make for him the declaration in writing, with the same binding effect as if the
person had himself signed or himself made the declaration in writing; provided that the
declaration and signature shall be witnessed and signed by at least two competent witnesses.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-329__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>When a person who is required to sign his name or to make a declaration in
writing under the provisions of this Title indicates that he cannot speak or write the English
language, the officer authorized to receive the signature or declaration in writing may provide
either an interpreter or a written form in the person's native language, enabling him to sign
his name or make a declaration in writing.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-329__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each address provided pursuant to Paragraph A of this Article shall be
conclusively presumed to continue for all proceedings until the party providing the address
changes it by filing a written declaration in the matter for which the bail undertaking was
filed.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-329__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except for the notice required by Article 330, by signing the bond undertaking,
the defendant and his surety waive any right of notice to appear, including actual notice.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112450</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>