<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-515"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-515"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CE 515"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-515/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-515/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-515/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-515/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CE-515">
        <num>CE 515</num>
        <heading>515.  Accountant-client privilege</heading>
        <subsection eId="CE-515__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Definitions.  As used in this Article:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CE-515__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>&quot;Client&quot; is a person, including a public officer, corporation, partnership, unincorporated association, or other organization or entity, public or private, to whom professional services are rendered by an accountant, or who consults an accountant with a view to obtaining professional services from the accountant.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-515__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>&quot;Representative of the client&quot; is either of the following:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-515__subsec_A__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A person having authority to obtain professional services from an accountant, or to act on advice so obtained, on behalf of the client.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-515__subsec_A__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any other person who makes or receives a confidential communication for the purpose of effectuating representation by an accountant for the client, while acting in the scope of employment for the client.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-515__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>&quot;Accountant&quot; is the holder of a license issued pursuant to the Louisiana Accountancy Act and shall include all persons and entities within the definition of licensee in R.S. 37:73(8).</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-515__subsec_A__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>&quot;Representative of the accountant&quot; means a person engaged by the accountant to assist the accountant in the accountant's rendition of professional services.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-515__subsec_A__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>&quot;Confidential communication&quot; is any communication not intended to be disclosed to persons other than:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-515__subsec_A__subsec_5__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Those to whom disclosure is made in furtherance of obtaining or rendering professional accounting services for the client.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-515__subsec_A__subsec_5__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Those reasonably necessary for the transmission of the communication.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-515__subsec_A__subsec_5__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When special circumstances warrant, those who are present at the behest of the client and are reasonably necessary to facilitate the communication.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CE-515__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>General rule of privilege.  A client has a privilege to refuse to disclose, and to prevent another person from disclosing, a confidential communication, whether oral, written, or otherwise, made for the purpose of facilitating the rendition of professional accounting services to the client, as well as the perceptions, observations, and the like, of the mental, emotional, or physical condition of the client in connection with such a communication.  This privilege includes the protection of other confidential information or material obtained by the accountant from the client for the purpose of rendering professional services.  This privilege exists when the communication is:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CE-515__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Between the client or a representative of the client and the client's accountant or a representative of the accountant.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-515__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Between the accountant and a representative of the accountant.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-515__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>By the client or his accountant or a representative of either, to an accountant or lawyer, or representative of an accountant or lawyer, who represents another party concerning a matter of common interest.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-515__subsec_B__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Between representatives of the client or between the client and a representative of the client.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-515__subsec_B__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Among accountants and their representatives representing the same client.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-515__subsec_B__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Between representatives of the client's accountant.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CE-515__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Exceptions.  There is no privilege under this Article as to a communication:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CE-515__subsec_C__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Which was with a client now deceased relevant to an issue between parties who claim through that decedent, regardless of whether the claims are by testate or intestate succession or by transaction inter vivos.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-515__subsec_C__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Which is relevant to an issue of breach of duty by an accountant to the client or by a client to the client's accountant.
(4)</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-515__subsec_C__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Which is relevant to an issue of authenticity or capacity concerning a document which the accountant signed as a witness or notary.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-515__subsec_C__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Concerning the testimony of a representative of an accountant regarding a communication relevant to an issue of authenticity or capacity concerning a document to which the representative is a witness or notary.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-515__subsec_C__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Which is relevant to a matter of common interest between or among two or more clients if the communication was made by any of them or their representative to an accountant or his representative retained or consulted in common, when subsequently offered by one client against the other in a civil action.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-515__subsec_C__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Concerning the identity of the accountant's client or his representative, unless disclosure of the identity by the accountant or his representative would reveal either the reason for which accounting services were sought or a communication which is otherwise privileged under this Article.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-515__subsec_C__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Concerning information required to be disclosed by the standards of the public accounting profession in reporting on the examination of financial statements whose proceedings are protected from discovery pursuant to R.S. 37:86.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-515__subsec_C__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Concerning disclosures in investigations or proceedings of the State Board of Certified Public Accountants of Louisiana pursuant to the provisions of Part I of the Louisiana Accountancy Act whose proceedings are protected from discovery pursuant to R.S. 37:86.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-515__subsec_C__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Concerning disclosures in ethical investigations of an accountant conducted by private professional organizations whose proceedings are protected from discovery pursuant to R.S. 37:86 or in the course of quality or peer reviews.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-515__subsec_C__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In any domestic proceeding including the partition of community property and the settlement of claims arising from matrimonial regimes, spousal support, and child support.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CE-515__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Who may claim privilege.  The privilege may be claimed by the client, the client's agent or accountant, or the successor, trustee, or similar representative of a client that is a corporation, partnership, unincorporated association, or other organization, whether or not in existence.  The person who was the accountant or the accountant's representative at the time of the communication is presumed to have authority to claim the privilege on behalf of the client, former client, or deceased client.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CE-515__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Scope.  Nothing in this Article is intended to affect the absolute privileges against disclosure contained in R.S. 37:86(B) through (E).</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=72486</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>