<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-10"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-10"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCP 10"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-10/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-10/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-10/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-10/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCP-10">
        <num>CCP 10</num>
        <heading>10.  Jurisdiction over status</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCP-10__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A court which is otherwise competent under the laws of this state has jurisdiction
of the following actions or proceedings only under the following conditions:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-10__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An adoption proceeding in accordance with Title XII of the Children's Code, if
the surrendering parent of the child, a prospective adoptive parent, the adoptive parent or
parents, or any parent of the child has been domiciled in this state for at least eight months,
or if the child is in the custody of the Department of Children and Family Services; and an
adoption proceeding in accordance with Civil Code Article 212, if either party to the
adoption of an adult is domiciled in this state.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-10__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An emancipation proceeding if the minor is domiciled in this state.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-10__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An interdiction proceeding brought pursuant to the provisions of the Louisiana
Uniform Adult Guardianship and Protective Proceedings Jurisdiction Act.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-10__subsec_A__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A tutorship or curatorship proceeding if the minor or absentee, as the case may
be, is domiciled in this state or has property herein.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-10__subsec_A__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A proceeding to obtain the legal custody of a minor if he is domiciled in, or is in,
this state.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-10__subsec_A__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An action to annul a marriage if one or both of the parties are domiciled in this
state.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-10__subsec_A__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An action of divorce, if, at the time of filing, one or both of the spouses are
domiciled in this state.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-10__subsec_A__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Unless otherwise provided by law, an action to establish parentage and support
or to disavow parentage if the child is domiciled in or is in this state, and was either born in
this state, born out of state while its mother was domiciled in this state, or acknowledged in
this state.  However, regardless of the location of the child or its place of birth, an action to
disavow may be brought if the person seeking to disavow was domiciled in this state at the
time of conception and birth and is presumed to be its parent under the laws of this state.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-10__subsec_A__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A proceeding for support of an adult child with a disability, as provided in R.S.
9:315.22.1, if he is domiciled in, or is in, this state.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-10__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>For purposes of Subparagraphs</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-10__subsec_B__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-10__subsec_B__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of Paragraph A of this Article, if a
spouse has established and maintained a residence in a parish of this state for a period of six
months, there shall be a rebuttable presumption that he has a domicile in this state in the
parish of such residence.
Amended by</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=111104</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>