<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-305"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-305"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 305"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-305/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-305/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-305/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-305/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-305">
        <num>CHC 305</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-305__subsec_1">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <content>
            <p>When a child is fifteen years of age or older at the time of the commission of
first degree murder, second degree murder, aggravated or first degree rape, or aggravated
kidnapping, he is subject to the exclusive jurisdiction of the juvenile court until either:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-305__subsec_1__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An indictment charging one of these offenses is returned.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-305__subsec_1__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The juvenile court holds a continued custody hearing pursuant to Articles 819
and 820 and finds probable cause that he committed one of these offenses, whichever occurs
first.  During this hearing, when the child is charged with aggravated or first degree rape, the
court shall inform him that if convicted he shall register as a sex offender for life, pursuant
to Chapter 3-B of Title 15 of the Louisiana Revised Statutes of 1950.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-305__subsec_1__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The district attorney shall have the discretion to file a petition alleging any of
the offenses listed in Subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-305__subsec_1">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this Paragraph in the juvenile court or,
alternatively, to obtain an indictment.  If the child is being held in detention, the district
attorney shall file the petition or indictment in the appropriate court within sixty calendar
days after the child's arrest, unless the child waives this right.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-305__subsec_1__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Failure to institute prosecution as provided in this Subparagraph shall result in
release of the child if, after a contradictory hearing with the district attorney, just cause for
the failure is not shown. If just cause is shown, the court shall reconsider bail for the child. 
Failure to institute prosecution as provided in this Subparagraph shall result in the release of
the bail obligation if, after a contradictory hearing with the district attorney, just cause for the
delay is not shown.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-305__subsec_1__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>When the juvenile court holds a continued custody hearing pursuant to Articles
819 and 820 and finds probable cause that the child committed one of the offenses listed in
Subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-305__subsec_1">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this Paragraph, the time limitations contained in this Code are
inapplicable, and the time period for filing an indictment after arrest shall be governed by
Code of Criminal Procedure Article 701.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-305__subsec_3">
          <num>(3)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Thereafter, if an indictment is returned, the child is subject to the exclusive
jurisdiction of the appropriate court exercising criminal jurisdiction for all subsequent
procedures, including the review of bail applications, and the court exercising criminal
jurisdiction may order that the child be transferred to the appropriate adult facility for
detention prior to his trial as an adult.  If the district attorney elects to file a petition and the
child waives the right to a continued custody hearing, the child is subject to the exclusive
jurisdiction of the juvenile court for all subsequent procedures, including the review of bail
applications.
B.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-305__subsec_1">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <content>
            <p>When a child is fifteen years of age or older at the time of the commission of
any of the offenses listed in Subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-305__subsec_2">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this Paragraph, he is subject to the exclusive
jurisdiction of the juvenile court until whichever of the following occurs first:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-305__subsec_2__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An indictment charging one of the offenses listed in Subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-305__subsec_2">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this
Paragraph is returned.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-305__subsec_2__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The juvenile court holds a continued custody hearing and finds probable cause
that the child has committed any of the offenses listed in Subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-305__subsec_2">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this Paragraph
and a bill of information charging any of the offenses listed in Subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-305__subsec_2">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this
Paragraph is filed.  During this hearing, when the child is charged with forcible or second
degree rape or second degree kidnapping, the court shall inform him that if convicted he shall
register as a sex offender for life, pursuant to Chapter 3-B of Title 15 of the Louisiana
Revised Statutes of 1950.
(2)</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-305__subsec_2__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Attempted first degree murder.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-305__subsec_2__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Attempted second degree murder.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-305__subsec_2__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Manslaughter.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-305__subsec_2__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Armed robbery.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-305__subsec_2__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Aggravated burglary.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-305__subsec_2__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Forcible or second degree rape.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-305__subsec_2__subsec_g">
            <num>(g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Simple or third degree rape.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-305__subsec_2__subsec_h">
            <num>(h)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Second degree kidnapping.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-305__subsec_2__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Repealed by</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=73103</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>