<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-657-3"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-657-3"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 657.3"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-657-3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-657-3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-657-3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-657-3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-657-3">
        <num>CCRP 657.3</num>
        <heading>657.3.  Active supervised release for dangerous but not mentally ill committed persons</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-657-3__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, the state may seek
active supervised release by the Department of Public Safety and Corrections, office of
probation and parole, of a committed person based upon the committed person's continued
dangerousness even if the committed person does not have a mental illness as defined by this
Article, if both of the following conditions are satisfied:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-657-3__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The committed person was found not guilty by reason of insanity for any of the
following offenses or attempts to commit any of them:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-657-3__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any crime punishable by death or by life imprisonment.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-657-3__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any crime that is either a crime of violence as defined by R.S. 14:2(B) or a sex
offense as defined by R.S. 15:541.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-657-3__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The state proves by clear and convincing evidence that the committed person is
dangerous to others or dangerous to himself as defined by R.S. 28:2.  In satisfying its burden
of proof, the state may not rely solely upon the nature of the crime for which the committed
person was found not guilty by reason of insanity and may not rely solely upon the diagnosis
of any personality disorder.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-657-3__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon satisfaction of the criteria for active supervised release provided in
Paragraph A of this Article and consideration of any report filed pursuant to Articles 655 and
656, the court shall order the committed person to be placed on active supervised release
with any special conditions recommended to the court as well as any conditions of probation
provided in Article 895 et seq. for a period not to exceed three years.  Such period may be
extended in three-year increments upon motion of the district attorney and proof that the
committed person still satisfies the criteria for active supervised release under this Article.
Under no circumstances shall a committed person who is on active supervised release
pursuant to this Article be subject to a probation period that is longer than the maximum term
that the committed person would have received if the committed person had been convicted
of the offense.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-657-3__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>When the committed person is placed on active supervised release, the clerk of
court shall deliver a certificate to him setting forth the conditions of his release.  The
committed person shall be required to agree in writing to the conditions of his release.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-657-3__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>When the committed person has violated or is suspected of violating the
conditions of his release, the committed person may be arrested and detained pursuant to
Article 899.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-657-3__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nothing in this Article shall be construed as abrogating or negating any other
provision of this Chapter or any other provision of law relative to the continued commitment,
discharge, or conditional release of a person committed pursuant to Article 654.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-657-3__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the purposes of this Title, &quot;mental illness&quot; means a psychiatric disorder which
has substantial adverse effects on a person's ability to function and requires care and
treatment.  It does not refer to a person with, solely, an intellectual disability, or who suffers
solely from epilepsy or a substance-related or addictive disorder.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=1386661</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>