<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-313-1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-313-1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 313.1"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-313-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-313-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-313-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-313-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-313-1">
        <num>CCRP 313.1</num>
        <heading>313.1.  Detention of noncitizen defendant pending bail hearing</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-313-1__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A contradictory bail hearing, as provided for in this Article, shall be held prior to
setting bail for any person in custody who is not a citizen of the United States or not lawfully
admitted for permanent residence and who is charged with the commission of an offense in
which there was a fatality.  The hearing shall be held within five days from the date of
determination of probable cause, exclusive of weekends and legal holidays.  At the
contradictory hearing, the court shall determine the conditions of bail or whether the
defendant should be held without bail pending trial.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-313-1__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In determining whether the defendant should be admitted to bail pending trial, or
in determining the conditions of bail, the judge or magistrate shall consider the following:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-313-1__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The criminal history of the defendant.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-313-1__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The nature and seriousness of the danger to any other person or the community
that would be posed by the defendant's release.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-313-1__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Documented history or records of substance abuse by the defendant.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-313-1__subsec_B__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The seriousness of the offense charged and the weight of the evidence against the
defendant.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-313-1__subsec_B__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The risk that the defendant might flee.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-313-1__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Following the contradictory hearing and based upon the judge's or magistrate's
review of the factors set forth in Paragraph B of this Article, the judge or magistrate may
order that the defendant not be admitted to bail, upon proof by clear and convincing evidence
that the defendant might flee, or that the defendant poses an imminent danger to any other
person or the community.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-313-1__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If bail is granted, the judge or magistrate may consider, as a condition of bail, a
requirement that the defendant wear an electronic monitoring device and be placed under
active electronic monitoring and house arrest.  The conditions of the electronic monitoring
and house arrest shall be determined by the court and may include but are not limited to
limitation of the defendant's activities outside the home and a curfew.  The defendant may
be required to pay a reasonable supervision fee to the supervising agency to defray the cost
of the required electronic monitoring and house arrest.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-313-1__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any violation of the conditions of bail may be punishable by revocation of the
bond and the issuance of a bench warrant for the defendant's arrest or remanding of the
defendant to custody or a modification of the terms of bail.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=1015265</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>