<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-927"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-927"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 927"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-927/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-927/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-927/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-927/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-927">
        <num>CCRP 927</num>
        <heading>927.  Action required after filing of application; procedural objections; answer</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-927__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If an application is not dismissed pursuant to Paragraph A of this Article,  the
court shall order the custodian, through the district attorney in the parish in which the
defendant was convicted, to file any procedural objections he may have, or an answer on the
merits if there are no procedural objections, within a specified period not in excess of sixty
days.  If the district attorney waives or does not file procedural objections, the response shall
be provided to the attorney general concurrent with filing.  The court's order shall include a
copy of the application for post conviction relief and the attorney general shall have thirty
days to file objections.  If procedural objections are filed by the district attorney or the
attorney general, no answer on the merits of the claim nor any hearing on the merits shall be
ordered until such objections have been considered and rulings thereon have become final.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-927__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In any order of the court requiring a response by the district attorney or attorney
general pursuant to this Article, the court shall render specific rulings dismissing any claim
which, if established as alleged, would not entitle the petitioner to relief and shall order a
response only as to such claim or claims which, if established as alleged, would entitle the
petitioner to relief.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-927__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the court orders an answer filed, the court need not order production of the
petitioner except as provided in Article 930.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-927__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Subject to the provisions of Article 930.4(F), if the application is successive or
supplemental to a previous application, the court shall send notice to the attorney general.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-927__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the court has determined that the application cannot be summarily dismissed,
the court shall determine after an answer is filed whether an evidentiary hearing is necessary
and shall set a status conference within sixty days.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112938</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>