<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-618"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-618"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 618"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-618/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-618/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-618/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-618/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-618">
        <num>CHC 618</num>
        <heading>618.  Protective orders; content; modification; service</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-618__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court may grant any protective order or approve any consent agreement to
bring about a cessation of abuse or neglect of a party, any children, or any person alleged to
be incompetent, and the relief may include but is not limited to:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-618__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Granting the relief enumerated in Article 617.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-618__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>When there is a duty to support a party, any children, or any person alleged to be
incompetent living in the residence or household, ordering payment of temporary support or
provision of suitable housing for them.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-618__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Awarding temporary custody of or establishing temporary visitation rights and
conditions with regard to any children or person alleged to be incompetent.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-618__subsec_A__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Ordering counseling or professional medical treatment for either the defendant
or the abused or neglected person, or both.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-618__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A protective order may be rendered pursuant to this Chapter if the court has
jurisdiction over the parties and subject matter and either of the following occurs:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-618__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The parties enter into a consent agreement.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-618__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Reasonable notice and opportunity to be heard are given to the person against
whom the order is sought sufficient to protect that person's right to due process.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-618__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any protective order issued within this state or outside this state that is consistent
with Paragraph B of this Article shall be accorded full faith and credit by the courts of this
state and enforced as if it were the order of the enforcing court.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-618__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>On the motion of any party, the court, after notice to the other parties and a
hearing, may modify a prior order to exclude any item included in the prior order or to
include any item that could have been included in the prior order.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-618__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A protective order made under this Article shall be served on the person to whom
the order applies in open court at the close of the hearing, or in the same manner as a writ of
injunction.  The clerk of the issuing court shall send a copy of the order or any modification
thereof to the chief law enforcement official of the parish where the person or persons
protected by the order reside.  A copy of the protective order shall be retained on file in the
office of the chief law enforcement officer as provided herein until otherwise directed by the
court.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-618__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any final protective order or approved consent agreement shall be for a fixed
period of time, not to exceed six months, and may be extended by the court, after a
contradictory hearing, in its discretion. Such protective order or extension thereof shall be
subject to a devolutive appeal only.
G, H.  Repealed by</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=73211</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>