<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-10-1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-10-1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CA 10 1"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-10-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-10-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-10-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CA-10-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CA-10-1">
        <num>CA 10 1</num>
        <heading>REVENUE AND TAXATION</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ART. X.  REVENUE AND TAXATION
ยง1.  Taxing power; specific taxes
Section 1.  Vesting of power; restrictions; assessments and valuations.
The power of taxation shall be vested in the Legislature; shall never be
surrendered, suspended or contracted away; and all taxes shall be uniform
upon the same class of subjects throughout the territorial limits of the authority
levying the tax, and shall be levied and collected for public purposes only. No
property shall be assessed for more than its actual cash value, ascertained as
directed by law, and all tax-payers shall have the right of testing the
correctness of their assessments before the courts at the domicile of the
assessing authority, or as may be directed by law. The valuation and
classification fixed for state purposes shall be the valuation and classification
for local purposes; but the taxing authorities of the local subdivision may adopt
a different percentage of such valuation for purposes of local taxation.
Income taxes. Equal and uniform taxes may be levied upon net
incomes, and such taxes may be graduated according to the amount of the net
income. Public officials shall not be exempted. Reasonable exemptions may
be allowed.
Reforestation; valuation agreements; severance tax. For the purpose of
encouraging the reforestation of denuded lands, contracts fixing the assessed
valuation of the specific lands for the duration of the agreements, and fixing
a total severance tax based on the value of forest products when severed, three-fourths of which shall go to the parish where they are severed, and which
severance tax, for a period not to exceed fifty years from the date of such
contract, shall be in lieu of all other taxes on said forest products, are hereby
authorized under such regulations, terms and conditions as may be prescribed
by law; and the regulations, terms and conditions of such contracts as
authorized may be made retroactive by the consent of the parties as respects
the limit of taxation, on contracts theretofore entered into.
General provisions. Any legislation adopted at the regular session of the
Legislature in 1934 based upon this proposed amendment shall be validated
and ratified by the adoption of this amendment.
The said income tax schedule of rates shall never exceed the schedule
imposed in House Bill No. 339 of the Regular Session of the Legislature for
the year 1934.
Severance tax on timber. Repealed by</p>
        </content>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=67947</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>