<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CC-2322-1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CC-2322-1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CC 2322.1"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CC-2322-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CC-2322-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CC-2322-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CC-2322-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CC-2322-1">
        <num>CC 2322.1</num>
        <heading>2322.1.  Users of blood or tissue; a medical service</heading>
        <subsection eId="CC-2322-1__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The screening, procurement, processing, distribution, transfusion,
or medical use of human blood and blood components of any kind and the
transplantation or medical use of any human organ, human tissue, or approved
animal tissue by physicians, dentists, hospitals, hospital blood banks, and
nonprofit community blood banks is declared to be, for all purposes
whatsoever, the rendition of a medical service by each and every physician,
dentist, hospital, hospital blood bank, and nonprofit community blood bank
participating therein, and shall not be construed to be and is declared not to be
a sale.  Strict liability and warranties of any kind without negligence shall not
be applicable to the aforementioned who provide these medical services.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CC-2322-1__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In any action based in whole or in part on the use of blood or tissue
by a healthcare provider, to which the provisions of Paragraph A do not apply,
the plaintiff shall have the burden of proving all elements of his claim,
including a defect in the thing sold and causation of his injuries by the defect,
by a preponderance of the evidence, unaided by any presumption.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CC-2322-1__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The provisions of Paragraphs A and B are procedural and shall
apply to all alleged causes of action or other act, omission, or neglect without
regard to the date when the alleged cause of action or other act, omission, or
neglect occurred.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CC-2322-1__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>As used in this Article:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CC-2322-1__subsec_D__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>&quot;Healthcare provider&quot; includes all individuals and entities listed in
R.S. 9:2797, this Article, R.S. 40:1237.1 and R.S. 40:1231.1 whether or not
enrolled with the Patient's Compensation Fund.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CC-2322-1__subsec_D__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>&quot;The use of blood or tissue&quot; means the screening, procurement,
processing, distribution, transfusion, or any medical use of human blood, blood
products, and blood components of any kind and the transplantation or medical
use of any human organ, human or approved animal tissue, and tissue products
or tissue components by any healthcare provider.
Added by</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=109386</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>