<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-221"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-221"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 221"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-221/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-221/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-221/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-221/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-221">
        <num>CCRP 221</num>
        <heading>221.  Blood and saliva testing</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-221__subsec_1">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Following arrest if an offender is charged by bill of information
or indicted by a grand jury for intentionally exposing a police officer to AIDS
virus as defined in R.S. 14:43.5, or battery upon a police officer as defined in
R.S. 14:34.2, the police officer may be tested to determine whether the police
officer is infected with a sexually transmitted disease, or is infected with
acquired immune deficiency syndrome (AIDS), the human immunodeficiency
virus (HIV), HIV-1 antibodies, or any other probable causative agent of AIDS,
or other infectious disease resulting from this exposure, or viral hepatitis.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-221__subsec_2">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For purposes of this Article, &quot;police officer&quot; means a commissioned
police officer, sheriff, deputy sheriff, marshal, deputy marshal, correctional
officer, constable, wildlife enforcement agent, and probation and parole
officer.
B.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-221__subsec_1">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If testing is requested by the police officer, as provided in
Paragraph A of this Article, the testing shall be performed at a state hospital
or other facility as determined by the Louisiana Department of Health or as
provided by law.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-221__subsec_2">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the police officer tested under the provisions of this Paragraph
tests positive for AIDS, HIV, HIV-1 antibodies, or any other probable
causative agent of AIDS, viral hepatitis, or other infectious disease, the police
officer, upon request, shall be provided with the following services:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-221__subsec_2__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Counseling regarding HIV, viral hepatitis, or other infectious
disease.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-221__subsec_2__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Referral to appropriate health care and support services.  These
services shall be provided in accordance with applicable state law and the
regulations governing the specific programs under which the services are to be
provided.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-221__subsec_3">
          <num>(3)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The cost associated with this testing and services shall be paid by
the employing law enforcement agency of the police officer.  The agency may
seek reimbursement for these expenses from the offender.
C.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-221__subsec_1">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the police officer tested under the provisions of Paragraph B
tests positive for AIDS, HIV, HIV-1 antibodies, or any other probable
causative agent of AIDS, viral hepatitis, or other infectious disease, then the
offender who may have exposed the officer shall submit to a test designed to
determine whether the offender is infected with a sexually transmitted disease,
or is infected with acquired immune deficiency syndrome (AIDS), the human
immunodeficiency virus (HIV), HIV-1 antibodies, or any other probable
causative agent of AIDS, viral hepatitis, or other infectious disease.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-221__subsec_2">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The procedure or test shall be performed by a qualified physician
or other qualified person who shall report any positive result to the chief
administrator of the jail or correctional facility, if the offender is incarcerated,
and shall also notify the offender, regardless of the results.  If the offender is
incarcerated, the test may be administered at the place of incarceration or the
offender may be transferred to an appropriate testing facility and returned to
incarceration following the testing procedure.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-221__subsec_3">
          <num>(3)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the offender tested under the provisions of this Paragraph tests
positive for AIDS, HIV, HIV-1 antibodies, or any other probable causative
agent of AIDS, viral hepatitis, or other infectious disease, upon request, he
shall be provided with the following services:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-221__subsec_3__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Counseling regarding HIV, viral hepatitis, or other infectious
disease.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-221__subsec_3__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Referral to appropriate health care and support services.  These
services shall be provided in accordance with applicable state law and the
regulations governing the specific programs under which the services are to be
provided.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-221__subsec_4">
          <num>(4)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The costs associated with this testing shall be paid by the offender.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112374</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>