<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1025-4"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1025-4"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 1025.4"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1025-4/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1025-4/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1025-4/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1025-4/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-1025-4">
        <num>CHC 1025.4</num>
        <heading>1025.4.  Prehearing and scheduling conference; order</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1025-4__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>At the appearance, on its own motion or on motion of counsel, the court shall
direct counsel for the petitioner, for the parents, and for the child to appear before it for a
conference to consider the following:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1025-4__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The consideration of alternatives to formal court proceedings when their use is
appropriate and in the best interest of the child.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1025-4__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Efforts to identify and locate an unidentified or absent parent and relatives or
other individuals willing and able to offer a wholesome and stable home for the child.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1025-4__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Whether there is an issue of paternity requiring the issuance of an order for
immediate blood or tissue sampling in accordance with the provisions of R.S. 9:396 et seq.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1025-4__subsec_A__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The simplification of the issues including the elimination of frivolous claims or
defenses.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1025-4__subsec_A__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The necessity or desirability of amendments to the petition.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1025-4__subsec_A__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>What material facts and issues exist without substantial controversy, and what
material facts and issues are actually and in good faith controverted.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1025-4__subsec_A__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Proof, stipulations regarding the authenticity of documents, and advance rulings
from the court on the admissibility of evidence.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1025-4__subsec_A__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Limitations or restrictions on or regulation of the use of expert testimony under
Louisiana Code of Evidence Article 702.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1025-4__subsec_A__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The control and scheduling of discovery.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1025-4__subsec_A__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The identification of witnesses, documents, and exhibits.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1025-4__subsec_A__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Such other matters as may aid in the disposition of the action.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1025-4__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court shall render an order which recites the action taken at the conference,
the amendments allowed to the petition, and the agreements made by the parties as to any of
the matters considered, and which limits the issues for adjudication to those not disposed of
by admissions or agreements of counsel.  Such order controls the subsequent course of the
action, unless modified at the termination of parental rights hearing to prevent manifest
injustice.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1025-4__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a party's counsel fails to obey a prehearing order, or to appear at the prehearing
and scheduling conference, or is substantially unprepared to participate in the conference, or
fails to participate in good faith, the court, upon its own motion or on the motion of a party,
after hearing, may make such orders as are just, including orders provided in Code of Civil
Procedure Article 1471(2), (3), and (4).  In lieu of or in addition to any other sanction, the
court may require the party or his counsel, or both, to pay the reasonable expenses incurred
by noncompliance with this Paragraph, including attorney fees.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=72555</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>