<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1306-11"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1306-11"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 1306.11"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1306-11/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1306-11/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1306-11/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1306-11/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-1306-11">
        <num>CHC 1306.11</num>
        <heading>1306.11.  Modification of child support order of another state</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1306-11__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If Article 1306.13 does not apply, upon petition a tribunal of this state may
modify a child support order issued in another state which is registered in this state if, after
notice and hearing, the tribunal finds that:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1306-11__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The following requirements are met:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-1306-11__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Neither the child, nor the obligee who is an individual, nor the obligor resides in
the issuing state.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-1306-11__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A petitioner who is a nonresident of this state seeks modification; and</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-1306-11__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The respondent is subject to the personal jurisdiction of the  tribunal of this state;
or</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1306-11__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>This state is the residence of the child, or a party who is an individual is subject
to the personal jurisdiction of the tribunal of this state, and all of the parties who are
individuals have filed consents in a record in the issuing tribunal for a tribunal of this state
to modify the support order and assume continuing, exclusive jurisdiction.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1306-11__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Modification of a registered child support order is subject to the same
requirements, procedures, and defenses that apply to the modification of an order issued by
a tribunal of this state and the order may be enforced and satisfied in the same manner.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1306-11__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A tribunal of this state may not modify any aspect of a child support order that
may not be modified under the law of the issuing state, including the duration of the
obligation of support.  If two or more tribunals have issued child support orders for the same
obligor and same child, the order that controls and must be so recognized under Article
1302.7 establishes the aspects of the support order which are nonmodifiable.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1306-11__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In a proceeding to modify a child support order, the law of the state that is
determined to have issued the controlling order governs the duration of the obligation of
support. The obligor's fulfillment of the duty of support established by that order precludes
imposition of a further obligation of support by a tribunal of this state.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1306-11__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>On issuance of an order by a tribunal of this state modifying a child support order
issued in another state, the tribunal of this state becomes the tribunal having continuing,
exclusive jurisdiction.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1306-11__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding Paragraphs A through E of this Article and Article 1302.1(B),
a tribunal of this state retains jurisdiction to modify an order issued by a tribunal of this state
if:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1306-11__subsec_F__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>One party resides in another state; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1306-11__subsec_F__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The other party resides outside the United States.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=72841</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>