<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-811-1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-811-1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 811.1"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-811-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-811-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-811-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-811-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-811-1">
        <num>CHC 811.1</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-811-1__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The juvenile court, district attorneys, and law enforcement agencies shall provide
the following services to victims of alleged delinquent acts, providing the victim reported the
act to law enforcement authorities within seventy-two hours of its occurrence or discovery,
unless extenuating circumstances exist for later reporting:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-811-1__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The district attorney shall, whenever practical, inform the victim or his legal
representative of judicial proceedings relating to their case including:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-811-1__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The taking into custody of the alleged delinquent.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-811-1__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Adjudication hearings and disposition hearings relating to the alleged delinquent.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-811-1__subsec_A__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The release pending adjudication after a continued custody hearing whenever an
alleged delinquent is accused of a violent offense, such as attempted murder, rape, or a crime
against another child.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-811-1__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The district attorney shall, whenever practical, notify the victim or his legal
representative if a court proceeding to which he has been subpoenaed will not go on as
scheduled, in order to save the person an unnecessary trip to court.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-811-1__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The district attorney shall notify the victim or his legal representative whenever
he is notified that a child accused of a violent offense such as attempted murder, rape, or a
crime against another child, has escaped from lawful confinement or has been released in
accordance with Chapter 6 of this Title, and whenever a child committed to the Department
of Public Safety and Corrections has escaped or has been released from a secure institution. 
The district attorney shall also inform the victim that the sheriff shall provide information
relative to victim assistance.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-811-1__subsec_A__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The sheriff shall inform the victim or his legal representative of financial
assistance, fees, or other social services available as a result of being a victim of a crime,
including information on how to apply for the financial assistance and services.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-811-1__subsec_A__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The court should provide, whenever possible, a secure waiting area during court
proceedings that does not require victims and their legal representatives to be in close
proximity to accused children and their families and friends.  The juvenile court shall provide
a secure waiting area in cases involving violent crime.  The victim, or the designated member
of the victim's family in a case involving homicide or injury to a minor, shall have the right
to be present at all court proceedings and, whenever practical, be allowed to observe the
proceedings by simultaneous transmission through audiovisual equipment, if such technology
is available in the courtroom.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-811-1__subsec_A__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>All judicial and law enforcement agencies shall expeditiously return any stolen
or other personal property to victims when no longer needed as evidence.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-811-1__subsec_A__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The appropriate law enforcement agency shall ensure that the victim receives
emergency, social, and medical services as soon as possible.  The appropriate law
enforcement agency shall also distribute to the victim, or to the family of a homicide victim,
a crime victim's brochure prepared by the Crime Victims Reparations Board as provided in
R.S. 46:1844(T), and supplemented as necessary by the district attorney with victim
information specific to the parish in which the delinquent act is alleged to have occurred, as
provided in R.S. 46:1844(A).</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-811-1__subsec_A__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>All law enforcement agencies shall provide a private setting for all interviewing
of victims of crime.  &quot;Private setting&quot; shall mean an enclosed room from which the occupants
are not visible or otherwise identifiable and whose conversations cannot be heard from
outside such room.  Only those persons directly and immediately related to the interviewing
of the victim, specifically the victim, a social worker, psychologist, or other professional, the
victim advocate designated by the sheriff's office, or a representative from a not-for-profit
victim service organization, including but not limited to rape crisis centers, domestic
violence advocacy groups, and alcohol abuse or substance abuse groups providing emotional
support to the victim, shall be present, unless the victim requests the exclusion of such
person from the interview, and, where appropriate, the parent or parents of the victim.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-811-1__subsec_A__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The victim or the family of the victim shall have the right to retain counsel to
confer with law enforcement and judicial  agencies on the disposition of the victim's case. 
The prosecutor, in accordance with the provisions of Code of Criminal Procedure Article 63,
may confer with the counsel retained by the victim or victim's family in the prosecution of
the case.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-811-1__subsec_A__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The district attorney shall, whenever practical, consult the victim or the
designated member of the victim's family in the case of homicide or injury to a minor in
order to obtain their view regarding:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-811-1__subsec_A__subsec_10__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The disposition of the delinquency case by dismissal, plea bargaining, or
adjudication hearing.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-811-1__subsec_A__subsec_10__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The use of available disposition alternatives such as placement in secure
detention, probation, community service, and the payment of restitution to the victim.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-811-1__subsec_A__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The victim or a member of the victim's family may file a victim notice form as
provided in R.S. 46:1842.  Upon filing of a victim notice form by a victim or a family
member, it shall be the duty of the Department of Public Safety and Corrections to notify the
victim or family member by certified mail of appeal or release at the time of such appeal,
discharge, or parole of a delinquent named in that form.  Such form shall be included in the
delinquent's commitment documents to be delivered to the state training facility where such
delinquent has been confined or transferred.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-811-1__subsec_A__subsec_12">
            <num>(12)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The victim or witness who so requests shall be assisted by judicial and law
enforcement agencies in informing employers that the need for victim and witness
cooperation in the prosecution of the case may necessitate absence of the victim or witness
from work.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-811-1__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The family members of all homicide victims shall be afforded all of the rights
under this Article accruing to victims.  Communication with the appropriate law enforcement
or judicial agencies concerning the rights of the victim's family members shall be made
through a designated family member.  A designated family member is a member of the
victim's family designated by a majority of the victim's family members to make such
communications.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-811-1__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>No order or disposition shall be invalidated because of failure to comply with the
provisions of this Article.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-811-1__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The juvenile court, the district attorney, the sheriff, and law enforcement agencies
are exempt from the requirements of this Section in any case in which either:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-811-1__subsec_D__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The victim has failed to provide a current address.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-811-1__subsec_D__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The victim refuses the services offered.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-811-1__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nothing in this Article shall be construed as creating a right of appeal on behalf
of any person nor as creating a cause of action on behalf of any person against any public
employee, office, or department responsible for the provision of services set forth in this
Article.
F.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-811-1__subsec_E__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In order to protect the identity and provide for the safety and welfare of juvenile
crime victims under the age of eighteen years, all public officials and officers and public
agencies, including but not limited to all law enforcement agencies, sheriffs, district
attorneys, judicial officers, clerks of court, and the Department of Children and Family
Services or any division thereof, shall not publicly disclose the name, address, or identity of
a juvenile victim of crime who at the time of the commission of the offense is under eighteen
years of age.  The public disclosure of the name of the juvenile crime victim by any public
official or officer or public agency is not prohibited by this Subparagraph when the crime
resulted in the death of the victim.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-811-1__subsec_E__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, all public officials,
officers, and public agencies, including but not limited to all law enforcement agencies,
sheriffs, district attorneys, judicial officers, clerks of court, and the Department of Children
and Family Services or any division thereof, charged with the responsibility of knowing the
name, address, and identity of juvenile crime victims as a necessary part of their duties shall
have full and complete access to this information regarding a juvenile crime victim, and they
may lawfully utilize initials, abbreviations, or other forms of indefinite descriptions on all
public documents used in the performance of their duties to whatever extent they deem
necessary, to prevent the public disclosure of the name, address, or identity of a juvenile
victim of crime under the age of eighteen years.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-811-1__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Repealed by</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=73400</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>