<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-925"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-925"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 925"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-925/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-925/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-925/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-925/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-925">
        <num>CHC 925</num>
        <heading>925.  Expungement and sealing; forms</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-925__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The following form shall be used for filing a motion, setting a contradictory
hearing, and ordering the expungement and sealing of records and reports:
MOTION FOR EXPUNGEMENT AND SEALING
NOW INTO COURT COMES _______________________________, in proper
person or through undersigned counsel, and herein moves this Honorable Court:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-925__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To order the expungement and sealing of all records and reports, including but
not limited to the record of arrest and order of disposition concerning the below-described
conduct or condition, and directing all officials, agencies, institutions, boards, and systems,
including their employees, agents, consultants, and special committees, to expunge and seal
any record, in any form, concerning the arrest of mover, and any other photographic,
fingerprint, DNA, or any other information of any and all kinds or descriptions; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-925__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To direct each agency and law enforcement office having any such records,
including but not limited to the above named entities, to file a sworn affidavit with the clerk
of court to the effect that such records have been expunged and sealed and that no notation
or reference has been retained in any central depository which could or might lead to the
inference that the expunged and sealed record was ever on file with that agency or law
enforcement office, except as otherwise specifically provided by law.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-925__subsec_I">
          <num>I.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Full name of mover:
_________________________________________________________________
SEX: {   } Male    {   } FemaleSocial Security Number:_________
Race/Ethnicity: ____________Date of Birth: ____/____/_____
Address: Street: ______________________________________ Apt. #: _______
City/State: __________________________________________Zip: __________
NOTE: A separate page shall be completed for EACH of the charges for
which expungement and sealing is sought.  Failure to provide ALL of the
requested information may result in dismissal of the motion for insufficiency.
II.
Offense Report #: ___________________Offense charged:________________
Date of Arrest: ____/____/________
Arresting Agency: ___________________________________________________
City/ Parish of Arrest: ________________________________________________
III.
Action taken: (Check appropriate action and insert date)
{   } Charges not filed
{   } Charges refused on____/____/________
{   } Informal Adjustment Agreement completed on____/____/________
{   } Adjudicated on ____/____/________
{   } Dismissed on ____/____/________
{   } Continued without date on____/____/________
IV.
Court Docket and Complaint #: __________________, # _____________</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-925__subsec_V">
          <num>V.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Authority for motion (Check one only)
{   } This matter did not result in adjudication.
{   } This matter resulted in a Families in Need of Services or delinquency
adjudication.
AND the court which had exercised juvenile jurisdiction has ceased to exercise such
in accordance with Children's Code Article 313.
AND the adjudication was not for murder, manslaughter, an offense requiring
registration as a sex offender under R.S. 15:542, kidnapping, or armed robbery.
AND mover has no adult felony conviction and no adult conviction for a
misdemeanor against a person involving a firearm.
AND mover has no pending indictment or bill of information against him.
WHEREFORE, mover prays that after due proceedings are had, there be an order
herein in favor of mover, ordering the clerk of court and all other agencies, offices or
organizations to expunge and seal their records or reports concerning the conduct or
condition of mover as a child as more fully described herein.
Respectfully submitted,
_________________________________________
Name of Mover or Attorney
_________________________________________
Address
_________________________________________
City/State/Zip
_________________________________________
Phone
ORDER
CONSIDERING the above and foregoing:
IT IS ORDERED that a contradictory hearing be and is hereby set for the ______ day
of _________________, 20____ at _________ in Section ________.
_________________, Louisiana this ______ day of __________________20___.
____________________________________
JUDGE
Note: Please add any additional necessary agencies below.
PLEASE SERVE:
Parish of___________________
District Attorney________________
Clerk of Court _________________
Sheriff________________________
Bureau of Criminal Identification and Information
Attn: Expungements
7919 Independence Blvd.
Baton Rouge, Louisiana   70806
and
_____________________________ __________________________________
Name of Agency Name of Agency
_________________________________ ___________</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-925__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The following form shall be used to order the expungement and sealing:
ORDER OF EXPUNGEMENT AND SEALING
CONSIDERING the Motion for Expungement and Sealing and the evidence adduced
as to the following described matter, and as to the following described conduct or conditions:
Item #s
Offense(s) Charged
Date of Arrest(s)
Arresting Agencies
IT IS ORDERED that the clerk of court expunge and seal all records and reports, in
any medium, including but not limited to pleadings, exhibits, reports, minute entries,
correspondence, and all other documents.  The court may maintain a confidential record of
the fact of an adjudication, which may be released only upon written motion of a court
exercising criminal jurisdiction over the mover herein and then only for purposes authorized
by the Code of Criminal Procedure.
IT IS FURTHER ORDERED that all officials, agencies, institutions, boards, systems,
and law enforcement officers and their employees, agents, and consultants expunge and seal
all records and reports, in any form, concerning the above-described matter, and any other
photographic, fingerprint, DNA, or any other information of any and all kinds and
descriptions.  The custodian of records and reports of the agency or office may maintain a
copy of this order.  However, the custodian shall not disclose to anyone the fact that an order
is maintained or that the expunged and sealed records or reports previously existed except
upon written order of the court.
IT IS FURTHER ORDERED that each agency and law enforcement office herein
served and having any records or reports of the conduct or condition file a sworn affidavit
with the clerk of court to the effect that the records and reports have been expunged and
sealed and that no notation or references have been retained in any central depository which
could or might lead to the inference that any report or record was on file with the agency or
law enforcement office served, which affidavit shall be filed with t</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=1054558</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>