<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-896"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-896"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 896"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-896/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-896/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-896/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-896/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-896">
        <num>CHC 896</num>
        <heading>896.  Deferred dispositional agreement</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-896__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>At any time after the entry of an adjudication order, the court may, on motion of
the district attorney or of counsel for the child, suspend further proceedings and place the
child on supervised or unsupervised probation, with or without any of the conditions
authorized by Article 897(B)</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-896__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>or Article 899(B)(1).</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-896__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The child and his parent must consent to this special type of disposition.  If the
child has waived counsel, the court must advise the child and his parent concerning the
consequences of a deferred dispositional agreement and of the child's right to have a
disposition imposed by the court in accordance with Articles 897 through 900.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-896__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A deferred dispositional agreement order shall comply with all the requirements
of Article 903.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-896__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A deferred dispositional agreement shall remain in force for six months unless
the child is discharged sooner by the court.  Upon application of the district attorney or by
any agency supervising the child made before the expiration of the six-month period, a
deferred dispositional agreement order may be extended by the court for an additional period
not to exceed six months, or for such period in which the child is a full-time participant in
a juvenile drug court program operated by a court of this state, whichever period is longer.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-896__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If prior to the expiration of the order a new petition alleging the commission of
a delinquent act is filed against the child, or the child otherwise fails to fulfill the express
terms and conditions of the order, the court may proceed to impose any disposition
authorized by this Title and the child may be held accountable as if the deferred dispositional
agreement order had never been entered.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-896__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the child satisfactorily completes the court ordered period of supervision, the
court shall discharge the child from any further supervision or conditions, set aside the
adjudication, and dismiss the petition with prejudice.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-896__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Pursuant to the provisions of this Article, the court has the authority to utilize or
initiate a teen or youth court program and may assess a fee to a participant in the program to
offset costs.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-896__subsec_H">
          <num>H.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, a child shall not be eligible
for a deferred dispositional agreement as provided in this Article if the child has been
convicted of a crime of violence as defined in R.S. 14:2(B).</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=73487</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>