<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-556-1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-556-1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 556.1"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-556-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-556-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-556-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-556-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-556-1">
        <num>CCRP 556.1</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-556-1__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In a felony case, the court shall not accept a plea of guilty or nolo contendere
without first addressing the defendant personally in open court and informing him of, and
determining that he understands, all of the following:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-556-1__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The nature of the charge to which the plea is offered, the mandatory minimum
penalty provided by law, if any, and the maximum possible penalty provided by law.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-556-1__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the defendant is not represented by an attorney, that he has the right to be
represented by an attorney at every stage of the proceeding against him and, if financially
unable to employ counsel, one will be appointed to represent him.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-556-1__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>That he has the right to plead not guilty or to persist in that plea if it has already
been made, and that he has the right to be tried by a jury and at that trial has the right to the
assistance of counsel, the right to confront and cross-examine witnesses against him, and the
right not to be compelled to incriminate himself.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-556-1__subsec_A__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>That if he pleads guilty or nolo contendere there will not be a further trial of any
kind, so that by pleading guilty or nolo contendere he waives the right to a trial.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-556-1__subsec_A__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>That if he pleads guilty or nolo contendere, he may be subject to additional
consequences or waivers of constitutional rights in the following areas as a result of his plea
to be informed as follows:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-556-1__subsec_A__subsec_5__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Defense counsel or the court shall inform him regarding:</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-556-1__subsec_A__subsec_5__subsec_i">
              <num>(i)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Potential deportation, for a person who is not a United States citizen.
(ii)  The right to vote.
(iii)  The right to bear arms.
(iv)  The right to due process.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-556-1__subsec_A__subsec_5__subsec_v">
              <num>(v)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The right to equal protection.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-556-1__subsec_A__subsec_5__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Defense counsel or the court may inform him of additional direct or potential
consequences impacting the following:</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-556-1__subsec_A__subsec_5__subsec_i">
              <num>(i)</num>
              <content>
                <p>College admissions and financial aid.
(ii)  Public housing benefits.
(iii)  Employment and licensing restrictions.
(iv)  Potential sentencing as a habitual offender.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-556-1__subsec_A__subsec_5__subsec_v">
              <num>(v)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Standard of proof for probation or parole revocations.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-556-1__subsec_A__subsec_5__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Failure to adhere to the provisions of Subsubparagraphs</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-556-1__subsec_A__subsec_5__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>and</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-556-1__subsec_A__subsec_5__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this
Subparagraph shall not be considered an error, defect, irregularity, or variance affecting the
substantial rights of the accused and does not constitute grounds for reversal pursuant to
Article 921.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-556-1__subsec_A__subsec_5__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>It shall be sufficient to utilize a form which conveys this information to the client
and the form shall constitute prima facie evidence that the content was conveyed and
understood.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-556-1__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In a felony case, the court shall not accept a plea of guilty or nolo contendere
without first addressing the defendant personally in open court and determining that the plea
is voluntary and not the result of force or threats or of promises apart from a plea agreement.
C.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-556-1__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The court shall also inquire as to whether the defendant's willingness to plead
guilty or nolo contendere results from prior discussions between the district attorney and the
defendant or his attorney.  If a plea agreement has been reached by the parties, the court, on
the record, shall require the disclosure of the agreement in open court or, on a showing of
good cause, in camera, at the time the plea is offered.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-556-1__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The court shall further inquire of the defendant and his attorney whether the
defendant has been informed of all plea offers made by the state.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-556-1__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In a felony case a verbatim record shall be made of the proceedings at which the
defendant enters a plea of guilty or nolo contendere.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-556-1__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any variance from the procedures required by this Article which does not affect
substantial rights of the accused shall not invalidate the plea.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-556-1__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nothing in this Article prohibits the court, by local rule, from providing for a
defendant's appearance at the entry of his plea of guilty or nolo contendere by simultaneous
audio-visual transmission in accordance with the provisions of Article 562.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112613</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>