<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1301-2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1301-2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 1301.2"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1301-2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1301-2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1301-2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1301-2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-1301-2">
        <num>CHC 1301.2</num>
        <heading>1301.2.  Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_1">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Child&quot; means an individual, whether over or under the age of majority, who is
or is alleged to be owed a duty of support by the individual's parent or who is or is alleged
to be the beneficiary of a support order directed to the parent.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_2">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot; Child support order&quot; means a support order for a child, including a child who
has attained the age of majority under the law of the issuing state or foreign country.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_3">
          <num>(3)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Convention&quot; means the Convention on the International Recovery of Child
Support and Other Forms of Family Maintenance, concluded at The Hague on November 23,
2007.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_4">
          <num>(4)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Duty of support&quot; means an obligation imposed or imposable by law to provide
support for a child, spouse, or former spouse, including an unsatisfied obligation to provide
support.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_5">
          <num>(5)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Foreign country&quot; means a country, including a political subdivision thereof,
other than the United States, that authorizes the issuance of support orders and:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_5__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Which has been declared under the law of the United States to be a foreign
reciprocating country;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_5__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Which has established a reciprocal arrangement for child support with this state
as provided in Article 1303.8;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_5__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Which has enacted a law or established procedures for the issuance and
enforcement of support orders which are substantially similar to the procedures under this
Chapter; or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_5__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In which the Convention is in full force with respect to the United States.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_6">
          <num>(6)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Foreign support order&quot; means a support order of a foreign tribunal.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_7">
          <num>(7)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Foreign tribunal&quot; means a court, administrative agency, or quasi-judicial entity
of a foreign country which is authorized to establish, enforce, or modify support orders or
to determine parentage of a child. The term includes a competent authority under the
Convention.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_8">
          <num>(8)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Home state&quot; means the state or foreign country in which a child lived with a
parent or a person acting as parent for at least six consecutive months immediately preceding
the time of filing of a petition or comparable pleading for support and, if a child is less than
six months old, the state or foreign country in which the child lived from birth with any of
them.  A period of temporary absence of any of them is counted as part of the six-month or
other period.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_9">
          <num>(9)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Income&quot; includes earnings or other periodic entitlements to money from any
source and any other property subject to withholding for support under the law of this state.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_10">
          <num>(10)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Income-withholding order&quot; means an order or other legal process directed to
an obligor's employer or other debtor, as defined by the income-withholding law of this state,
to withhold support from the income of the obligor.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_11">
          <num>(11)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Initiating tribunal&quot; means the tribunal of a state or foreign country from which
a petition or comparable pleading is forwarded or in which a petition or comparable pleading
is filed for forwarding to another state or foreign country.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_12">
          <num>(12)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Issuing foreign country&quot; means the foreign country in which a tribunal issues
a support order or a judgment determining parentage of a child.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_13">
          <num>(13)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Issuing state&quot; means the state in which a tribunal issues a support order or a
judgment determining parentage of a child.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_14">
          <num>(14)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Issuing tribunal&quot; means the tribunal of a state or foreign country that issues a
support order or a judgment determining parentage of a child.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_15">
          <num>(15)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Law&quot; includes decisional and statutory law and rules and regulations having
the force of law.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_16">
          <num>(16)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Obligee&quot; means:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_16__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An individual to whom a duty of support is or is alleged to be owed or in whose
favor a support order or a judgment determining parentage of a child has been issued;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_16__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A foreign country, state or political subdivision of a state to which the rights
under a duty of support or support order have been assigned or which has independent claims
based on financial assistance provided to an individual obligee in place of child support;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_16__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An individual seeking a judgment determining parentage of the individual's child;
or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_16__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person that is a creditor in a proceeding under Section 7.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_17">
          <num>(17)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Obligor&quot; means an individual or the estate of a decedent who:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_17__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Owes or is alleged to owe a duty of support;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_17__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Is alleged, but has not been adjudicated to be a parent of a child;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_17__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Is liable under a support order; or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_17__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Is a debtor in a proceeding under Section 7.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_18">
          <num>(18)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Outside this state&quot; means a location in another state or a country other than the
United States, whether or not the country is a foreign country.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_19">
          <num>(19)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Person&quot; means an individual, corporation, business trust, estate, trust,
partnership, limited liability company, association, joint venture, public corporation,
government or governmental subdivision, agency, or instrumentality, or any other legal or
commercial entity.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_20">
          <num>(20)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Record&quot; means information that is inscribed on a tangible medium or that is
stored in an electronic or other medium and is retrievable in perceivable form.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_21">
          <num>(21)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Register&quot; means to record or file in a tribunal of this state a support order or
judgment determining parentage of a child issued in another state or a foreign country.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_22">
          <num>(22)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Registering tribunal&quot; means a tribunal in which a support order or judgment
determining parentage of a child is registered.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_23">
          <num>(23)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Responding state&quot; means a state in which a petition or comparable pleading
for support or to determine parentage of a child is filed or to which a petition or comparable
pleading is forwarded for filing from another state or a foreign country.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_24">
          <num>(24)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Responding tribunal&quot; means the authorized tribunal in a responding state or
foreign country.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_25">
          <num>(25)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Spousal support order&quot; means a support order for a spouse or former spouse
of the obligor.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_26">
          <num>(26)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;State&quot; means a state of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto
Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, or any territory or insular possession under the
jurisdiction of the United States.  The term includes an Indian nation or tribe.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_27">
          <num>(27)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Support enforcement agency&quot; means a public official, governmental entity, or
private agency authorized to:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_27__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Seek enforcement of support orders or laws relating to the duty of support;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_27__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Seek establishment or modification of child support;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_27__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Request determination of parentage of a child;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_27__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Attempt to locate obligors or their assets; or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_27__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Request determination of the controlling child support order.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_28">
          <num>(28)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Support order&quot; means a judgment, decree, order, decision, or directive, whether
temporary, final, or subject to modification, issued in a state or foreign country for the benefit
of a child, a spouse, or a former spouse, which provides for monetary support, health care,
arrearages, retroactive support, or reimbursement for financial assistance provided to an
individual obligee in place of child support. The term may include related costs and fees,
interest, income withholding, automatic adjustment, reasonable attorney fees, and other
relief.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1301-2__subsec_29">
          <num>(29)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Tribunal&quot; means a court, administrative agency, or quasi judicial entity
authorized to establish, enforce, or modify support orders or to determine parentage of a
child.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=72794</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>