<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-905-5-1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-905-5-1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 905.5.1"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-905-5-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-905-5-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-905-5-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-905-5-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-905-5-1">
        <num>CCRP 905.5.1</num>
        <heading>905.5.1.  Intellectual disability</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-905-5-1__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provisions of law to the contrary, no person with an
intellectual disability shall be subjected to a sentence of death.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-905-5-1__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any capital defendant who claims to have an intellectual disability shall file
written notice thereof within the time period for filing of pretrial motions as provided by
Article 521 of this Code.
C.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-905-5-1__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any defendant in a capital case making a claim of  intellectual disability shall
prove the allegation by a preponderance of the evidence.  The jury shall try the issue of
intellectual disability of a capital defendant during the capital sentencing hearing unless the
state and the defendant agree that the issue is to be tried by the judge.  If the state and the
defendant agree, the issue of intellectual disability of a capital defendant may be tried prior
to trial by the judge alone.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-905-5-1__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any pretrial determination by the judge that a defendant does not have an
intellectual disability shall not preclude the defendant from raising the issue at the penalty
phase, nor shall it preclude any instruction to the jury pursuant to this Article.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-905-5-1__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Once the issue of intellectual disability is raised by the defendant, and upon
written motion of the district attorney, the defendant shall provide the state, within time
limits set by the court, any and all medical, correctional, educational, and military records,
raw data, tests, test scores, notes, behavioral observations, reports, evaluations, and any other
information of any kind reviewed by any defense expert in forming the basis of his opinion
that the defendant has an intellectual disability.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-905-5-1__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>By filing a notice relative to a claim of intellectual disability under this Article,
the defendant waives all claims of confidentiality and privilege to, and is deemed to have
consented to the release of, any and all medical, correctional, educational, and military
records, raw data, tests, test scores, notes, behavioral observations, reports, evaluations,
expert opinions, and any other such information of any kind or other records relevant or
necessary to an examination or determination under this Article.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-905-5-1__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>When a defendant makes a claim of intellectual disability under this Article, the
state shall have the right to an independent psychological and psychiatric examination of the
defendant.  A psychologist or medical psychologist conducting such examination must be
licensed by the Louisiana State Board of Examiners of Psychologists or the Louisiana State
Board of Medical Examiners, whichever is applicable.  If the state exercises this right, and
upon written motion of the defendant, the state shall provide the defendant, within time
limits set by the court, any and all medical, correctional, educational, and military records,
and all raw data, tests, test scores, notes, behavioral observations, reports, evaluations, and
any other information of any kind reviewed by any state expert in forming the basis of his
opinion that the defendant does not have an intellectual disability.  If the state fails to comply
with any such order, the court may impose sanctions as provided by Article 729.5 of this
Code.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-905-5-1__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the defendant making a claim of intellectual disability fails to comply with any
order issued pursuant to Paragraph D of this Article, or refuses to submit to or fully cooperate
in any examination by experts for the state pursuant to either Paragraph D or F of this Article,
upon motion by the district attorney, the court shall neither conduct a pretrial hearing
concerning the issue of intellectual disability nor instruct the jury of the prohibition of
executing defendants with intellectual disabilities.
H.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-905-5-1__subsec_G__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>&quot;Intellectual disability&quot;, formerly referred to as &quot;mental retardation&quot;, is a
disability characterized by all of the following deficits, the onset of which must occur during
the developmental period:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-905-5-1__subsec_G__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Deficits in intellectual functions such as reasoning, problem solving, planning,
abstract thinking, judgment, academic learning, and learning from experience, confirmed by
both clinical assessment and individualized, standardized intelligence testing.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-905-5-1__subsec_G__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Deficits in adaptive functioning that result in failure to meet developmental and
sociocultural standards for personal independence and social responsibility; and that, without
ongoing support, limit functioning in one or more activities of daily life including, without
limitation, communication, social participation, and independent living, across multiple
environments such as home, school, work, and community.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-905-5-1__subsec_G__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A diagnosis of one or more of the following conditions does not necessarily
constitute an intellectual disability:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-905-5-1__subsec_G__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Autism.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-905-5-1__subsec_G__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Behavioral disorders.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-905-5-1__subsec_G__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Cerebral palsy and other motor deficits.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-905-5-1__subsec_G__subsec_2__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Difficulty in adjusting to school.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-905-5-1__subsec_G__subsec_2__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Emotional disturbance.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-905-5-1__subsec_G__subsec_2__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Emotional stress in home or school.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-905-5-1__subsec_G__subsec_2__subsec_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Environmental, cultural, or economic disadvantage.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-905-5-1__subsec_G__subsec_2__subsec_h">
              <num>(h)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Epilepsy and other seizure disorders.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-905-5-1__subsec_G__subsec_2__subsec_i">
              <num>(i)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Lack of educational opportunities.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-905-5-1__subsec_G__subsec_2__subsec_j">
              <num>(j)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Learning disabilities.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-905-5-1__subsec_G__subsec_2__subsec_k">
              <num>(k)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Mental illness.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-905-5-1__subsec_G__subsec_2__subsec_l">
              <num>(l)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Neurological disorders.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-905-5-1__subsec_G__subsec_2__subsec_m">
              <num>(m)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Organic brain damage occurring after age eighteen.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-905-5-1__subsec_G__subsec_2__subsec_n">
              <num>(n)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Other disabling conditions.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-905-5-1__subsec_G__subsec_2__subsec_o">
              <num>(o)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Personality disorders.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-905-5-1__subsec_G__subsec_2__subsec_p">
              <num>(p)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Sensory impairments.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-905-5-1__subsec_G__subsec_2__subsec_q">
              <num>(q)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Speech and language disorders.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-905-5-1__subsec_G__subsec_2__subsec_r">
              <num>(r)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A temporary crisis situation.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-905-5-1__subsec_G__subsec_2__subsec_s">
              <num>(s)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Traumatic brain damage occurring after age eighteen.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=191015</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>