<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-811-2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-811-2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 811.2"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-811-2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-811-2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-811-2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-811-2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-811-2">
        <num>CHC 811.2</num>
        <heading>811.2.  Victims of juvenile crime compensation fund; established; disbursements</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-811-2__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>All courts exercising juvenile jurisdiction may levy a special cost in an amount not to exceed fifteen dollars against any juvenile defendant, other than an indigent, who is found to have committed a traffic violation resulting in injury or property loss, or who pleads guilty to or is adjudicated convicted of a juvenile offense.  Such cost shall be in addition to any fine, clerk's fees or costs, or any other fees or costs provided by law.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-811-2__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The clerk of court shall remit two-thirds of the sums collected or received pursuant to this Article for deposit in a special account which is hereby designated as the Victims of Juvenile Crime Compensation Fund.  The fund shall be used to compensate victims of juvenile crimes who do not otherwise receive restitution or reparation.  The judges of the courts exercising juvenile jurisdiction shall have control over the fund and disbursements made therefrom. The judges shall cause to be conducted annually an audit of the fund and the books and accounts relating thereto and shall file the same with the office of the legislative auditor, where it shall be available for public inspection.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-811-2__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The judges shall provide by court rule for the collection, administration, and distribution of the fund in order to implement the purpose of this Article.  However, no amount greater than five hundred dollars shall be disbursed from the fund to any one claimant.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-811-2__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The clerk of court shall remit one-third of the total sums collected or received pursuant to this Article monthly to the Crime Victims Reparations Fund as provided in R.S. 46:1801 et seq.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=73401</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>