<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-905-1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-905-1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 905.1"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-905-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-905-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-905-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-905-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-905-1">
        <num>CHC 905.1</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-905-1__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>When a child is assigned to the secure custody of the Department of Public Safety
and Corrections following an adjudication of delinquency, the department shall assess the
child's academic grade level using a research-based diagnostic tool within thirty days of the
child's admission to a secure care facility.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-905-1__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The department shall develop a written academic plan for the child based upon
all of the following criteria for each individual child:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-905-1__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Grade level diagnostic test results.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-905-1__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Past academic performance.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-905-1__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The individualized education plan or individualized learning plan, as applicable.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-905-1__subsec_B__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The length of time the child will be in the department's secure custody.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-905-1__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the child tests at grade level or above, the individualized education plan or
individualized learning plan shall be structured to allow the child to timely prepare for or
earn a high school diploma, General Educational Development Certification or certificate of
achievement from the Special School District, during the period the child is in the
department's secure custody.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-905-1__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the child tests below grade level, the individualized education plan or
individualized learning plan shall be structured, depending on the child's abilities, to bring
the child's academic performance up to grade level or as reasonably close thereto as possible,
during the period the child is in the department's secure custody.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-905-1__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The department shall submit the individualized education plan or individualized
learning plan to the court within forty-five days of the child's admission to the secure care
facility and a copy shall be provided to the parents or guardian of the child, the district
attorney, and counsel for the child at the time it is submitted to the court.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-905-1__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A report on the child's academic progress shall be included in the department's
quarterly report to the court.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-905-1__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>For purposes of this Code, &quot;individualized learning plan&quot; shall include vocational
training.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-905-1__subsec_H">
          <num>H.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon discharge from the department's custody, a copy of the child's academic
plan and all progress reports shall be provided to the child's parents or guardian.  The
department shall provide this information to the school or academic program in which the
child is thereafter enrolled upon written request.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=814352</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>