<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-717"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-717"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 717"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-717/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-717/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-717/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-717/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-717">
        <num>CCRP 717</num>
        <heading>717.  Disclosure by the state; criminal records of defendant and witnesses; inducements to the state's witnesses</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-717__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon written motion of the defendant, the court shall order the district attorney to disclose, or to direct the appropriate law enforcement agency to disclose to the defendant, the record of arrests and convictions of the defendant, any codefendant, and any witness the state calls, or intends to call at trial.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-717__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The district attorney shall also disclose any inducement offered by the district attorney, or by any law enforcement officer on behalf of the district attorney, to any state witness.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-717__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The time for disclosure provided for by this Article shall be set by the court, provided that the district attorney shall not be required to disclose inducements or records of arrests and convictions until the commencement of trial.  For any witness called by the state in its rebuttal case, the record of arrests and convictions of the rebuttal witness, and any inducement offered by the district attorney, or by any law enforcement officer on behalf of the district attorney, to secure testimony of the witness in the state's rebuttal case shall be disclosed immediately prior to the witness being sworn.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-717__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The provisions of Article 729.7 of this Code regarding the protection of a witness's identity shall apply to this Article.
Added by</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112724</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>