<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-791-3"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-791-3"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 791.3"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-791-3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-791-3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-791-3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-791-3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-791-3">
        <num>CHC 791.3</num>
        <heading>791.3.  State, state agencies; participation</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-791-3__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The state recognizes that juvenile crime is a statewide problem which is
increasing and which adversely affects all its citizens starting with the child and family. In
metropolitan areas of the state, juvenile courts report that almost all of its families under the
Families in Need of Services program involve school-related issues and the overwhelming
majority are truant cases involving children below the age of twelve.  &quot;Out-of-school&quot;
suspension rates in elementary schools are comparable to those of middle and junior high
schools.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-791-3__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The state is obligated to provide certain social and health care services to needy
families through the Department of Children and Family  Services and the Louisiana
Department of Health.  These services for assessment and psychiatric evaluation and
treatment, if deemed needed, must be continued.  The state substance abuse clinics, through
its employees and contracted programs, shall accept referrals for substance abuse evaluation
and treatment if warranted.  The legislature recognizes that each parish included in this
Chapter has committed through binding interagency agreements to provide certain
enumerated services, including providing physical space.  This commitment by the parishes
is predicated on financial assistance from the state in order to fully comply with the creation
of truancy assessment service centers.  Additionally, in order to support each truancy
assessment service center with sufficient services pursuant to this Chapter, the state will
continue to provide social and health-related services where available.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=73386</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>