<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-658"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-658"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 658"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-658/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-658/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-658/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-658/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-658">
        <num>CCRP 658</num>
        <heading>658.  Probation; conditional release; reporting</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-658__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>When the committed person is released on probation, which shall also be known
as conditional release, the clerk of court shall deliver to him a certificate setting forth the
period and the conditions of his probation.  It shall be a condition of every such probation
that the person released shall be recommitted if he becomes dangerous to others or to himself
for reasons of mental illness, substance abuse, or intellectual disability.  The probationer
shall be required to agree in writing to the conditions of his probation.
B.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-658__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The probationer shall be under the supervision of the division of probation and
parole.  When the probationer violates or is about to violate the conditions of his probation,
he may be arrested and detained in conformity with the applicable provisions of Article 899
of this Code.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-658__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Louisiana Department of Health shall be responsible for the community
treatment and monitoring of persons placed on outpatient status under this Chapter.  These
services shall be available on a parish or regional basis.  The department may provide
treatment services directly or through contracts with private providers or local jurisdictions.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-658__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The department shall designate for each parish or for each region comprised of
two or more parishes a conditional release program coordinator, who shall be responsible for
the provisions specified in this Chapter.  The coordinator shall monitor the forensic aftercare
provider's implementation of the conditional release order and the forensic aftercare
provider's submission to the court of written reports on the acquittee's progress, adjustment
in the community, and compliance with the order no less frequently than ninety days after
admission to the program and every one hundred eighty days thereafter.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-658__subsec_A__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a person on conditional release or otherwise probated under this Chapter is in
need of acute, i.e. short-term, hospitalization and is not charged with a new criminal offense,
he may be voluntarily admitted pursuant to R.S. 28:52 or admitted by emergency certificate
pursuant to R.S. 28:53 to the Feliciana Forensic Facility or to another suitable treatment
facility, with subsequent notice to the court.  Transportation to and from the receiving
hospital may be effected by the Feliciana Forensic Facility or the sheriff of the parish of
incarceration.  Hospital discharge of the person under this provision shall be at the discretion
of the clinical director of the facility and a hospital admission pursuant to this provision will
not be grounds for revocation or recommitment under Subparagraph (C)</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-658__subsec_A__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Article. 
However, the discharge of a person based on the need for indefinite hospitalization or
noncompliance with treatment recommendations shall be grounds for revocation or
recommitment.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-658__subsec_A__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The division of probation and parole or the Louisiana Department of Health 
through the conditional release program coordinator or a designee shall immediately notify
the court of any substantive violations or imminent violations of the conditions of a person's
probated release and shall present recommendations to the court regarding whether the court
should revoke the probation and recommit the probationer to a state mental institution or
other recommendations as may be appropriate.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-658__subsec_A__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The court, on its own motion or that of the district attorney or probation officer,
or upon receiving a report recommending revocation or other disposition from the
conditional release program coordinator, may cause the person to be arrested, if he is not
already in custody, and shall immediately hold a hearing to consider the violations listed or
transfer the case to the parish of commitment, if different from that of the arrest, at which
place the hearing should be held as soon as possible.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-658__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the court determines that there has been a violation or that the probationer was
about to violate the conditions of release or probation it may do any of the following:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-658__subsec_C__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Reprimand and warn the probationer.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-658__subsec_C__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Order that supervision be intensified.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-658__subsec_C__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Modify or add additional conditions to the probation.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-658__subsec_C__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Revoke the probation and recommit the probationer to a state mental institution,
subject to consideration for discharge or release on probation only after one year has elapsed
from the date of revocation and in accordance with the procedure prescribed in Articles 655
through 657 of this Code for a first application and hearing.  If the probation is revoked and
the probationer recommitted, the court shall provide the hospital with the report of the
probation officer or forensic aftercare provider regarding the details of the violations
involved.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-658__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court may completely discharge the probationer after the expiration of one
year in a supervised conditional release program only on recommendation of the director of
the division of probation and parole or the administrator of the conditional release program
or on other proper evidence of expected outpatient compliance with any continued treatment
recommendations, and after a contradictory hearing with the district attorney.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-658__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>No person who is on outpatient conditional release status pursuant to this Chapter
shall leave this state without first obtaining written approval to do so from the director of the
division of probation and parole and the administrator of the conditional release program. 
Any person who violates the provisions of this Paragraph may be fined not more than one
thousand dollars or imprisoned with or without hard labor for not more than one year, or
both.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112683</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>