<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-930-11"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-930-11"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 930.11"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-930-11/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-930-11/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-930-11/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-930-11/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-930-11">
        <num>CCRP 930.11</num>
        <heading>930.11.  Time delays applicable to this Title; writ of mandamus</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-930-11__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court of appropriate jurisdiction shall adhere to the following time periods
in post conviction proceedings:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-930-11__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The court shall conduct the preliminary review provided in Article 927 within
thirty days of the filing of application.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-930-11__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>When ruling on procedural objections that have been filed pursuant to Article
927, the court shall issue its ruling within thirty days of receipt of such objections.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-930-11__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the court determines that no evidentiary hearing is necessary, it shall issue its
ruling on the merits of any remaining claim alleged in the application within thirty days of
the state's answer on the merits.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-930-11__subsec_A__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>When the court determines that there are questions of fact which cannot properly
be resolved pursuant to Article 929, it shall conduct an evidentiary hearing provided in
Article 930 within one hundred eighty days of such determination and issue a ruling on the
merits of any remaining claim within thirty days following the conclusion of such hearing.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-930-11__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The district attorney and the attorney general shall adhere to the following time
periods in post conviction proceedings:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-930-11__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The district attorney shall have sixty days to file procedural objections pursuant
to Article 927.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-930-11__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If an answer is required, the district attorney shall have sixty days from the court's
ruling on procedural objections to file an answer on the merits pursuant to Article 927.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-930-11__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The attorney general shall have thirty days to file procedural objections pursuant
to Article 927 if the district attorney waives such objections.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-930-11__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A petitioner who has been sentenced to death shall only seek supervisory review
directly from the Louisiana Supreme Court.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-930-11__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a petitioner invokes the supervisory jurisdiction of the Louisiana Supreme
Court, the supreme court shall rule on an application for a writ of review within one hundred
eighty days of receipt.  If there is an active death warrant, the court shall issue a ruling prior
to the effective date of that warrant.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-930-11__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The state or petitioner shall have the right to seek a writ of mandamus to compel
a court to issue a requested ruling within a specified period not to exceed thirty days if that
court has not issued a ruling within the deadlines provided in this Title.  The reviewing court
may order the lower court to submit a per curiam opinion to the reviewing court with an
explanation regarding why the lower court has not issued a ruling within the deadlines
provided in this Title.
F.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-930-11__subsec_E__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon the motion of either party, any deadline set forth in this Title, except for
the deadline for filing applications for post-conviction relief set forth in Article 930.8, may
be extended by the court subject to the requirements of this Article.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-930-11__subsec_E__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any motion for an extension of time filed by either party shall be filed not later
than seven days prior to the deadline sought to be extended and shall be served on all parties
and the court by any method allowed by law.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-930-11__subsec_E__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any motion for an extension of time granted by the court pursuant to this Article
shall not exceed sixty days in length, and in no case shall either party be allowed more than
three extensions of time.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-930-11__subsec_E__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Each party's first motion for an extension of time may be granted by the court
without a contradictory hearing.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-930-11__subsec_E__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>After a party's first motion for an extension of time has been granted, any
subsequent motion for an additional extension of time by the same mover shall require a
contradictory hearing.  Following the contradictory hearing, the court may only grant the
motion upon a showing by the mover that extraordinary circumstances outside of the control
of the moving party exist that necessitate the requested extension of time.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=1429005</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>