<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-252"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-252"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 252"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-252/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-252/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-252/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-252/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-252">
        <num>CCRP 252</num>
        <heading>252.  Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-252__subsec_1">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Administrator&quot; means the person conducting the photo or live lineup.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-252__subsec_2">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Blind&quot; means conducted in such a way that the administrator does not know the
identity of the suspect.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-252__subsec_3">
          <num>(3)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Blinded&quot; means conducted in such a way that the administrator may know who
the suspect is, but does not know which lineup member is being viewed by the eyewitness.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-252__subsec_4">
          <num>(4)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Criminal justice entity&quot; means any government agency or subunit thereof, or
private agency that, through statutory authorization or a legal formal agreement with a
governmental unit or agency, has the power of investigation, arrest, detention, prosecution,
adjudication, treatment, supervision, rehabilitation, or release of persons suspected, charged,
or convicted of a crime.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-252__subsec_5">
          <num>(5)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Eyewitness&quot; means a person who observes another person at or near the scene
of an offense.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-252__subsec_6">
          <num>(6)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Filler&quot; means either a person or a photograph of a person who is not suspected
of an offense but is included in an identification procedure.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-252__subsec_7">
          <num>(7)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Folder shuffle method&quot; means a blinded procedure in which the suspect photos
and nonsuspect or filler photos are each placed in separate folders for a total of six
photographs and shuffled together along with four blank folders and handed to the
eyewitness one at a time so that the administrator cannot see which photograph the
eyewitness is viewing.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-252__subsec_8">
          <num>(8)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Live lineup&quot; means an identification procedure in which a group of persons,
including the suspected perpetrator of an offense and other persons not suspected of the
offense, is displayed to an eyewitness for the purpose of determining whether the eyewitness
identifies the suspect as the perpetrator.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-252__subsec_9">
          <num>(9)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Photo lineup&quot; means an identification procedure in which an array of
photographs, including a photograph of the suspected perpetrator of an offense and additional
photographs of other persons not suspected of the offense, is displayed to an eyewitness
either in hard copy form or via computer or similar device for the purpose of determining
whether the eyewitness identifies the suspect as the perpetrator.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-252__subsec_10">
          <num>(10)</num>
          <content>
            <p>&quot;Suspect&quot; means a person believed by law enforcement to be the possible
perpetrator of an offense.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=1106481</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>