<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-326"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-326"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 326"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-326/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-326/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-326/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-326/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-326">
        <num>CCRP 326</num>
        <heading>326.  Cash deposits</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-326__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon final disposition of all cases in which a deposit of money, checks, bonds,
or money orders has been made pursuant to this Article, and the deposits have remained
unclaimed for a period of one year from the date of the final disposition, the officer
authorized to accept the bail shall apply and use one-half of such funds for the operation and
maintenance of the office of the clerk of court, or the office of the clerk of the criminal
district court, or the office of the clerk of the criminal district court in Orleans Parish, and
one-half to the local governing authority after advertising his intention to so utilize the funds
by publication in the official parish journal of a notice to the public containing an itemized
list of all of such funds on deposit, containing the names and last known addresses of
defendants and the docket numbers of the cases involved.  The publication shall be made
once within thirty days after the final disposition of the case as aforesaid.  The clerk shall
also send a notice by certified mail to each of such defendants at the last known address of
the defendant.  Any interest earned on the funds deposited for bail shall be disbursed as
provided in Paragraph E of this Article.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-326__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>After the publication and mailing of the notice by certified mail, the clerk of court,
or the clerk of the criminal district court in Orleans Parish shall petition the court of proper
jurisdiction for permission to utilize the funds for the use, operation, and maintenance of the
office of the clerk of court or the clerk of criminal district court in Orleans Parish.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-326__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>When bail has been given in conformity with this Article, the money, check,
bond, or money order shall not be subject to garnishment, attachment, or seizure under any
legal process. An assignment or sale thereof by the owner, to be valid, must be in the form
of an authentic act and filed in the proceedings in the court having jurisdiction to discharge
the bail. The property shall remain on deposit and the assignment or sale shall be contingent
upon the nonforfeiture of the bail.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-326__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>When money, checks, or money orders have been given for bail in conformity
with this Article, those funds may be deposited by the officer authorized to accept bail into
an interest-bearing account established exclusively for the deposit of such funds. Interest
earned on the deposits in the account shall be used solely for the operation and maintenance
of the office of the clerk of court.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112446</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>