<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-162-3"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-162-3"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 162.3"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-162-3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-162-3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-162-3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-162-3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-162-3">
        <num>CCRP 162.3</num>
        <heading>162.3.  No-knock warrant</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-162-3__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>No law enforcement officer shall seek, execute, or participate in the execution of
a no-knock warrant, except in cases where both of the following apply:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-162-3__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The affidavit supporting the request for the warrant establishes probable cause
that exigent circumstances exist requiring the warrant to be executed in a no-knock manner.
For purposes of this Subparagraph, exigent circumstances shall include circumstances where
the surprise of a no-knock entry is necessary to protect life and limb of the law enforcement
officers and the occupants.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-162-3__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The copy of the warrant being executed that is in the possession of law
enforcement officers to be delivered as provided in Paragraph C of this Article includes the
judge's signature.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-162-3__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A search warrant authorized under this Article shall require that a law
enforcement officer be recognizable and identifiable as a uniformed law enforcement officer
and provide audible notice of his authority and purpose reasonably expected to be heard by
occupants of such place to be searched prior to the execution of such search warrant.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-162-3__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>After entering and securing the place to be searched and prior to undertaking any
search or seizure pursuant to the search warrant, the executing law enforcement officer shall
read and give a copy of the search warrant to the person to be searched or the owner of the
place to be searched or, if the owner is not present, to any occupant of the place to be
searched. If the place to be searched is unoccupied, the executing law enforcement officer
shall leave a copy of the search warrant suitably affixed to the place to be searched.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-162-3__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Search warrants authorized under this Article shall be executed only from sunrise
to sunset except in either of the following instances:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-162-3__subsec_D__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A judge authorizes the execution of such search warrant at another time for good
cause shown.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-162-3__subsec_D__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The search warrant is for the withdrawal of blood. A search warrant for the
withdrawal of blood may be executed at any time of day.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-162-3__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any evidence obtained from a search warrant in violation of this Article shall not
be admitted into evidence for prosecution.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-162-3__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>For purposes of this Article, &quot;no-knock warrant&quot; means a warrant issued by a
judge that allows law enforcement to enter a property without immediate prior notification
of the residents, such as by knocking or ringing a doorbell.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-162-3__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the purposes of this Article, only a district court judge may issue a no-knock
warrant.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=1238743</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>