<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1302-5"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1302-5"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 1302.5"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1302-5/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1302-5/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1302-5/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1302-5/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-1302-5">
        <num>CHC 1302.5</num>
        <heading>1302.5.  Continuing exclusive jurisdiction to modify child support order</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1302-5__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A tribunal of this state that has issued a child support order consistent with the
law of this state has and shall exercise continuing, exclusive jurisdiction to modify its child
support order if the order is the controlling order and:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1302-5__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>At the time of the filing of a request for modification, this state is the residence
of the obligor, the individual obligee, or the child for whose benefit the support order is
issued; or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1302-5__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Even if this state is not the residence of the obligor, the individual obligee, or the
child for whose benefit the support order is issued, the parties consent in a record or in open
court that the tribunal of this state may continue to exercise jurisdiction to modify its order.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1302-5__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A tribunal of this state that has issued a child support order consistent with the
law of this state may not exercise continuing, exclusive jurisdiction to modify the order if:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1302-5__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>All of the parties who are individuals file consent in a record with the tribunal
of this state that a tribunal of another state that has jurisdiction over at least one of the parties
who is an individual or that is located in the state of residence of the child may modify the
order and assume continuing, exclusive jurisdiction; or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1302-5__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Its order is not the controlling order.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1302-5__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a tribunal of another state has issued a child support order pursuant to the
Uniform Interstate Family Support Act or a law substantially similar to that Act which
modifies a child support order of a tribunal of this state, tribunals of this state shall recognize
the continuing, exclusive jurisdiction of the tribunal of the other state.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1302-5__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A tribunal of this state that lacks continuing, exclusive jurisdiction to modify a
child support order may serve as an initiating tribunal to request a tribunal of another state
to modify a support order issued in that state.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1302-5__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A temporary support order issued ex parte or pending resolution of a jurisdictional
conflict does not create continuing, exclusive jurisdiction in the issuing tribunal.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=72803</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>