<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-330-1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-330-1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 330.1"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-330-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-330-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-330-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-330-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-330-1">
        <num>CCRP 330.1</num>
        <heading>330.1.  Posting bail when arrested outside of originating jurisdiction</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-330-1__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any provisions of law to the contrary, a person who is arrested
and booked in an executing jurisdiction pursuant to a warrant for arrest issued by the
originating jurisdiction may be released from custody when bail is posted under the following
conditions:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-330-1__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The amount of the bail obligation is included on the warrant for arrest. If the
warrant for arrest does not include the amount of the bail obligation, the amount may be set
within forty-eight hours by anyone in the originating jurisdiction who is authorized to set bail
pursuant to Article 314.  If a personal surety undertaking is authorized, the personal surety
undertaking shall be in accordance with either Article 323 or 324.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-330-1__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>There are no holds, court orders, or other legal impediments that would prohibit
the release of the arrested person from custody.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-330-1__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The executing jurisdiction does not object.  If the executing jurisdiction objects,
the originating jurisdiction shall comply with existing provisions of law relative to bail.  The
originating jurisdiction shall retain the right to transport or to have the person in custody
transported to the originating jurisdiction for the purpose of posting bail in the originating
jurisdiction.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-330-1__subsec_A__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Written notice shall be provided to the executing jurisdiction when bail is posted
in the originating jurisdiction and release from custody is authorized. When released, the
executing jurisdiction shall provide notice in accordance with Article 330 to the arrested
person.  The originating jurisdiction shall deliver to the executing jurisdiction the
information necessary to provide such notice to the arrested person. The notice shall include
the date, time, and location of any required court appearances as well as any conditions of
bail.  Notwithstanding any provisions of law to the contrary, an electronic copy, digital copy,
or photocopy of the arrested person's signature on the notice shall be the equivalent of an
original signature.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-330-1__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The provisions of this Article shall not apply to warrants for sex offenses,
homicides and crimes resulting in a death or deaths, felony domestic violence offenses, and
aggravated offenses.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112453</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>