<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-412"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-412"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 412"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-412/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-412/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-412/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-412/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-412">
        <num>CHC 412</num>
        <heading>412.  Confidentiality of records; disclosure exceptions; sanctions</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-412__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Records and reports concerning all matters or proceedings before the juvenile
court, except traffic violations, are confidential and shall not be disclosed except as expressly
authorized by this Code.  Any person authorized to review or receive confidential
information shall preserve its confidentiality unless a court order authorizes them to share
with others.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-412__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nonidentifying information of a general nature, including statistics, is not
confidential and may be released without a court order.  By court order, an individual may
be authorized to review confidential records and reports, including case file samples, for the
purpose of collecting nonidentifying general information, including statistics.  The court
order shall specify the type of information authorized for review and bind the reviewer to
preserving the confidentiality of any identifying information reviewed.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-412__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Records and reports in individual cases may be released to parties, their counsel
or other legal representatives, and court-appointed special advocates (CASAs) in accordance
with discovery and disclosure provisions of this Code. Notwithstanding any other provision
of law to the contrary, access to review all records and reports concerning a child in the
custody of the office of juvenile justice, including but not limited to records relating to
condition, housing, supervision, treatment, rehabilitation program, education, health,
discipline, transition planning, risk assessments, and status reports shall be promptly
provided to counsel enrolled for the child or engaged by the child, or to the child's legal
guardian, upon written request to the office of juvenile justice. If the child is indigent, copies
of all records and reports relevant to post-dispositional defense and reentry advocacy shall
be furnished at no cost to the child, the child's family, legal guardian, or counsel.
Representation by a public defender shall create an irrebuttable presumption of indigence for
the purposes of this Paragraph.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-412__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>When such information is relevant and necessary to the performance of their
respective duties and enhances services to the child or his family, the court may authorize the
release of records, reports, or certain information contained therein, limited to the specific
purpose for which the court authorizes release, to appropriate individuals who represent any
of the following when they are providing services to the child whose records are disclosed
during the pendency of the matter about which the records are disclosed:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-412__subsec_D__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Other courts and court-affiliated programs.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-412__subsec_D__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department of Children and Family Services.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-412__subsec_D__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The office of juvenile justice of the Department of Public Safety and Corrections.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-412__subsec_D__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Louisiana Department of Health.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-412__subsec_D__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department of Education or the local school in which the child is a student.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-412__subsec_D__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The local district attorney's office.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-412__subsec_D__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A multidisciplinary investigative child abuse team.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-412__subsec_D__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A child advocacy center.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-412__subsec_D__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The attorney general's office.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-412__subsec_D__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A district public defender or the district public defender's representative, or the
representative of a public defender program established pursuant to the Louisiana Public
Defender Act of 2007.
E.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-412__subsec_D__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For good cause when the information is material and necessary to a specific
investigation or proceeding, the court may order the release of individual records and reports,
or certain information contained therein, to a petitioner, limited to the specific purpose for
which the court authorizes release.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-412__subsec_D__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The petition must:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-412__subsec_D__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Be filed with the juvenile court and served on the juvenile and his attorney.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-412__subsec_D__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>State the reason for the request and the intended use of the information, including
any intended redisclosure.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-412__subsec_D__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>State the names of all persons that will have access to the information.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-412__subsec_D__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In ruling on the petition, the juvenile court shall consider the privacy of the
juvenile, risk of harm to the juvenile, whether a compelling reason exists for releasing the
information, and whether the release is necessary for the protection of a legitimate interest.
The court shall ensure the juvenile is afforded notice of the hearing and an opportunity to be
heard at a contradictory hearing on the petition.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-412__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court may release records and reports concerning any proceeding, except
adoption, to an adult who, as a child, was the subject of the proceeding.  For good cause, the
court may also order release of records and reports to the counsel or other appropriate legal
representative of a child, still a minor, who was the subject of any proceedings, except
adoption.
G.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-412__subsec_F__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In accordance with Articles 811.1 and 811.3, the district attorney or court shall,
upon request, release to the victim of a delinquent act constituting a crime of violence as
defined in R.S. 14:2(B), or to the victim's legal representative or designated family member:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-412__subsec_F__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The results of adjudication and disposition hearings.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-412__subsec_F__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Notice of the taking into custody, release pursuant to Chapter 6 of Title VIII of
this Code, release due to a rejection of charges by the district attorney, escape, or re-apprehension of the child accused of the crime of violence against the victim.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-412__subsec_F__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Advance notice of court proceedings relating to the delinquent act.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-412__subsec_F__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Certain information contained in the predisposition report to the court pursuant
to Article 890, limited to those items described in Subparagraph (A)</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-412__subsec_F__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of that Article.</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-412__subsec_F__subsec_2__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The name of the judge presiding over the adjudication and disposition hearings.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-412__subsec_F__subsec_2__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The offense which forms the basis for adjudication.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-412__subsec_F__subsec_2__subsec_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The name of the accused.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-412__subsec_F__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In a juvenile delinquency case involving a crime of violence as defined in R.S.
14:2(B), the court shall, upon written request, release to the public the following:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-412__subsec_F__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The nonidentifying results of adjudication and disposition hearings.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-412__subsec_F__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The name of the judge presiding over the adjudication and disposition hearings.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-412__subsec_F__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The offense which forms the basis for adjudication.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-412__subsec_H">
          <num>H.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In order to assist in finding and taking into custody a child wanted for a felony-grade delinquent act involving an offense against the person or involving a dangerous
weapon, law enforcement agencies may release to the public identifying information
regarding the child if a court has issued an order for taking the child into custody pursuant
to Article 813, or if probable cause that the child committed the alleged delinquent act has
already been established pursuant to Article 820. Identifying information may include the
child's name, age, alleged delinquent act, physical description, and photograph.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-412__subsec_I">
          <num>I.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any violation of the confidentiality provisions of this Article shall be punishable
as a constructive contempt of court pursuant to Articles 1507 through 1509.1.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-412__subsec_J">
          <num>J.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whenever a child escapes from a juvenile detention center, law enforcement
agencies are hereby authorized to release to the public the child's name, age, physical
description, and photograph.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-412__subsec_K">
          <num>K.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Every person, other than the juvenile, parents of the juvenile, and attorney for the
juvenile, to whom a juvenile record or information from a juvenile is disclosed pursuant to
this Article shall execute a non-disclosure agreement that certifies the person is familiar with
the applicable disclosure provisions and agrees not to disclose any information to
unauthorized persons.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-412__subsec_L">
          <num>L.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Juvenile records or information from juvenile records disclosed pursuant to this
Article shall be marked &quot;UNLAWFUL DISSEMINATION OF THIS INFORMATION IS
PUNISHABLE AS A CONSTRUCTIVE CONTEMPT OF COURT PURSUANT TO
LOUISIANA CHILDREN'S CODE ARTICLE 1509(E)&quot;.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-412__subsec_M">
          <num>M.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Records of juvenile criminal conduct shall not be disseminated as a criminal
background check to anyone outside of the criminal justice system as defined in R.S. 15:576.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-412__subsec_N">
          <num>N.</num>
          <content>
            <p>This Article shall not apply to records relative to any matters identified in Article
879(B)</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-412__subsec_N__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding any other law to the contrary, the state child ombudsman shall
have access to judgments and court minute entries concerning matters or proceedings before
the juvenile court as needed in furtherance of the ombudsman's statutory duties.  Any
judgments and court minute entries provided to the state child ombudsman shall remain
confidential and shall not be subject to any further disclosure, absent an order of the juvenile
court for that purpose.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-412__subsec_N__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The office of juvenile justice shall provide to the state child ombudsman, upon
written request of the state child ombudsman, any record or report concerning a child in the
custody of or under the supervision of the office of juvenile justice needed in furtherance of
the ombudsman's statutory duties, including but not limited to records related to condition,
housing, supervision, treatment, rehabilitation program, education, health, discipline,
transition planning, risk assessments, and status reports.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-412__subsec_P">
          <num>P.</num>
          <content>
            <p>This Article shall not prohibit the creation of an interoperable set of criminal
justice information systems at the state and local levels pursuant to R.S. 15:575 et seq., or
preclude the dissemination of criminal history record information as defined in R.S. 15:576
in and to the criminal justice system as defined in R.S. 15:576.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=73150</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>