<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-863"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-863"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCP 863"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-863/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-863/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-863/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-863/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCP-863">
        <num>CCP 863</num>
        <heading>863.  Signing of pleadings; effect</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCP-863__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Every pleading of a party represented by an attorney shall be signed by at least
one attorney of record in his individual name, whose physical address and email address for
service of process shall be stated.  A party who is not represented by an attorney shall sign
his pleading and state his physical address and email address, if the party has an email
address, for service of process.  If mail is not received at the physical address for service of
process, a designated mailing address shall also be provided.  A party or attorney may sign
a pleading by electronic signature in accordance with Article 253.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-863__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Pleadings need not be verified or accompanied by affidavit or certificate, except
as otherwise provided by law, but the signature of an attorney or party shall constitute a
certification by him that he has read the pleading, and that to the best of his knowledge,
information, and belief formed after reasonable inquiry, he certifies all of the following:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-863__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The pleading is not being presented for any improper purpose, such as to harass,
cause unnecessary delay, or needlessly increase the cost of litigation.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-863__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Each claim, defense, or other legal assertion in the pleading is warranted by
existing law or by a nonfrivolous argument for the extension, modification, or reversal of
existing law.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-863__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Each allegation or other factual assertion in the pleading has evidentiary support
or, for a specifically identified allegation or factual assertion, is likely to have evidentiary
support after a reasonable opportunity for further investigation or discovery.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCP-863__subsec_B__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Each denial in the pleading of a factual assertion is warranted by the evidence or,
for a specifically identified denial, is reasonably based on a lack of information or belief.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-863__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a pleading is not signed, it shall be stricken unless promptly signed after the
omission is called to the attention of the pleader.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-863__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If, upon motion of any party or upon its own motion, the court determines that a
certification has been made in violation of the provisions of this Article, the court shall
impose upon the person who made the certification or the represented party, or both, an
appropriate sanction which may include an order to pay to the other party the amount of the
reasonable expenses incurred because of the filing of the pleading, including reasonable
attorney fees.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-863__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A sanction authorized in Paragraph D shall be imposed only after a hearing at
which any party or his counsel may present any evidence or argument relevant to the issue
of imposition of the sanction.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-863__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A sanction authorized in Paragraph D of this Article shall not be imposed with
respect to an original petition that is filed within sixty days of an applicable prescriptive date
and then voluntarily dismissed or transferred to a court of proper venue within ninety days
after its filing or on the date of a hearing on the pleading, whichever is earlier.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-863__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the court imposes a sanction, it shall describe the conduct determined to
constitute a violation of the provisions of this Article and explain the basis for the sanction
imposed.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112283</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>