<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-412"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-412"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CE 412"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-412/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-412/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-412/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-412/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CE-412">
        <num>CE 412</num>
        <heading>412.  Victim's past sexual behavior in sexual assault cases; trafficking offenses</heading>
        <subsection eId="CE-412__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Motion.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CE-412__subsec_C__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Before the person, accused of committing a crime that involves
sexually assaultive behavior, human trafficking, or trafficking of children for sexual
purposes, may offer under Subparagraph (A)</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-412__subsec_C__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>or (B)</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-412__subsec_C__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Article evidence of specific
instances of the victim's past sexual behavior, the accused shall make a written motion in
camera to offer such evidence.  The motion shall be accompanied by a written statement of
evidence setting forth the names and addresses of persons to be called as witnesses.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-412__subsec_C__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The motion and statement of evidence shall be served on the state which shall
make a reasonable effort to notify the victim prior to the hearing.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CE-412__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Time for a motion.  The motion shall be made within the time for filing pre-trial
motions specified in Code of Criminal Procedure Article 521, except that the court shall
allow the motion to be made at a later date, if the court determines that:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CE-412__subsec_D__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The evidence is of past sexual behavior with the accused, and the accused
establishes that the motion was not timely made because of an impossibility arising through
no fault of his own; or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-412__subsec_D__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The evidence is of past sexual behavior with someone other than the accused, and
the accused establishes that the evidence or the issue to which it relates is newly discovered
and could not have been obtained earlier through the exercise of due diligence.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CE-412__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Hearing.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CE-412__subsec_E__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the court determines that the statement of evidence contains
evidence described in Subparagraph (A)</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-412__subsec_E__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>or (B)(2), the court shall order a hearing which
shall be closed to determine if such evidence is admissible.  At such hearing the parties may
call witnesses.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-412__subsec_E__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The victim, if present, has the right to attend the hearing and may be
accompanied by counsel.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-412__subsec_E__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the court determines on the basis of the hearing described in Subparagraph
(E)</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-412__subsec_E__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>that the evidence which the accused seeks to offer is relevant and that the probative
value of such evidence outweighs the danger of unfair prejudice, such evidence may be
admissible in the trial to the extent an order made by the court specifies evidence which may
be offered and areas with respect to which the victim may be examined or cross-examined. 
Introduction of such evidence shall be limited to that specified in the order.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-412__subsec_E__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any motion made under Subparagraph C and any statement of evidence, brief,
record of a hearing, or like material made or used in connection with the motion shall be kept
in a separate, sealed package as part of the record in the case.  Nothing in this Article shall
preclude the use of the testimony at such hearing in a subsequent prosecution for perjury or
false swearing.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CE-412__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Past sexual behavior defined.  For purposes of this Article, the term &quot;past sexual
behavior&quot; means sexual behavior other than the sexual behavior with respect to which the
offense of sexually assaultive behavior is alleged.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CE-412__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The rules of admissibility of evidence provided by this Article shall also apply to
civil actions brought by the victim which are alleged to arise from sexually assaultive
behavior, human trafficking, or trafficking of children for sexual purposes by the defendant,
whether or not convicted of such crimes.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=72466</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>