<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-901"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-901"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 901"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-901/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-901/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-901/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-901/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-901">
        <num>CCRP 901</num>
        <heading>901.  Revocation for commission of another offense</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-901__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition to the grounds for revocation of probation enumerated in Article 900,
a defendant who is on probation for a felony who subsequently commits and is convicted of
a felony under the laws of this state, another state, the United States, or the District of
Columbia, and which if committed in this state would be a felony, shall have his probation
revoked as of the date of the commission of the felony or final conviction of the felony.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-901__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>When a defendant who is under a suspended sentence or on probation for a
misdemeanor commits or is convicted of any offense under the laws of this state, a political
subdivision thereof, another state or a political subdivision thereof, the United States, or the
District of Columbia, his suspended sentence or probation may be revoked as of the date of
the commission or final conviction of the offense.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-901__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In cases of revocation provided for in this Article:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-901__subsec_C__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>No credit shall be allowed for time spent on probation or for the time elapsed
during suspension of the sentence.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-901__subsec_C__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>When the new conviction is a Louisiana conviction, the court shall specify in the
minutes whether the sentence shall run consecutively or concurrently with the sentence for
the new conviction.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-901__subsec_C__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The defendant may be given credit for time served prior to the revocation hearing
for time served in actual custody while being held for a probation violation in a local
detention facility, state institution, or out-of-state institution pursuant to Article 880.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-901__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The provisions of this Article shall not apply to a defendant who, as an additional
condition for the violation of his probation, has been ordered to complete a drug or specialty
court program.  A defendant who is eligible for revocation of probation pursuant to
Paragraph A of this Article and does not successfully complete such court-ordered drug or
specialty court program shall have his probation revoked as of the date of the commission
of the felony or final conviction of the felony.
Amended by</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112903</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>