<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-253"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-253"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 253"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-253/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-253/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-253/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-253/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-253">
        <num>CCRP 253</num>
        <heading>253.  Eyewitness identification procedures</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-253__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>For any criminal justice entity that elects to draft its own policy on eyewitness
identification procedures, these policies shall:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-253__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Be based on all of the following:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-253__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Credible field, academic, or laboratory research on eyewitness memory.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-253__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Relevant policies, guidelines, and best practices designed to reduce erroneous
eyewitness identifications and to enhance the reliability and objectivity of eyewitness
identifications.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-253__subsec_B__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Other relevant information as appropriate.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-253__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Include the following information regarding evidence-based practices:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-253__subsec_B__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Procedures for selecting photograph and live lineup filler photographs or
participants to ensure that the photographs or participants:</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-253__subsec_B__subsec_2__subsec_i">
              <num>(i)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Are consistent in appearance with the description of the alleged perpetrator.
(ii)  Do not make the suspect noticeably stand out.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-253__subsec_B__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Instructions given to a witness before conducting a photograph or live lineup
identification procedure shall include a statement that the person who committed the offense
may or may not be present in the procedure.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-253__subsec_B__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Procedures for documenting and preserving the results of a photograph or live
lineup identification procedure, including the documentation of witness statements,
regardless of the outcome of the procedure.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-253__subsec_B__subsec_2__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Procedures for administering a photograph or live lineup identification procedure
to an illiterate person or a person with limited English language proficiency.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-253__subsec_B__subsec_2__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For a live lineup identification procedure, if practicable, procedures for assigning
an administrator who is unaware of which member of the live lineup is the suspect in the
case or alternative procedures designed to prevent opportunities to influence the witness.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-253__subsec_B__subsec_2__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For a photograph identification procedure, procedures for assigning an
administrator who is capable of administering a photograph array in a blind manner or in a
blinded manner consistent with other proven or supported best practices designed to prevent
opportunities to influence the witness.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-253__subsec_B__subsec_2__subsec_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any other procedures or best practices supported by credible research or
commonly accepted as a means to reduce erroneous eyewitness identifications and to
enhance the objectivity and reliability of eyewitness identifications.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-253__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Provide that a witness who makes an identification based on a photograph or live
lineup identification procedure be asked immediately after the procedure to state, in the
witness's own words, how confident the witness is in making the identification.  A law
enforcement agency shall document in accordance with Subsubparagraph (2)</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-253__subsec_B__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this
Paragraph any statement made under this Subparagraph.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-253__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Not later than December thirty-first of each odd-numbered year, the institute shall
review the model policy and training materials adopted under this Article and shall modify
the policy and materials as appropriate while maintaining the requirements outlined in
Paragraph B of this Article.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-253__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Not later than December thirty-first of each even-numbered year, each law
enforcement agency shall review its policy adopted under this Article and shall modify that
policy as appropriate while maintaining the requirements outlined in Paragraph B of this
Article.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-253__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Failure to conduct a photograph or live lineup identification procedure in
substantial compliance with the model policy or any other policy adopted under this Article
shall not bar the admission of eyewitness identification testimony.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-253__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A video record of identification procedures shall be made or, if a video record is
not practicable, an audio record shall be made.  If neither a video nor audio record are
practicable, the reasons shall be documented in writing, and the lineup administrator shall
make a full and complete written record of the lineup in accordance with Subsubparagraph
(B)(2)(c) of this Article.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-253__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The written eyewitness identification procedures of a criminal justice entity shall
be made available, in writing, to the public upon request.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-253__subsec_H">
          <num>H.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Evidence of failure to comply with any of the provisions of this Article:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-253__subsec_H__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>May be considered by the district court in adjudicating motions to suppress an
eyewitness identification.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-253__subsec_H__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>May be admissible in support of any claim of eyewitness misidentification, as
long as the evidence is otherwise admissible.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=1106482</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>