<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-4843"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-4843"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCP 4843"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-4843/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-4843/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-4843/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCP-4843/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCP-4843">
        <num>CCP 4843</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="CCP-4843__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as otherwise provided for in this Article, the civil jurisdiction of a city
court is concurrent with the district court in cases where the amount in dispute, or the value
of the property involved, does not exceed fifteen thousand dollars.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-4843__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The civil jurisdiction of a city court in which the population of the territorial
jurisdiction is greater than fifty thousand is concurrent with the district court in cases or
proceedings instituted by the state, a parish, a municipality, or other political subdivision of
the state for injunctive relief or other civil relief for the cessation or abatement of any acts
or practices which may violate a parish or municipal ordinance or state law.  In such case,
the court has jurisdiction regardless of the amount in dispute or the value of the property
involved.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-4843__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the City Court of Bossier City, and any city court in which the population of
the territorial jurisdiction is less than fifty thousand, except as otherwise specifically
provided by law, the civil jurisdiction is concurrent with the district court in cases where the
amount in dispute, or the value of the property involved, does not exceed fifteen thousand
dollars.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-4843__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the City Court of Breaux Bridge, the City Court of Houma, the City Court of
Jeanerette, the City Court of Jennings, the City Court of Monroe, the City Court of New
Iberia, the City Court of Oakdale, and the City Court of Winnfield, the civil jurisdiction is
concurrent with the district court in cases where the amount in dispute, or the value of the
property involved, does not exceed thirty thousand dollars.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-4843__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the City Court of Breaux Bridge,  the City Court of Houma, the City Court of
Jeanerette, the City Court of Jennings, the City Court of Monroe, the City Court of New
Iberia, the City Court of Oakdale,  and the City Court of Winnfield, the civil jurisdiction is
concurrent with the district court in cases where the amount in dispute, or the value of the
property involved, does not exceed thirty thousand dollars.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-4843__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the City Court of Abbeville, the City Court of Baker, the City Court of Baton
Rouge, the City Court of Crowley, the City Court of Kaplan, the City Court of Lafayette, the
City Court of Leesville, the City Court of Minden, the City Court of Plaquemine, the City
Court of Rayne, the City Court of Shreveport, the City Court of Springhill, and the City
Court of Zachary, the civil jurisdiction is concurrent with the district court in cases where the
amount in dispute, or the value of the property involved, does not exceed thirty-five thousand
dollars.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-4843__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the City Court of Alexandria, the City Court of East St. Tammany, the City
Court of Hammond, the City Court of Lake Charles, the City Court of Pineville, the City
Court of Ruston, the City Court of Sulphur, and the Third Ward City Court of Franklin, the
civil jurisdiction is concurrent with the district court in cases where the amount in dispute,
or the value of the property involved, does not exceed fifty thousand dollars.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCP-4843__subsec_H">
          <num>H.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Repealed by</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112087</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>