<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-814"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-814"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 814"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-814/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-814/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-814/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-814/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-814">
        <num>CHC 814</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-814__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A child may be taken into custody without a court order or warrant by a peace
officer or probation officer if the officer has probable cause to believe that the child has
committed a delinquent act.  When the officer has probable cause to believe that the child
has committed a delinquent act, the officer, in lieu of taking the child into custody, may issue
a verbal warning to the child.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-814__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a child is taken into custody without a court order or warrant, the officer shall
have the responsibility to either:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-814__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Counsel and release the child to the care of his parents upon their written promise
to bring the child to court at such time as may be fixed by the court.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-814__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Follow the appropriate procedures set forth in Article 815.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-814__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the officer does not release the child to the care of his parents, the officer shall
promptly notify the child's parents that he has been taken into custody.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-814__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The officer shall immediately execute a written statement of facts, sworn to before
an officer authorized by law to administer oaths, supporting the existence of probable cause
to believe either that the child committed a delinquent act or that the child has violated the
terms of his probation or otherwise has violated the terms of his release.  This affidavit shall
be submitted to the juvenile court.  Within forty-eight hours after the child has been taken
into custody, including legal holidays within the time computation, the court shall review the
affidavit, and if it determines that probable cause exists, the child shall be held for a
continued custody hearing pursuant to Article 819.  If the court determines that probable
cause does not exist, the child shall be released from custody.  The provisions of this
Paragraph shall not be construed to require the officer who executed the written statement
to personally appear in court for any determination of probable cause in connection with the
child being taken into custody.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-814__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The officer shall submit a report to the district attorney or an officer designated
by the court to receive such reports.  The report shall include:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-814__subsec_E__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The name, address, date of birth, sex, and race of the child.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-814__subsec_E__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The name and address of the parents, or spouse, if any, of the child.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-814__subsec_E__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A plain and concise statement of the facts and circumstances of the officer's
taking the child into custody.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-814__subsec_E__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A plain and concise statement of facts and circumstances showing probable cause
that the child committed a delinquent act.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-814__subsec_E__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A statement indicating whether the child was released, or escorted to a juvenile
detention center, or placed in a shelter care facility.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-814__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the child is released pursuant to Paragraph B or D of this Article, the report shall
be submitted by the officer within seven days from the child's release.  If the child is not so
released, the report shall be submitted within twenty-four hours of the child being taken into
custody.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=73405</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>