<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1353"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1353"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 1353"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1353/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1353/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1353/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-1353/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-1353">
        <num>CHC 1353</num>
        <heading>1353.  Support provisions; contempt; penalties; defenses</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1353__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the defendant violates the terms of the court order, the court, upon motion, may
issue an order directing the defendant to show cause why he or she should not be found in
contempt of court for failure to pay the court ordered support or maintain health care
insurance, which rule shall be tried in a summary manner.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1353__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If on the hearing of such rule the court finds the accused guilty of contempt for
failure to comply with the judgment of the court in paying the support assessed, the court
may punish for such contempt as follows, either:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1353__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The court may sentence the defendant to be imprisoned for not more than six
months.  The court in its discretion may suspend this term of imprisonment in whole or in
part on condition that the defendant pay the total amount of unpaid support and obtain health
care insurance in a manner to be determined by the court and on such other conditions as set
by the court.  If the court suspends the sentence in whole or in part, the court may place the
defendant on probation under R.S. 15:305 with conditions of probation to be set by the court. 
In addition, the court may fine the defendant an amount not to exceed one hundred dollars
to be paid to the applicable payee.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1353__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The court may order the defendant to pay the total amount of unpaid support to
the applicable payee and obtain health care insurance within a period of time fixed by the
court.  During this period of time, the defendant may be released upon giving bond for his
appearance in court if he fails to comply with the order of the court within the period of time
fixed.  Should the defendant not pay the total amount of unpaid support which the court has
ordered, the defendant shall be imprisoned for not more than six months.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1353__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon a second or subsequent finding of contempt, the court shall sentence the
defendant to imprisonment for not more than six months.  At the discretion of the judge, the
sentence may be suspended by the court upon the occurrence of all of the following:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1353__subsec_C__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Payment of the amount of unpaid support.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1353__subsec_C__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Payment of the amount of unpaid support accrued since the date of the said order.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1353__subsec_C__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Payment of the amount of all attendant court costs.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-1353__subsec_C__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Proof of health care insurance.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1353__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon recommendation of the state attorney or the support enforcement officer,
or both, the remainder of the sentence may be suspended upon payment of a lesser amount,
plus attendant court costs.  Such payment shall apply toward but not extinguish the total
amount due.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1353__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the court finds the accused guilty of contempt, the  court shall also render
judgment directing the defendant to obtain health care insurance and to pay the total amount
of unpaid support to the applicable payee, and attendant court costs.  Such judgment for the
payment of unpaid support and court costs shall have the same force and effect as a final
judgment for money damages against the defendant.  This judgment may be made executory
by any Louisiana court of competent jurisdiction on petition of the department or the district
attorney.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1353__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the defendant has entered into a recognizance in the amount fixed by the court
to insure the payment of the support and maintenance of health care insurance, the court may
order the forfeiture of the recognizance and enforcement thereof by execution.  The sum
recovered shall be paid in whole or in part to the applicable payee. However, should the court
order both the forfeiture of the recognizance and at the same time order the defendant to pay
all unpaid support under the sentence for contempt, the amount of unpaid support plus
attendant court costs and fines shall be the maximum payable.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-1353__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>It is a defense as provided by R.S. 9:311.1 to a charge of contempt of court for
failure to comply with a court order of child support if an obligor can prove that he was
incarcerated during the period of noncompliance.  This defense applies only to the time
period of actual incarceration.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=72894</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>