<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-644"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-644"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 644"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-644/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-644/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-644/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-644/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-644">
        <num>CHC 644</num>
        <heading>644.  Duties of curator ad hoc</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-644__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The curator ad hoc shall make a diligent effort to locate the parent and notify him
of the pendency and nature of the proceedings.  Such notice shall include:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-644__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The allegations made against the parent.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-644__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The right of the parent to appear at the hearing, to defend against the allegations,
and to compel the attendance of witnesses in his behalf.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-644__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The right of the parent to retain counsel, or to have counsel appointed if indigent.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-644__subsec_A__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The possibility that the parent may be able to enter into an informal adjustment
agreement, to consent to judgment, or to transfer custody, with the consent of the court.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-644__subsec_A__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The parent's responsibility to notify the department and his counsel in writing of
his current whereabouts, including his address, cellular number, telephone number, and any
other contact information, and that if he fails to do so, the law authorizes hearings to be held
in his absence.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-644__subsec_A__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The parent's responsibility to notify the department and the court in writing of the
current whereabouts, including address, cellular number, telephone number, and any other
contact information, of the child's other parent and any relative or other individual willing
and able to offer a wholesome and stable home for the child.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-644__subsec_A__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The parent's responsibility to support the achievement of timely permanency for
the child.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-644__subsec_A__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The parent's responsibility to advise the department and the court in writing of
the whereabouts, including the address, cellular number, telephone number, and any other
contact information, of all grandparents, all parents of a sibling where such parent has legal
custody of such sibling, and all other adult relatives of the child.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-644__subsec_A__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The possibility that a judicial certification for adoption proceeding may be
initiated if the child remains in the custody of the state.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-644__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the curator ad hoc fails to locate the parent, the curator ad hoc shall attend the
hearing of this matter, submit a note of evidence on the record indicating the efforts made
to locate the parent, and proceed contradictorily unless the parent is subsequently served or
waives objection to jurisdiction.  Proceedings held contradictorily with the curator ad hoc
shall be of full force and legal effect against the parent.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-644__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the parent is subsequently served in accordance with either Article 640 or 641
or is located by the curator ad hoc, the curator ad hoc shall be required only to attend the
hearing and submit a note of evidence on the record indicating the efforts made to locate the
parent.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=73237</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>