<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-801"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-801"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CE 801"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-801/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-801/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-801/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-801/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CE-801">
        <num>CE 801</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="CE-801__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Statement.  A &quot;statement&quot; is:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CE-801__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An oral or written assertion; or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-801__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Nonverbal conduct of a person, if it is intended by him as an assertion.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CE-801__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Declarant.  A &quot;declarant&quot; is a person who makes a statement.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CE-801__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Hearsay.  &quot;Hearsay&quot; is a statement, other than one made by the declarant while
testifying at the present trial or hearing, offered in evidence to prove the truth of the matter
asserted.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CE-801__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Statements which are not hearsay.  A statement is not hearsay if:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CE-801__subsec_D__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Prior statement by witness.  The declarant testifies at the trial or hearing and is
subject to cross-examination concerning the statement, and the statement is:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-801__subsec_D__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>In a criminal case, inconsistent with his testimony, provided that the proponent
has first fairly directed the witness' attention to the statement and the witness has been given
the opportunity to admit the fact and where there exists any additional evidence to
corroborate the matter asserted by the prior inconsistent statement;</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-801__subsec_D__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Consistent with his testimony and is offered to rebut an express or implied charge
against him of recent fabrication or improper influence or motive;</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-801__subsec_D__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>One of identification of a person made after perceiving the person; or</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-801__subsec_D__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Consistent with the declarant's testimony and is one of initial complaint of
sexually assaultive behavior.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-801__subsec_D__subsec_1__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A statement made by the victim of a sexually oriented criminal offense to a
healthcare provider during the course of a forensic medical examination as defined in R.S.
15:622 and the healthcare provider has documented that statement in writing during the
course of the forensic medical examination.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-801__subsec_D__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Personal, adoptive, and authorized admissions.  The statement is offered against
a party and is:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-801__subsec_D__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>His own statement, in either his individual or a representative capacity;</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-801__subsec_D__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A statement of which he has manifested his adoption or belief in its truth; or</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-801__subsec_D__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A statement by a person authorized by him to make a statement concerning the
subject.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-801__subsec_D__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Relational and privity admissions.  The statement is offered against a party, and
the statement is:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-801__subsec_D__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A statement by an agent or employee of the party against whom it is offered,
concerning a matter within the scope of his agency or employment, made during the
existence of the relationship;</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-801__subsec_D__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A statement by a declarant while participating in a conspiracy to commit a crime
or civil wrong and in furtherance of the objective of the conspiracy, provided that a prima
facie case of conspiracy is established;</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-801__subsec_D__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>In a civil case, a statement by a declarant when the liability, obligation, or duty
of the party against whom it is offered is derivatively based in whole or in part upon a
liability, obligation, or duty of the declarant, or when the claim or right asserted by that party
is barred or diminished by a breach of duty by the declarant, and when the statement would
be admissible if offered against the declarant as a party in an action involving that liability,
obligation, or breach of duty;</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-801__subsec_D__subsec_3__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>In a civil case, a statement by a declarant when a right, title, or interest in any
property or claim asserted by the party against whom it is offered requires a determination
that a right, title, or interest exists or existed in the declarant during the time that that party
now claims the declarant was the holder of the right, title, or interest, and when the statement
would be admissible if offered against the declarant as a party in an action involving that
right, title, or interest;</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-801__subsec_D__subsec_3__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A statement by a declarant offered against the party in an action for damages
arising from the death of that declarant; or</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CE-801__subsec_D__subsec_3__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A statement by a minor child offered against a party in an action to recover for
injury to that child, or against the person responsible for the child in an action to recover
damages for losses caused by the child.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-801__subsec_D__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Things said or done.  The statements are events speaking for themselves under
the immediate pressure of the occurrence, through the instructive, impulsive and spontaneous
words and acts of the participants, and not the words of the participants when narrating the
events, and which are necessary incidents of the criminal act, or immediate concomitants of
it, or form in conjunction with it one continuous transaction.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CE-801__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Optical disk imaging system.  &quot;Optical disk imaging system&quot; means a storage
system that utilizes non-erasable Write Once Read Many (WORM) optical storage
technology to record information on an optical disk with the use of laser technology, and that
utilizes laser technology to retrieve and read previously stored information.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=72511</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>