<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-895-1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-895-1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 895.1"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-895-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-895-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-895-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-895-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-895-1">
        <num>CCRP 895.1</num>
        <heading>895.1.  Probation; restitution; judgment for restitution; fees</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-895-1__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>When a court suspends the imposition or the execution of a sentence and places
the defendant on probation, it may in its discretion, order placed, as a condition of probation,
an amount of money to be paid by the defendant to any or all of the following:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895-1__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To the indigent defender program for that court.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895-1__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To the criminal court fund to defray the costs of operation of that court.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895-1__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To the sheriff and clerk of court for costs incurred.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895-1__subsec_B__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To a law enforcement agency for the reasonable costs incurred in arresting the
defendant, in felony cases involving the distribution of or intent to distribute controlled
dangerous substances.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895-1__subsec_B__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To the victim to compensate him for his loss and inconvenience.  Such an amount
may be in addition to any amounts ordered to be paid by the defendant under Paragraph A
herein.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895-1__subsec_B__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To a duly incorporated crime stoppers organization for the reasonable costs
incurred in obtaining information which leads to the arrest of the defendant.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895-1__subsec_B__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To a local public or private nonprofit agency involved in drug abuse prevention
and treatment for supervising a treatment program ordered by the court for a particular
defendant, provided that such agency is qualified as a tax-exempt organization under Section
501</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-895-1__subsec_B__subsec_7__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of the Internal Revenue Code of the United States.  Any nonprofit agency receiving
money under the provisions of this Paragraph must be licensed by the Louisiana Department
of Health in the supervision of drug abuse prevention and treatment.
C.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895-1__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>When the court places the defendant on supervised probation, it shall order as
a condition of probation a monthly fee of not less than sixty nor more than one hundred ten
dollars payable to the Department of Public Safety and Corrections or such other probation
office, agency, or officer as designated by the court, to defray the cost of supervision which
includes salaries for probation and parole officers.  If the probation supervision services are
rendered by an agency other than the department, the fee may be ordered payable to that
agency.  These fees are only to supplement the level of funds that would ordinarily be
available from regular state appropriations or any other source of funding.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895-1__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>When the court places the defendant on unsupervised probation, it shall order as
a condition of probation a monthly fee of not more than one dollar payable to the Department
of Public Safety and Corrections or such other probation office, agency, or officer as
designated by the court.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-895-1__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court may, in lieu of the monthly supervision fee provided for in Paragraph
C of this Article, require the defendant to perform a specified amount of community service
work each month if the court finds the defendant is unable to pay the minimum supervision
fee provided for in Paragraph C of this Article.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-895-1__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>When the court places any defendant convicted of a violation of the Uniform
Controlled Dangerous Substances Law, R.S. 40:966 through 1034, on any type of probation,
it shall order as a condition of probation a fee of not less than fifty nor more than one
hundred dollars, payable to the Louisiana Commission on Law Enforcement and
Administration of Criminal Justice to be credited to the Drug Abuse Education and
Treatment Dedicated Fund Account and used for the purposes provided in R.S. 15:1224.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-895-1__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>When the court places the defendant on supervised probation, it shall order as a
condition of probation the payment of a monthly fee of eleven dollars.  The monthly fee
established in this Paragraph shall be in addition to the fee established in Paragraph C of this
Article and shall be collected by the Department of Public Safety and Corrections and shall
be transmitted, deposited, appropriated, and used in accordance with the following
provisions:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895-1__subsec_F__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The monthly fee established in this Paragraph shall be deposited immediately
upon receipt in the state treasury.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895-1__subsec_F__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>After compliance with the requirements of Article VII, Section 9(B) of the
Constitution of Louisiana relative to the Bond Security and Redemption Fund, and prior to
monies being placed in the state general fund, the treasurer shall credit an amount equal to
that deposited as required by Subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895-1__subsec_F__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Paragraph to a special agency account
to be retained for future appropriation as provided in this Article which is hereby created in
the state treasury to be known as the &quot;Sex Offender Registry Technology Dedicated Fund
Account&quot;.  The monies in this account shall be used solely as provided in Subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895-1__subsec_F__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Paragraph and only in the amounts appropriated by the legislature.  Monies deposited
into this account shall be categorized as fees and self-generated revenue for the sole purpose
of reporting related to the executive budget, supporting documents, and general
appropriations bills and shall be available for annual appropriations by the legislature.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-895-1__subsec_F__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The monies in the Sex Offender Registry Technology Dedicated Fund Account
shall be appropriated as follows:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-895-1__subsec_F__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For Fiscal Year 2006-2007, the amount of one hundred ninety thousand dollars
to the Department of Public Safety and Corrections, office of state police, to be used in the
administration of programs for the registration of sex offenders in compliance with federal
and state laws, and support of community notification efforts by local law enforcement
agencies. For Fiscal Years 2007-2008 through 2009-2010, the amount to be appropriated
under this Subparagraph shall be twenty-five thousand dollars.  For Fiscal Years 2010-2011,
and thereafter, the amount to be appropriated to the Department of Public Safety and
Corrections, office of state police, shall be twenty-five thousand dollars for the purposes of
maintaining and administering the programs for the registration of sex offenders pursuant to
this Subparagraph and special law enforcement initiatives.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-895-1__subsec_F__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For Fiscal Year 2010-2011 and each year thereafter, an amount equal to fifteen
percent of the total residual monies available for appropriation from the account shall be
appropriated to the Department of Public Safety and Corrections, office of adult services,
division of probation and parole.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-895-1__subsec_F__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For Fiscal Year 2010-2011 through Fiscal Year 2013-2014, residual monies
available for appropriation after satisfying the requirements of Subsubparagraphs</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-895-1__subsec_F__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>and</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-895-1__subsec_F__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this Subparagraph shall be appropriated to the Department of Justice, office of the attorney
general.  Of that residual amount, one hundred fifty thousand dollars shall be allocated to the
office of the attorney general of which fifty thousand dollars shall be allocated for personnel
and other costs to assist and monitor sheriff participation in utilization of the computer
system, and one hundred thousand dollars of which shall be allocated to the cost of
maintenance of the computer system which shall interface with the computer systems of the
sheriffs of the parishes for registration of sex offenders and child predators.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-895-1__subsec_F__subsec_3__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For Fiscal Year 2014-2015, and thereafter, residual monies available for
appropriation after satisfying the requirements of Subsubparagraphs</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-895-1__subsec_F__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>and</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-895-1__subsec_F__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this
Subparagraph shall be appropriated to the Department of Justice, office of the attorney
general.  Of that residual amount, two hundred and fifty thousand dollars shall be allocated
to the office of the attorney general of which one hundred and fifty thousand dollars shall be
allocated for personnel and other costs to assist and monitor sheriff participation in
utilization of the computer system and the administration of the sex offender and child
predator registration and notification laws as set forth in R.S. 15:540 et seq., and one hundred
thousand dollars of which shall be allocated to the cost of maintenance of the computer
system of the sheriffs of the parishes for registration of sex offenders and child predators.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-895-1__subsec_F__subsec_3__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>After providing for the allocations in Subsubparagraphs (a), (b), (c), and</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="CCRP-895-1__subsec_F__subsec_3__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of
this Subparagraph, the remainder of the residual monies in the Sex Offender Registry
Technology Dedicated Fund Account shall, pursuant to an appropriation to the office of the
attorney general, be distributed to the sheriff of each parish, based on the population of
convicted sex offenders, sexually violent predators, and child predators who are residing in
the parish and who are active sex offender registrants or active child predator registrants in
the respective parishes according to the State Sex Offender and Child Predator Registry.
These funds shall be used to cover the costs associated with sex offender registration and
compliance. Population data necessary to implement the provisions of this Subparagraph
shall be as compiled and certified by the undersecretary of the Department of Public Safety
and Corrections on the first day of June of each year. No later than thirty days after the
Revenue Estimating Conference recognizes the prior year account balance, the office of the
attorney general shall make these distributions, which are based on the data certified by the
undersecretary of the Department of Public Safety and Corrections, to the recipient sheriffs
who are actively registering offenders pursuant to this Paragraph.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112893</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>