<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-508"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-508"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CE 508"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-508/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-508/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-508/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CE-508/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CE-508">
        <num>CE 508</num>
        <heading>508.  Subpoena of lawyer or his representative in civil cases</heading>
        <subsection eId="CE-508__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>General rule.  Neither a subpoena nor a court order shall be issued to a lawyer or his representative to appear or testify in any civil or juvenile proceeding, including pretrial discovery, or in an administrative investigation or hearing, where the purpose of the subpoena or order is to ask the lawyer or his representative to reveal information about a client or former client obtained in the course of representing the client unless, after a contradictory hearing, it has been determined that the information sought is not protected from disclosure by any applicable privilege or work product rule; and all of the following:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CE-508__subsec_A__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The information sought is essential to the successful completion of an ongoing investigation, is essential to the case of the party seeking the information, and is not merely peripheral, cumulative, or speculative.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-508__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The purpose of seeking the information is not to harass the attorney or his client.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-508__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>With respect to a subpoena, the subpoena lists the information sought with particularity, is reasonably limited as to subject matter and period of time, and gives timely notice.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CE-508__subsec_A__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>There is no practicable alternative means of obtaining the information.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CE-508__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Waiver.  Failure to object timely to non-compliance with the terms of this Article constitutes a waiver of the procedural protections of this Article, but does not constitute a waiver of any privilege.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CE-508__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Binding effect of determination; notice to client.  The determination that a lawyer-client privilege is not applicable to the testimony shall not bind the client or former client unless the client or former client was given notice of the time, place, and substance of the hearing and had an opportunity fully to participate in that hearing.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CE-508__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Scope.  Nothing in this Article is intended to affect the provisions of Code of Civil Procedure Articles 863 and 1452(B).</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CE-508__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The procedural provisions and protections afforded by Paragraph A of this Article shall extend to lawyers representing the state or any political subdivision, whether the lawyer is the attorney general or assistant attorney general, a district attorney or assistant district attorney, a parish attorney or assistant parish attorney; or a municipal or city attorney or assistant municipal or assistant city attorney; and shall extend to lawyers employed by either house of the Louisiana Legislature.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=72479</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>