<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-615"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-615"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 615"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-615/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-615/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-615/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-615/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-615">
        <num>CHC 615</num>
        <heading>615.  Disposition of reports</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-615__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In determining the disposition of the report, the agency shall take into account,
in mitigation, the possibility of accidental injury or condition, or that the injury resulted from
what might be considered a reasonable exercise of discipline for the child's misbehavior.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-615__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>After investigation, the local child protection unit shall make one of the following
determinations:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-615__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The child appears to be a child in need of care and the child's immediate removal
is necessary for protection from further abuse or neglect, in which case, whenever
extraordinary justification arises, the local child protection unit shall apply for an instanter
removal order to place the child in the custody of a suitable relative or other suitable
individual capable of protecting the health, welfare, and safety of the child or the state as
authorized by Articles 619 and 620 and shall notify the district attorney as soon as possible.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-615__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The report  is substantiated, in that there is evidence of child abuse, or neglect,
and a protective order or instanter safety plan order would eliminate the need for removal of
the child in order to protect him from further abuse, in which case it may apply for a
temporary restraining order or protective order authorized by Articles 617 and 618, or an
instanter safety plan order authorized by Article 619 or 620.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-615__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The report  is substantiated, in that there is evidence of child abuse or neglect,
in which case it shall report all pertinent information to the district attorney, as soon as
possible but in no case more than thirty days after such determination, for evaluation of
whether a child in need of care petition should be filed in the court with juvenile jurisdiction.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-615__subsec_B__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The report is inconclusive, in that the evidence tends to support a finding of
abuse or neglect, but there is not enough  information to confirm a justified report.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-615__subsec_B__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The report  is unsubstantiated as the evidence does not support a finding of child
abuse or neglect.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-615__subsec_B__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The investigation indicates the report appears to be false and that the reporter
knowingly made a false report in which case all pertinent information shall be forwarded to
the district attorney for a determination of whether the evidence supports a finding of a false
public report.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-615__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition to investigation or assessment of reports, or both, the local child
protection family services unit may offer available information, referrals, or services to the
family when there appears to be some need for medical, mental health, social, basic support,
supervision, or other services. Assignments for case response and allocation of resources
shall be made in the order of children at greatest risk of harm to the lowest risk of harm. The
individualized intervention strategies based on this risk assessment may include concurrent
planning.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-615__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Violation of the duties imposed by this Article subjects the offender to criminal
prosecution authorized by R.S. 14:403(A)(2).</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-615__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>When after the investigation of a report, the determination is made that the report
is inconclusive or  unsubstantiated, as provided in Subparagraphs (B)</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-615__subsec_E__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-615__subsec_E__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this
Article, the files, records, and pertinent information regarding the report and investigation
shall be strictly confidential, shall not become part of the central registry except as otherwise
provided in Subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-615__subsec_E__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Paragraph or in Article 616(F), shall not be disclosed
or ordered to be produced in conjunction with any legal proceeding or other matter except
as provided in Subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-615__subsec_E__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Paragraph, and shall be maintained only for the
following purposes:</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-615__subsec_E__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The files, records, and information shall remain unsealed and shall be maintained
for the exclusive use of child protective services, to assist in future risk and safety
assessments. The Department of Children and Family Services shall maintain all files and
records for seven years from the date of the determination, unless a subsequent inconclusive
or  unsubstantiated report is received during that period. In that case, information from all
such reports will be maintained until the youngest child in the alleged victim's family attains
the age of eighteen years or seven years from the date of the latest determination, whichever
is longer. If information from an inconclusive or  unsubstantiated report is used as a part of
the basis for a later, related, and  substantiated report, the earlier report shall become part of
the file of the  substantiated report and shall cease to be a separate report.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-615__subsec_E__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>All files, records, and information shall be admissible in any civil litigation or
criminal proceeding against the Department of Children and Family Services or its
employees wherein work performance or conduct is at issue.  They shall remain confidential
and be placed under seal by the court to prevent disclosure to the public.  The department
shall maintain the files, records and information during the pendency of the litigation or
prosecution.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-615__subsec_E__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>All files, records, and information regarding a report that has been determined
to be inconclusive may be released to law enforcement investigators in the course of
investigations of crimes involving acts against children in order to assist in the proper
evaluation of current reports of abuse which may include a pattern of incidents. 
Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, these files, records, and
information shall remain confidential and shall not be subject to disclosure pursuant to R.S.
44:1 et seq.  If a court determines that the files, records, and information are admissible in
criminal proceedings involving acts against children, those files, records, and information
shall be placed under seal by the court to prevent disclosure to the public.
(4)</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-615__subsec_E__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>All files, records, and information regarding a report that has been determined
to be inconclusive or  unsubstantiated shall be released to local, state, and federal law
enforcement agencies, military authorities, prosecuting authorities, and coroners upon request
when such entity is in the course of investigations or legal proceedings and the requesting
entity has good cause to believe that the files, records, or information contain information
which may be constitutionally required to be disclosed pursuant to Brady v. Maryland, 373
U.S. 83</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-615__subsec_E__subsec_1963">
            <num>(1963)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and its progeny. The requesting agency shall request the information in
writing and state the purpose for which the information is being requested.</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="CHC-615__subsec_E__subsec_1963__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Files, records, and information released pursuant to this Subparagraph shall be
confidential and shall not be further disclosed except as expressly authorized by Article 412. 
Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, files, records, and information
released pursuant to this Subparagraph shall not be subject to disclosure pursuant to R.S.
44:1 et seq.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-615__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The department shall promulgate rules to provide for the disposition, handling,
maintenance, and storage of inconclusive and  unsubstantiated reports in keeping with this
Article. Nothing in this Article shall be construed to modify or abrogate the provisions of
R.S. 44:411.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-615__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as provided in Subparagraph (B)</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-615__subsec_G__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Article, the name of the
reporter shall not be disclosed.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=73207</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>