<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-930-4"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-930-4"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 930.4"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-930-4/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-930-4/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-930-4/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-930-4/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-930-4">
        <num>CCRP 930.4</num>
        <heading>930.4.  Jurisdictional bars to relief; repetitive applications</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-930-4__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any claim for relief which was fully litigated in an appeal from the proceedings
leading to the judgment of conviction and sentence shall not be considered.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-930-4__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the application alleges a claim of which the petitioner had knowledge and
inexcusably failed to raise in the proceedings leading to conviction, the court shall deny
relief.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-930-4__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the application alleges a claim which the petitioner raised in the trial court and
inexcusably failed to pursue on appeal, the court shall deny relief.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-930-4__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the application alleges a claim seeking to apply a new rule of criminal
procedure that has been held by the United States Supreme Court and the Louisiana Supreme
Court to be nonretroactive, the court shall deny relief.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-930-4__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A successive application shall be dismissed if it fails to raise a new or different
claim.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-930-4__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A successive application shall be dismissed if it raises a new or different claim
that was inexcusably omitted from a prior application.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-930-4__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any attempt or request by a petitioner to supplement or amend the application
shall be subject to all of the limitations and restrictions set forth in this Article.  In addition
to serving the district attorney for the jurisdiction where the underlying conviction was
obtained, any subsequent, successive, amending, or supplemental application shall be served
by the petitioner on the district attorney and the attorney general.  If the court subsequently
orders any hearing on the application, the court shall send notice to the district attorney and
attorney general at least sixty days in advance of the hearing date.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-930-4__subsec_H">
          <num>H.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The limitations set forth in this Article shall be jurisdictional and shall not be
waived or excused by the court or the district attorney.
Added by</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112945</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>