<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-926-1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-926-1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 926.1"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-926-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-926-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-926-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-926-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-926-1">
        <num>CCRP 926.1</num>
        <heading>926.1.  Application for DNA testing</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-926-1__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>An application filed under the provisions of this Article shall comply with the
provisions of Article 926  and shall allege all of the following:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-926-1__subsec_B__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A factual explanation of why there is an articulable doubt, based on competent
evidence whether or not introduced at trial, as to the guilt of the petitioner in that DNA
testing will resolve the doubt and establish the innocence of the petitioner.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-926-1__subsec_B__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The factual circumstances establishing the timeliness of the application.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-926-1__subsec_B__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The identification of the particular evidence for which DNA testing is sought.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-926-1__subsec_B__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>That the applicant is factually innocent of the crime for which he was convicted,
in the form of an affidavit signed by the petitioner under penalty of perjury.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-926-1__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition to any other reason established by legislation or jurisprudence, and
whether based on the petition and answer or after contradictory hearing, the court shall
dismiss any application filed pursuant to this Article unless it finds all of the following:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-926-1__subsec_C__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>There is an articulable doubt based on competent evidence, whether or not
introduced at trial, as to the guilt of the petitioner and there is a reasonable likelihood that the
requested DNA testing will resolve the doubt and establish the innocence of the petitioner. 
In making this finding the court shall evaluate and consider the evidentiary importance of the
DNA sample to be tested.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-926-1__subsec_C__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The application has been timely filed.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-926-1__subsec_C__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The evidence to be tested is available and in a condition that would permit DNA
testing.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-926-1__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Relief under this Article shall not be granted when the court finds that there is a
substantial question as to the integrity of the evidence to be tested.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-926-1__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Relief under this Article shall not be granted solely because there is evidence
currently available for DNA testing but the testing was not available or was not done at the
time of the conviction.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-926-1__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Once an application has been filed and the court determines the location of the
evidence sought to be tested, the court shall serve a copy of the application on the district
attorney and the law enforcement agency which has possession of the evidence to be tested,
including but not limited to sheriffs, the office of state police, local police agencies, and
crime laboratories.  If the court grants relief under this Article and orders DNA testing the
court shall also issue such orders as are appropriate to obtain the necessary samples to be
tested and to protect their integrity.  The testing shall be conducted by a laboratory mutually
agreed upon by the district attorney and the petitioner.  If the parties cannot agree, the court
shall designate a laboratory to perform the tests that is accredited in forensic DNA analysis
by an accrediting body that is a signatory to the International Laboratory Accreditation
Cooperation Mutual Recognition Arrangements for Testing Laboratories (ILAC MRA) and
requires conformance to an accreditation program based on the international standard
ISO/IEC 17025 with an accreditation scope in the field of forensic science testing in the
discipline of biology, and that is compliant with the current version of the Federal Bureau
of Investigations Quality Assurance Standards for Forensic DNA Testing Laboratories.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-926-1__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the court orders the testing performed at a private laboratory, the district
attorney shall have the right to withhold a sufficient portion of any unknown sample for
purposes of his independent testing.  Under such circumstances, the petitioner shall submit
DNA samples to the district attorney for purposes of comparison with the unknown sample
retained by the district attorney.  A laboratory selected to perform the analysis shall, if
possible, retain and maintain the integrity of a sufficient portion of the unknown sample for
replicate testing.  If after initial examination of the evidence, but before actual testing, the
laboratory decides that there is insufficient evidentially significant material for replicate tests,
then it shall notify the district attorney in writing of its finding.  If the petitioner and district
attorney cannot agree, the court shall determine which laboratory as required by Paragraph
F of this Article is best suited to conduct the testing and shall fashion its order to allow the
laboratory conducting the tests to consume the entirety of the unknown sample for testing
purposes if necessary.
H.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-926-1__subsec_G__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The results of the DNA testing ordered under this Article shall be filed by the
laboratory with the court and served upon the petitioner and the district attorney.  The court
may, in its discretion, order production of the underlying facts or data and laboratory notes.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-926-1__subsec_G__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>After service of the application on the district attorney and the law enforcement
agency in possession of the evidence, no evidence shall be destroyed that is relevant to a case
in which an application for DNA testing has been filed until the case has been finally
resolved by the court.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-926-1__subsec_G__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>After service of the application on the district attorney and the law enforcement
agency in possession of the evidence, the clerks of court of each parish and all law
enforcement agencies, including but not limited to district attorneys, sheriffs, the office of
state police, local police agencies, and crime laboratories, shall preserve until August 31,
2030, all items of evidence in their possession which are known to contain biological
material that can be subjected to DNA testing, in all cases that, as of August 15, 2001, have
been concluded by a verdict of guilty or a plea of guilty.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-926-1__subsec_G__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In all cases in which the defendant has been sentenced to death prior to August
15, 2001, the clerks of court of each parish and all law enforcement agencies, including but
not limited to district attorneys, sheriffs, the office of state police, local police agencies, and
crime laboratories shall preserve, until the execution of sentence is completed, all items of
evidence in their possession which are known to contain biological material that can be
subjected to DNA testing.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-926-1__subsec_G__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of Subparagraphs</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-926-1__subsec_G__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-926-1__subsec_G__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Paragraph,
after service of the application on the district attorney and the law enforcement agency in
possession of the evidence, the clerks of court of each parish and all law enforcement
agencies, including but not limited to district attorneys, sheriffs, the office of state police,
local police agencies, and crime laboratories may forward for proper storage and preservation
all items of evidence described in Subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-926-1__subsec_G__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Paragraph to a laboratory that is
accredited by an accrediting body that is a signatory to the International Laboratory
Accreditation Cooperation Mutual Recognition Arrangements for Testing Laboratories
(ILAC MRA) and requires conformance to an accreditation program based on the
international standard ISO/IEC 17025 with an accreditation scope in the field of forensic
science testing in the discipline of biology, and that is compliant with the current version of
the Federal Bureau of Investigations Quality Assurance Standards for Forensic DNA Testing
Laboratories.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-926-1__subsec_G__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except in the case of willful or wanton misconduct or gross negligence, no clerk
of court or law enforcement officer or law enforcement agency, including but not limited to
any district attorney, sheriff, the office of state police, local police agency, or crime
laboratory which is responsible for the storage or preservation of any item of evidence in
compliance with either the requirements of Subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-926-1__subsec_G__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Paragraph or R.S.
15:621 shall be held civilly or criminally liable for the unavailability or deterioration of any
such evidence to the extent that adequate or proper testing cannot be performed on the
evidence.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-926-1__subsec_I">
          <num>I.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The DNA profile of the petitioner obtained under this Article shall be sent by the
district attorney to the state police for inclusion in the state DNA data base established
pursuant to R.S. 15:605.  The petitioner may seek removal of his DNA record pursuant to
R.S. 15:614.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-926-1__subsec_J">
          <num>J.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The petitioner, in addition to other service requirements, shall mail a copy of the
application requesting DNA testing to the Department of Public Safety and Corrections,
Corrections Services, office of adult services.  If the court grants relief under this Article, the
court shall mail a copy of the order to the Department of Public Safety and  Corrections,
Corrections Services, office of adult services.  The Department of Public Safety and
Corrections, Corrections Services, office of adult services, shall keep a copy of all records
sent to them pursuant to this Subsection and report to the legislature before January 1, 2003,
on the number of petitions filed and the number of orders granting relief.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-926-1__subsec_K">
          <num>K.</num>
          <content>
            <p>There is hereby created in the state treasury a special fund designated as the DNA
Testing Post-Conviction Relief for Indigents Fund. The fund shall consist of money specially
appropriated by the legislature. No other public money may be used to pay for the DNA
testing authorized under the provisions of this Article. The fund shall be administered by the
office of the state public defender. The fund shall be segregated from all other funds and
shall be used exclusively for the purposes established under the provisions of this Article.
If the court finds that a petitioner under this Article is indigent, the fund shall pay for the
testing as authorized in the court order.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=112937</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>