<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-815"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-815"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 815"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-815/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-815/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-815/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-815/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-815">
        <num>CHC 815</num>
        <heading>815.  Child taken into custody; place of detention</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-815__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as provided in Paragraph E of this Article, if the child has been taken into
custody for the commission of a felony-grade delinquent act or of a misdemeanor-grade
delinquent act based upon an offense against the person of another, the child may be taken
to a juvenile detention center and the procedures regarding the administration of the
detention screening instrument set forth in Paragraph A of this Article shall apply.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-815__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as provided in Paragraph E of this Article, for the commission of any other
misdemeanor-grade delinquent act, the child may be taken to a juvenile detention center or
shelter care facility or released to a parent or guardian upon the written promise of the parent
or guardian to bring the child to court pursuant to Article 814.  If the child is not released to
a parent or guardian, the officer shall follow the procedures set forth in Paragraph A of this
Article.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-815__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The governing authority of the parish or municipality requesting placement of a
juvenile in either a regional detention center or a shelter care facility shall be responsible to
the regional detention center or shelter care facility for the cost of confinement in accordance
with a schedule which may be adopted by the regional detention center or shelter care
facility.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-815__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>No child under the age of thirteen shall be detained in a juvenile detention center
after being taken into custody for the alleged commission of a misdemeanor-grade delinquent
act.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-815__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a juvenile detention center is not available, a juvenile may be held in an adult
jail or lockup for purposes of and only as long as necessary to complete identification or
processing procedures or while awaiting transportation, but not to exceed six hours. 
However, in nonmetropolitan areas, the juvenile may be held for up to forty-eight hours if
all of the following occur:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-815__subsec_F__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The juvenile is accused of a nonstatus offense.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-815__subsec_F__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A continued custody hearing in accordance with Articles 820 and 821 is held
within forty-eight hours after his arrest.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-815__subsec_F__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>There is no acceptable alternative placement to the jail or lockup in which the
juvenile is being held.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CHC-815__subsec_F__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The sheriff or the administrator of the adult jail or lockup has certified to the
court that facilities exist that provide for sight and sound separation of the juvenile from
adult offenders and the juvenile can be given continuous visual supervision while placed in
the jail or lockup.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=73406</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>