<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-1003"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-1003"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CCRP 1003"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-1003/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-1003/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-1003/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CCRP-1003/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CCRP-1003">
        <num>CCRP 1003</num>
        <heading>1003.  Transfer or storage of transferred firearms</heading>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-1003__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The sheriff of each parish shall be responsible for oversight of firearm transfers
in his parish.  For each firearm transferred pursuant to this Title, the sheriff shall offer all of
the following options to the transferor:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-1003__subsec_A__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Store the transferred firearms in a storage facility with which the sheriff has
contracted for the storage of transferred firearms or with the sheriff.  The sheriff may charge
a reasonable fee for the storage of such firearms.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-1003__subsec_A__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Oversee the legal sale of the transferred firearms to a third party.  The sheriff may
contract with a licensed firearms dealer for such purpose.  The sheriff may charge a
reasonable fee to oversee the sale of firearms.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-1003__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The sheriff shall prepare a receipt for each firearm transferred and provide a copy
to the person transferring the firearms.  The receipt shall include the firearm manufacturer
and firearm serial number.  The receipt shall be signed by the officer accepting the firearms
and the person transferring the firearms.  The sheriff may require the receipt to be presented
before returning a transferred firearm.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-1003__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The sheriff shall keep a record of all transferred firearms including but not limited
to the name of the person transferring the firearm, the manufacturer, model, serial number,
and the manner in which the firearm is stored.
D.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-1003__subsec_C__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>When the person is no longer prohibited from possessing a firearm under state
or federal law, the person whose firearms were transferred pursuant to the provisions of this
Title may file a motion with the court seeking an order for the return of the transferred
firearms.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-1003__subsec_C__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon reviewing the motion, if the court determines that the person is no longer
prohibited from possessing a firearm under state or federal law, the court shall issue an order
stating that the firearms transferred pursuant to the provisions of this Title shall be returned
to the person.  The order shall include the date on which the person is no longer prohibited
from possessing a firearm and a copy of the order shall be sent to the sheriff.  However, all
outstanding fees shall be paid to the sheriff prior to the firearms being returned.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-1003__subsec_C__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>No sheriff or third party to whom the firearms were transferred pursuant to the
provisions of this Title, shall return a transferred firearm prior to receiving the order issued
by the court pursuant to the provisions of this Paragraph.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="CCRP-1003__subsec_C__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the person refuses to pay outstanding fees to the sheriff or fails to file a motion
with the court seeking an order for the return of the transferred firearms within one year of
the expiration of the prohibition on possessing firearms under state or federal law, the sheriff
may send, by United States mail to the person's last known address, a notice informing the
person that if he does not pay the outstanding fees to the sheriff or file a motion with the
court seeking an order for the return of the transferred firearms within ninety days, the
firearms shall be forfeited to the sheriff.  If, after ninety days from the mailing of the notice,
the person does not pay the outstanding fees to the sheriff or file a motion with the court
seeking an order for the return of the transferred firearms, the sheriff may file a motion
seeking a court order declaring that the firearms are forfeited to the sheriff, who may
thereafter dispose of the firearms at his discretion.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-1003__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The sheriff shall exercise due care to preserve the quality and function of all
firearms transferred under the provisions of this Title.  However, the sheriff shall not be
liable for damage to firearms except for cases of willful or wanton misconduct or gross
negligence.  In addition, the sheriff shall not be liable for damage caused by the third party
to whom the firearms were transferred pursuant to the provisions of this Title.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-1003__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nothing in this Title shall be construed to prohibit the sheriff, consistent with
constitutional requirements, from obtaining a search warrant to authorize testing or
examination upon any firearm so as to facilitate any criminal investigation or prosecution. 
Notwithstanding Article 163(C) or any other provision of law to the contrary, the testing or
examination of the firearms pursuant to the search warrant may be conducted at any time
before or during the pendency of any criminal proceeding in which the firearms, or the
testing or examination of the firearms, may be used as evidence, and shall not be subject to
the ten-day period in Article 163(C).</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CCRP-1003__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Not sooner than three years after the date on which a firearm or firearms are
returned pursuant to the provisions of this Article, the person may file a motion with the
court requesting that the records relative to the firearm or firearms held by the clerk of court
and by the sheriff be destroyed.  After a contradictory hearing with the sheriff and the district
attorney, which may be waived by the sheriff or the district attorney, the court, if the person
is no longer prohibited from possessing firearms under state or federal law and if the firearm
or firearms have actually been returned, shall order that the records held by the clerk of court
and by the sheriff relative to the returned firearm or firearms be destroyed.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=1106500</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>