<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-HRULE-1-2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-HRULE-1-2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="HRULE 1.2"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-HRULE-1-2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-HRULE-1-2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-HRULE-1-2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-HRULE-1-2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_HRULE-1-2">
        <num>HRULE 1.2</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="HRULE-1-2__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Only the members of the House and the Clerk of the House; officers and
employees of the House or of members of the House; the Secretary of the Senate, members
of the Senate and the officers and employees of the Senate, or of senators; the director of the
Legislative Council, the Legislative Auditor, the Legislative Fiscal Officer and their
employees shall be admitted on the floor while the House is in session.  The House floor, for
purposes of these rules, is defined as that area so designated in the diagram of the House
Chamber and House floor included in this rule.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="HRULE-1-2__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>One chair shall be permanently affixed to the floor at the desk of each House
member, and no other chairs shall be permitted on the floor of the House.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="HRULE-1-2__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Special permission to sit on the House floor may be granted by the presiding
officer of the House to visiting officials of other states or of the United States or of foreign
countries.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="HRULE-1-2__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A designated place in the House Chamber shall be provided for the news media,
who shall have free access thereto.  Accreditation of members of the press and of members
of any news media for admission shall be administered by the Speaker of the House or he
may delegate this function to the House and Governmental Affairs Committee.  No member
of the press or of any news media shall conduct any formal interview with a House member
on the House floor while the House is in session.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="HRULE-1-2__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Section A of the attached diagram shall be designated for use of employees of the
House and others designated in Paragraph A of this Rule and, upon permission of the
presiding officer of the House, it shall be for the use of family members and special guests
of House members.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="HRULE-1-2__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Section B of the attached diagram shall be provided with seating facilities for the
public and House members on a first-come, first-served basis.  No person shall be allowed
into this section unless there is an available seat.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="HRULE-1-2__subsec_G">
          <num>G.</num>
          <content>
            <p>One or more sergeants at arms shall be designated to supervise Section B, and one
or more employees shall be designated to carry messages from the public in this area to any
House member with whom a consultation is desired.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="HRULE-1-2__subsec_H">
          <num>H.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Seating facilities shall be provided for the public in the House gallery. 
Admittance shall be under such conditions as determined by the presiding officer of the
House.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="HRULE-1-2__subsec_I">
          <num>I.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Only members of the House and of the Senate and legislative staff shall be
admitted to the legislative lounges.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="HRULE-1-2__subsec_J">
          <num>J.</num>
          <content>
            <p>An interpreter designated and authorized by the presiding officer of the House to
provide speech translation services for the House of Representatives shall be admitted to the
floor while the House is in session in order to provide such services.
Mason's Manual:  Sec. 705(3 and 6)
HR 3, 1973; HR 7, 1975; HR 4, 1978; HR 14, 1985; HR 4, 1st Ex. Sess., 1988; HR
13, 1988; HR 8, 1991, eff. Jan. 13, 1991; HR 45, 1998, eff. May 20, 1998; HR 3, 2018.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=113192</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>