<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-919"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-919"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 919"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-919/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-919/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-919/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-919/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-919">
        <num>CHC 919</num>
        <heading>919.  Procedure for expungement and sealing; motions; order</heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-919__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>A person may move for the expungement and sealing of his records and reports.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-919__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The motion for expungement and sealing shall be substantially in the form
provided in Article 925 and shall state facts that constitute grounds for expungement and
sealing under Article 918.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-919__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The motion for expungement and sealing shall be filed with the court possessing
the records and reports, or with the court exercising juvenile jurisdiction over the arresting
agency.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-919__subsec_D">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The motion shall be served personally or by domiciliary service, or by United
States mail or electronic means, on the district attorney, the clerk of the court whose records
and reports are sought to be expunged and sealed, and the head of any agency whose records
and reports are sought to be expunged and sealed, including but not limited to the Federal
Bureau of Investigation, the Louisiana Bureau of Criminal Identification and Information,
the Department of Public Safety and Corrections, office of juvenile justice, and local law
enforcement agencies.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-919__subsec_E">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any person or agency that objects to the granting of the motion for a matter that
resulted in a delinquency adjudication for a misdemeanor offense or for a felony offense shall
file an affidavit of response in the form provided in Article 926, and a contradictory hearing
shall be conducted with the district attorney and any agency whose records and reports are
sought to be expunged and sealed.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-919__subsec_F">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the court finds that the grounds have been established and that the person is
entitled to expungement and sealing, the court shall order expungement and sealing.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=73513</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>