<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-571"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-571"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#louisiana-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-la"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="CHC 571"/>
          <FRBRname value="LRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-571/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-571/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-571/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-la/act/lrs/title-0/sec-CHC-571/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="louisiana-legislature" href="https://www.legis.la.gov" showAs="Louisiana State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_CHC-571">
        <num>CHC 571</num>
        <heading>Section </heading>
        <subsection eId="CHC-571__subsec_A">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The legislature finds that society has a responsibility to provide indigent or absent
parents with quality legal representation, including curatorship appointments, in child abuse
and neglect cases.  Provision of counsel for indigent parents or curators for absent parents
are essential due process rights provided by Louisiana law to ensure sound and fair decision-making concerning children's safety, permanency, and well-being.  Legal counsel providing
representation in child abuse and neglect cases should have specialized knowledge and skills
essential for effective representation.  Resources to support the provision of legal
representation, including curatorship appointments, of indigent or absent parents should be
used efficiently and equitably to assure qualified representation throughout the state.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-571__subsec_B">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The legislature finds that there is a need for a uniform system of representation
of indigent or absent parents statewide that provides for appropriate oversight, minimization
of potential conflicts, and adequate local and state funding.  To this end, the legislature finds
that local public defender offices best serve the interests of children and families by
representing indigent or absent parents, which shall include curatorship appointments, in
child abuse and neglect cases consistent with the provisions of R S. 15:185.1 et seq., and
with the Trial Court Performance Standards for Attorneys Representing Parents in Child in
Need of Care and Termination of Parental Right Cases provided in Chapter 11 of Part XV
of Title 22 of the Louisiana Administrative Code.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="CHC-571__subsec_C">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Repealed by</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <authorialNote marker="source">
          <p>Source: https://www.legis.la.gov/legis/Law.aspx?d=451561</p>
        </authorialNote>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>